Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
♪
( indistinct
conversations )
Woman: GODDAMNIT.
( door opens )
( door closes)
Man:
YOU KNOW, THEY'RE, UM...
THEY'RE BASED ON
A TENNYSON POEM.
I'M SORRY?
THE--THE WINDOWS?
THE STAINED GLASS?
THEY'RE BASED ON
A TENNYSON POEM.
THEY'RE SUPPOSED TO, UM...
THEY'RE SUPPOSED
TO BE CONSOLING.
IT'S NOT WORKIN' FOR YA?
YEAH...
ME NEITHER.
( clears throat )
SO, UH, ARE YOU HERE--
YOU VISITING SOMEBODY?
OH, NO, N-NOT HERE.
I MEAN, I-I JUST
CAME IN HERE.
OH. TO--
TO LOOK AT THE WINDOWS?
SOMETHING LIKE THAT,
YEAH.
WELL, THERE'S TEN OF 'EM,
EACH DEPICTING A RIVER,
AND--
OKAY, I LIED. UM...
TWO MINUTES. OKAY.
I-I SHOULD GET OUT
TO THE THING.
I MADE ALL
THE ARRANGEMENTS.
UH--OKAY.
WHOSE, UM,
FUNERAL IS IT?
OH, UH, MY DAD.
OH.
GOD, I'M SORRY.
I'M NOT. I MEAN,
I DON'T CARE ABOUT IT.
I--
I DON'T KNOW--
THANK YOU.
IT'S JUST A BUNCH
OF HIS OLD FISHING BUDDIES
OUT THERE.
I DON'T KNOW ANYONE.
RIGHT.
I HAVEN'T SEEN HIM
SINCE 1979.
OH.
WELL, HE'LL NEVER KNOW
IF YOU'RE NOT THERE.
I-I THOUGHT YOU'D ASK
WHY I HAVEN'T SEEN HIM.
EVERYBODY DOES.
DO WANT TO TELL ME?
THANK YOU, THOUGH.
OKAY.
( sighs )
ALL THESE NAMES.
IT'S KIND OF OVERWHELMING
WHEN YOU THINK OF IT,
EACH ONE OF THEM
A DIFFERENT LIFE.
SO WHAT HAPPENED?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
IN 1979.
CLASSIC ROCK DIED.
♪
WAITING FOR
THE BREAK OF DAY ♪
♪ SEARCHING FOR
SOMETHING TO SAY ♪
♪ DANCING LIGHTS
AGAINST THE SKY ♪
♪ GIVING UP,
I CLOSE MY EYES ♪
WOW.
♪ SITTING CROSS-LEGGED
ON THE FLOOR ♪
♪ 25 OR 6 TO 4
CONGRATULATIONS.
SMILE.
♪ STARING BLINDLY
INTO SPACE... ♪
HMM.
I'M--
I'M ANDREW, BY THE WAY.
OH. UH, JUNIOR.
JUNIOR?
( chuckles )
BEAUTIFUL FLOWERS.
YEAH, IT'S MY MOM'S
BIRTHDAY, SO...
WHAT IS SHE, TWO?
NO, NO,
IT'S THE, UH...
THE SECOND ANNIVERSARY
OF HER...
OF HER, UH...
YOU KNOW.
OH. THAT WAS--
THAT WAS SO DUMB OF ME.
I'M REALLY SORRY.
IT'S OKAY.
HERE.
NO, NO.
I INSIST.
REALLY.
THANK YOU.
MMM. NICE.
SO, UH...
ARE YOU MARRIED
OR ANYTHING?
YOU SHOULD
TAKE THIS BACK.
DON'T WORRY,
I WAS JUST WONDERING
IF YOU HAVE ANY,
YOU KNOW, SUPPORT
AMONGST THE FISHERMEN
OUT THERE.
( laughs )
NO, I'M, UH,
I'M DIVORCED.
NO KIDS, NO HUSBAND.
NO BOYFRIEND.
NO GIRLFRIEND.
HUH.
LOOK.
Man: OH, MAN!
JESUS CHRIST!
CONGRATULATIONS!
THANK YOU.
THAT'S GREAT.
Woman: YOU FINALLY GOT IT UP.
YEAH, THAT'S REALLY GREAT.
THAT'S GREAT.
SO WHEN'S
THE BIG DAY?
OH. UM...
I DON'T KNOW.
I MEAN, IT'S JUST A RING.
IT'S A PRETTY RING, THOUGH.
( horn honks )
OH, MY GOSH.
WHAT?
LOOK!
HE'S GOT A FUCKING CAMPER?!
WHERE WOULD DAD
GET THE MONEY FOR
SOMETHING LIKE THAT?
I GUESS MAUDE'S NIGHT JOB
IS FINALLY PAYING OFF.
ALL RIGHT.
COME ON, MAUDE.
NOW, LET ME DO
ALL THE TALKING, OKAY?
( laughing ) OKAY.
AWRIGHT?
DON'T LET ON A THING.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY,
ANDREW'S MOM.
SO HOW DID SHE DIE?
YOU FIRST.
OKAY. HE CRASHED
HIS MOTORHOME.
MOTORHOME. WOW.
THOSE THINGS COST
LIKE HUNDREDS OF THOUSANDS
OF DOLLARS, RIGHT?
THIS IS FROM
THE SEVENTIES.
THAT'S GOOD.
( laughs )
HE'S DEAD.
YEAH.
GODDAMN, HOW DO YOU CRASH
A BIG MOTORHOME LIKE THAT?
WELL, HE WASN'T DRUNK,
IF THAT'S WHAT YOU MEAN.
NO, I DEFINITELY
DIDN'T MEAN THAT.
NO, I SUPPOSE YOU DIDN'T.
YOUR BROTHERS?
THEY'RE FRATERNAL TWINS,
WHICH MEANS THEY DON'T
REALLY LOOK EXACTLY--
I KNOW WHAT IT MEANS,
BUT ARE THEY HERE?
POLLY, BRET'S WIFE,
SHE FACEBOOKED ME.
SHE SAID THEY WERE GOING FISHING
AND NONE OF THEM WERE GONNA
BE ABLE TO MAKE IT.
SHE TOLD ME ON FACEBOOK!
( chuckles )
MAYBE WE SHOULD, UH,
MAYBE WE SHOULD BE
FACEBOOK FRIENDS.
MAYBE.
HMM.
CAREFUL, IT'S WHISKEY.
WHAT KIND OF MAN
GOES THIRTY YEARS
WITHOUT TALKING TO HIS KIDS?
CONGRATULATIONS,
LITTLE GIRL.
THANKS, DAD.
MAUDE. THAT LACE TRIM
ON YOUR DRESS
IS SO...UNUSUAL.
YES, I SEWED IT ON MYSELF
TODAY WHEN WE WERE
DRIVING DOWN HERE.
OH. WAS THE ROAD
THAT BUMPY?
Junior: UM...
IT'S A MAP.
YEAH. HERE.
THERE'S A BIG SPENDER.
HMM!
HERE. HERE.
LET ME HELP YOU.
NOW...
THIS IS OUR PLAYGROUND, KIDS.
HMM. PLAYGROUND.
PLAY.
BRYCE, ZION, RUSHMORE.
ALL OF US.
A FAMILY VACATION.
WHICH BUNK IS MINE?
DAD, I GOT WORK.
POLLY AND ME, WE'RE TRYING
TO BUY A HOUSE.
AND BART, HE'S GOT--
THAT MOTORHOME, KIDS,
THAT'S JUST THE BEGINNING,
THE TIP OF THE ICEBERG.
Bret: WHAT ICEBERG?
A CHANCE FOR US
TO BE A FAMILY AGAIN.
WE'RE ALREADY A FAMILY.
WELL...
A CHANCE FOR ME.
YEAH.
WHAT I WAS HOPING FOR
WAS THAT--
HIGHLIGHTS.
IT'S ALWAYS ABOUT
THE HIGHLIGHTS WITH YOU, STAN.
MOM.
WHAT?
YOU KNOW, GRADUATIONS,
THE TWINS' BIRTHDAY
FIVE YEARS AGO...
YOU JUST GET THE HIGHLIGHTS
OF OUR KIDS' LIVES.
ONE WEEK IN THAT MOTORHOME,
THAT WOULD BE A HIGHLIGHT,
HUH, GUYS?
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
YOU SAW YOUR KIDS, STAN?
DISNEYLAND, YOSEMITE--
NOW,
THOSE
ARE SOME HIGHLIGHTS!
IT WAS THREE YEARS AGO.
THREE YEARS AGO.
THAT'S WHEN YOU MARRIED HER.
HIGHLIGHTS. LIGHT.
LIGHT!
I RAISED THESE KIDS
ALL BY MYSELF.
ALL BY MYSELF
I RAISED THESE KIDS!
GIVE HER A MEDAL.
I DO IT OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
DID I GET ANY HELP?
NO.
KIDS, WHEN HAVE YOU
SEEN YOUR DAD SINCE
THEIR WEDDING?
I HAVE A CANCER.
MELANOMA.
I HAVE THIS.
I DRINK THIS
FOUR TIMES A DAY.
MY DAMN HAIR
HAS STARTED TO--
OH, MY GOSH, DAD--
I'M SORRY, LITTLE GIRL,
I DIDN'T MEAN TO SPRING IT
ON YOU ON YOUR BIG DAY.
NO, IT'S OKAY, BUT--
HOW DO YOU TAKE ANY OCCASION
AND MAKE IT
ALL
ABOUT YOU?
MOM. HE COULD DIE.
WE ALL DIE.
HE IS GOING UPHILL.
HE LET IT GO TOO LONG,
AND--AND NOW IT'S LATE,
AND HE'S GOING UPHILL.
UPHILL BATTLE, MAUDIE.
BATTLE?
IT
IS
A BATTLE,
UPHILL BATTLE,
AND WE ARE FIGHTING IT.
FIGHTING IT UPHILL.
WHAT DO YOU SAY, KIDS?
ONE WEEK IN THE MOTORHOME
AS A FAMILY?
WOULD YA? FOR ME.
A WEEK!
♪ SITTING ON
THE DOOR STOOP ♪
♪ WATCHING MULTIPLES
OF PEOPLE PASS ME BY ♪
♪ LOOK THROUGH THE WINDOWS,
THROUGH THE HOUSES ♪
♪ OH, THEY'RE MADE OF SKY
♪ GARGOYLE WATCHING
THE BOUNCING BALL ♪
♪ STRANGERS MYSTIFIED BY ALL
♪ ALL THE GOINGS ON
♪ SUFFICIENTLY BREATHLESS
( sighs )
HEY, JUNIOR,
WHY DIDN'T HOWARD COME?
I TOLD HIM IT WAS MY LAST CHANCE
TO GO ON SUMMER VACATION
WITH MY LOVING FAMILY.
JUNIOR,
HE BOUGHT THAT?
I NEED TO TINKLE AGAIN.
( sighs )
UHH!
OH, MY GOD!
( laughter )
YOU KNOW, IF YOU'D LET ME
USE THE TOILET IN THE CAMPER...
NO ONE FOULS
THE POSEIDON, MAUDE.
OKAY?
ALL RIGHT!
( cheers, applause )
ALL RIGHT, TURN IT ON.
UH...
KIDS, THERE'S SOMETHING,
UM...
WELL, MY DAD, UH...
THERE'S SOMETHING
I SHOULD HAVE TOLD YOU
BEFORE NOW,
BEFORE WE TURN ON
THE ROADSHOW. UH....
GRANDPA--WELL,
HIM AND GRAM,
LAST YEAR,
LAST, UM...OCTOBER,
THEY WERE OUT
ON UPPER LAKES HIGHWAY,
UP NEAR CURSON CREEK THERE,
AND, UH...
THEY'D BEEN FISHIN',
AND, UH, DAD, UM--
I THINK THEY'D HAD A GOOD DAY,
AND DAD, UH...
BOY, YOU KNOW,
ANYTIME YOU WENT FISHIN'
WITH DAD, YOU WERE SURE--
A TRAILER TRUCK HIT THEM.
DEAD. INSTANTLY.
IT'S LUCKY, IF YOU--
IF YOU ASK ME.
IT TOOK BOTH OF THEM TOGETHER...
LIKE THAT.
THE FISH WERE LYING THERE
RIGHT NEXT TO 'EM,
GOOD AS DAY, AND--
WE ENDED UP GIVING THE FISH
TO THE PATROLMEN...
SOME--
IT'S A SHAME
TO WASTE GOOD TROUT.
SORRY, DAD.
UH...YEAH.
YA KNOW, IT'S ALMOST EIGHT,
SO...
OH. YEAH, IT'S...
WELL, DRUM ROLL, PLEASE.
OH, YEAH.
( plays drum roll
with hands )
I THOUGHT YOU
LIKED MY COOKING1
YOU HAD A THOUGHT?
UNHHHH!
( clears throat )
I DIDN'T THINK THERE WAS
ANYTHING UNDER
THAT LITTLE BARBIE DOLL
HAIR-DO OF YOURS!
WHOA, LOOK!
ECHO! ECHO! ECHO!
WHY DON'T YOU JUST
SHAVE IT ALL OFF
AND GET YOURSELF A MOHAWK?
THAT WAY IT'LL DRAW ATTENTION
AWAY FROM YOUR NOSE!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'M PUTTING YOUR PHONES
IN ORBIT, THAT'S WHAT!
( laughter, applause )
( campfire crackling )
YEAH, I'M SORRY
ABOUT GRAMPS, DAD.
I'LL BET THERE'S FISHIN'
OUT HERE.
I'LL BET GRAMPS
WOULD HAVE...
I BET HE WOULD.
NO, NO. I'M FINE.
I MEAN, THAT IS
A NICE MOTORHOME, DAD.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU GOT IT WITH A TV.
I MEAN, THAT MUST HAVE
COST YOU--
WOULDN'T MIND SEEIN' YOU
ON THAT.
SEEING ME ON...?
ON TV.
ON TELEVISION.
UH...
YOU GOT ONE OF THOSE FACES.
I GOT ONE OF THOSE FACES?
YEAH.
OH, YOU'D...
YOU'D STAND OUT ON TV.
YOU'RE CRAZY, DAD.
WELL, WE'RE ON OUR WAY
TO HOLLYWOOD.
HOLLYWOOD? WE'RE ON OUR WAY
TO DISNEYLAND. ( laughs )
HOLLYWOOD. ( laughs )
( laughs )
YOU THINK I GOT
ONE OF THOSE FACES?
THE FAMOUS KIND?
( both laugh )
YOU COMFY,
LITTLE GIRL?
I'M NOT
YOUR LITTLE GIRL.
AH. YOU'LL ALWAYS BE
MY LITTLE GIRL,
NO MATTER WHAT.
( Andrew, indistinct;
both chuckle )
WHY DID YOU LOOK AT
THE CAMPER'S REGISTRATION?
BECAUSE MY DAD
WAS A HUSTLER.
A HUSTLER.
SERIOUSLY. I NEVER SAW HIM
BUY A BRAND-NEW ANYTHING,
CAR, PAIR OF PANTS,
LOAF OF BREAD...
( laughs )
LOAF OF BREAD?
ALL RIGHT, BUT, YOU KNOW,
GRAMPS DIES, AND SUDDENLY MY DAD
HAD A BRAND-NEW MOTORHOME.
TWO PLUS TO EQUALS FOUR,
RIGHT?
BINGO.
YOU KNOW, MY MOTHER
USED TO, UH...
SHE CALLED ME EVERY DAY.
I HATED IT.
I WISHED SHE'D JUST
LEAVE ME ALONE, YA KNOW?
AND NOW YOU'RE NOT SO SURE,
ARE YOU?
MAYBE YOU HAVE MORE IN COMMON
WITH STAN THAN YOU THOUGHT.
I'M NOT AN ALCOHOLIC.
I DIDN'T MEAN THAT.
YES, YOU DID.
IT
IS
ELEVEN A.M.
I ONLY DRINK ON WEEKENDS.
IT'S TUESDAY.
WELL, AT LEAST I'M NOT
HAVING A RELATIONSHIP
WITH A MARBLE WALL.
I SHOULD PROBABLY GET GOING.
THE PRIEST IS PROBABLY DONE.
GREET THE PEOPLE
THAT CAME FOR THE BURIAL,
YA KNOW?
WHY'D YOU COME TO IDAHO?
REAL ESTATE'S
A LITTLE SLOW RIGHT NOW.
NO, SERIOUSLY.
TO BURY MY DAD.
YOU HAVEN'T BEEN AROUND
IN THIRTY YEARS.
WELL, SOMEONE NEEDED TO DO IT,
AND EVERYBODY ELSE IS FISHING.
MY MOM...
UM...
MY MOM WANTED HER ASHES
SCATTERED
FROM THE TOP OF
THE EMPIRE STATE BUILDING.
BUT HERE WE ARE.
I LIKE THAT IDEA.
WHAT, DO YOU THINK
I'M SELFISH, TOO?
( ironic chuckle )
MAYBE I AM.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU'RE
HERE FOR YOUR DAD, JUNIOR.
GOOD. BECAUSE I NEVER DID
KNOW WHAT HE WANTED.
Stan:
MORNIN', LITTLE GIRL!
MORNING.
AHH.
HEY, DAD, WAS THIS
GRAMP'S CAMPER?
IT'S A MOTORHOME.
WHY DID YOU LIE?
I'M HAPPY
YOU'RE ALL HERE--
WITH ME-- THAT'S WHY.
BUT--
ARE YOU HAPPY, JUNIOR?
WHAT ABOUT WHEN YOU'RE WITH--
WHAT IS IT--?
HOWARD?
YEAH, HOWARD,
RIGHT.
( sighs ) YEAH.
YOU KNOW, THE CREEK
CLOSEST TO THE ROAD
DOESN'T ALWAYS HAVE
THE BIGGEST FISH.
IS MOM THE FISH?
HOWARD
IS THE FISH,
JUNIOR.
YOU ONLY MET HIM ONCE,
DAD.
HEY, JUST DON'T MAKE
THE SAME MISTAKE I MADE.
OH.
SO I SHOULDN'T GET
MY GIRLFRIEND PREGNANT
AT EIGHTEEN.
WE
WANTED
THIS BABY.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
Bret: WHAT?
Polly: DID YOU TELL HER?
OH, JESUS CHRIST, MAUDE!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING UP THERE,
WITH YOUR HIP?!
NO, NO, IT DOESN'T GO THAT WAY.
NO. NO.
NO. NO, NO, NO, NO. NO.
ALL RIGHT, HANG ON.
HANG ON.
( door opens )
HE LIKES TO BE
IN CHARGE, HUH?
SOMETHING'S BURNING,
HONEY.
NO, NO.
DON'T TOUCH THE OVEN.
STAN'S RULES.
DAD, HOW--
HOW WOULD YOU GET ON TV?
LET ME ASK YOU
A QUESTION, BART.
HOW DO YOU THINK
I PAID FOR THIS CAMPER?
YOU ROBBED A BANK
WITH PATTY HEARST.
I KNOW.
( laughs )
WHAT?
YEAH! YEAH.
NO. SERIOUSLY?
THE MATCH GAME.
HE CAN BE MEAN
SOMETIMES.
WELL, IF YOU, UM,
IF YOU WANT A CAKE,
YOU GOTTA BE WILLING
TO GRIND UP THE WHEAT.
IS DAD THE CAKE?
YOU, STAN TALMADGE,
WERE ON TV WHEN?
ABOUT SIX MONTHS AGO.
YOU SHOULDA SEEN ME.
I WASN'T BAD.
YOU'RE SERIOUS? WAIT, WAIT,
POLLY MUST HAVE SEEN YOU.
SHE WATCHES THAT SHIT
LIKE EVERY DAY.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
IF IT'S BEEN ON THE AIR YET.
THEY TAPE THOSE SHOWS,
LIKE, WAY AHEAD OF TIME.
"TAPE"? "TAPE"!
HA HA HA!
LISTEN TO YOU,
MR. HOLLYWOOD!
( laughs )
( camera shutter clicks )
KIDS, LET'S GET ON
THE ROAD, OKAY?
RIGHT, DAD.
HEY, DAD.
WHEN WE GET TO L.A.,
DO YOU THINK WE COULD
MAYBE TALK TO SOMEONE?
ABOUT TV. I MEAN,
DO YOU KNOW ANYONE?
WELL, YEAH, SURE, SON,
SURE, IF YOU'D LIKE.
REALLY?
YOU KNOW, BART,
HAVE YOU EVER WATCHED THE SHOW
WHERE THE FAMILY IS A TEAM
AND THEY COMPETE
AGAINST EACH OTHER?
YOU MEAN
BEAT YOUR NEIGHBOR?
YEAH. YEAH,
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
YOU EVER SEEN THAT?
OH, MY GOD, OF COURSE!
DAD, WE HAVE THE RIGHT NUMBER!
IT'S FIVE, RIGHT?
( camera shutter clicks )
MAUDE, WILL YOU
TAKE ONE OF US?
OKAY. READY?
KIDS, UH,
LET'S GET ON THE ROAD.
OKAY.
BART, YOU DRIVE.
TIME FOR MY MEDICINE.
POLLY,
DON'T YOU WATCH
MATCH GAME?
Polly: IS JESUS
MY PERSONAL SAVIOR?
WHY IS IT THAT
YOU HAVE TO BRING JESUS
INTO
EVERYTHING?
( overlapping,
indistinct chatter )
ONWARD, BART, GOING WHERE
NO TALMADGE HAS GONE BEFORE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
( palms slap )
( country music
on radio )
( mutters drunkenly )
( burps )
HEY, BUD.
LOOK AT ME AND BRET.
DON'T YOU THINK WE LOOK LIKE
THOSE GUYS ON TV?
LIKE THE TV STARS?
WHAT KIND OF WORK YOU DO,
STAN?
STAN USED TO MANAGE
THE MEAT DEPARTMENT
AT THE ALBERTSON'S
IN TWIN FALLS.
USED TO?
THAT GOOD MONEY?
WELL, I GOT
OTHER PLANS NOW, BUD.
YOU KNOW, WE'RE NAMED
AFTER THE MAVERICK BROTHERS.
HE'S BRET, I'M BART...
OUR DAD NAMED US
AFTER THOSE GUYS.
DAD,
YOU STOPPED WORKING?
HOW MUCH FOR
THIS POSEIDON, STAN?
( burps )
JEALOUS?
( chuckles )
HE WON IT
ON A GAME SHOW.
WHAT?
MATCH GAME.
NO KIDDIN'.
HUH. I THOUGHT
WE WERE ON OUR WAY
TO TRY OUT FOR THAT
BEAT YOUR NEIGHBOR
GAME SHOW.
MAUDE!
WHAT?
GAME SHOW?
I LOVE THOSE!
BEAT YOUR NEIGHBOR.
I TOLD YOU THAT.
YOU GOT A TV
IN YOUR CAMPER THERE, BUD?
DAD--
WHAT DO YOU GOT,
BLACK AND WHITE, OR COLOR?
COLOR.
WAIT A MINUTE.
WHAT THE HELL
IS GOING ON?
MAUDE, ARE YOU
MAKING ALL THIS UP?
DAD, WHAT'S
GOING ON?
HOW ABOUT YOU JUST RELAX?
WE GOT IT ALL FIGURED OUT.
WE GOT THE RIGHT NUMBER
AND EVERYTHING.
AND DAD KNOWS SOMEBODY.
WHEN WE GO TO L.A.,
WE ARE GOING TO AUDITION
FOR BEAT...
YOUR NEIGHBOR!
All:
OVER MY DEAD BODY.
BUD, HELP ME.
MY FAMILY'S CRAZY,
RIGHT?
WELL, WE SHOULD REALLY
GET GOIN', HON.
MM-HMM.
MAUDE, THANK YOU FOR DINNER.
IT WAS WONDERFUL.
Maude: THANK YOU SO MUCH.
NICE TO MEET YOU ALL.
BEST OF LUCK
WITH THE GAME SHOW.
I'LL WATCH FOR YOU ALL.
Bart: OH, YOU'LL SEE US, BUD.
BUD, DON'T LEAVE ME
WITH THEM!
I'M THE ONE
THAT MADE DINNER!
GOD, DOESN'T ANYBODY
LISTEN TO ME?
SOMEONE SAY SOMETHING?
I DON'T HEAR ANYTHING.
Y'ALL COME BACK NOW,
YA HEAR?
JESUS LISTENS, JUNIOR.
EVERY TIME.
OHH!
WHY DID HE LIE TO ME?
YOU KNOW, I MEAN,
THIS CANCER STUFF REALLY
MESSES WITH YOU.
GOD, I CAN'T EVEN
THINK ABOUT IT.
IT SCARES ME.
IT'S JUST THAT...
I'M JUST STARTING TO
GET TO KNOW DAD AGAIN.
SO LET'S GO DO
BEAT YOUR NEIGHBOR
AS A FAMILY.
I FEEL BAD FOR MOM.
WELL, WITH ALL
THE AMAZING THINGS
THAT I'M SURE
ARE GOING ON IN MAUDE'S HEAD,
I REALLY DON'T THINK SHE CARES.
AND IT'LL BE FUN
TO BE ON TV, JUNIOR.
YOU REMEMBER FUN,
DON'T YOU?
SURE.
AND IF DAD CAN GET US
ON TV, THAT WOULD BE COOL.
IT'LL BE...
THE ONLY THING
HE'S EVER DONE RIGHT
OUR WHOLE LIVES.
( overlapping chatter )
YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU TWO REALLY ARE TWINS.
DAD,
CALL THE SHOW.
YOU KNOW, BETWEEN ALL OF US,
WE REALLY DO KNOW EVERYTHING.
BART, SPORTS,
ME, SCIENCE FACT
AND
FICTION,
JUNIOR, BOTANY--
BOTANY?
YEAH.
WELL, WHAT AM I? THE MONKEY?
YOU SHOULD TAKE GEOGRAPHY
NOW THAT YOU'VE GOT THE CAMPER.
CAMPERS ARE PICK-UPS.
MOTORHOMES ARE COACHES.
IS HAS CAPTAIN'S CHAIRS.
IT HAS CAPTAIN'S CHAIRS.
IT'S NOT ABOUT
BEING SMART.
IT'S ABOUT SCREAMING
AS LOUD AS YOU CAN
AND PRETENDING
THAT WE LOVE EACH OTHER.
CALL, DAD!
NO, NO--
WHAT?
UH-HUH.
YEAH, I SEE.
WELL--
RIGHT. OKAY.
BYE.
AHH.
TOMORROW, TEN A.M.
YES!
SO IT'S DAD, ME, BART,
POL AND JUNIOR.
DAD, WHAT'D THEY SAY?
MAUDE, YOU DRIVE.
I NEED TO REHEARSE. OKAY?
HOW DID YOU GET
AN INTERVIEW SO FAST?
HOW'D THAT HAPPEN?
LUCK.
LUCK FOLLOWS ME LIKE A PUPPY
FOLLOWS A BITCH, BOYS.
WHAT ABOUT--
WE GOT A LONG WAY TO DRIVE.
LET'S GO. COME ON.
BREAK ALL YOUR LEGS!
GO!
♪ ( no distinct dialogue )
Stan: WHOO!
WE ARE THE TALMADGE FAMILY.
GO AHEAD, GUYS,
SIT DOWN.
UH, BART, SIT DOWN.
HMM.
HELLO.
I ALWAYS...
I ALWAYS WANTED
TO BE ON THAT GAME SHOW.
GIVE ME A QUESTION.
TEST ME.
OH, GOD.
COME ON.
FINE.
TELL AMERICA... OKAY.
(game show host voice):
TELL AMERICA AN ANIMAL
PEOPLE KEEP AS PETS!
DOGS, RABBITS, CATS,
SNAKES, BIRDS...
YOU FORGOT FISH.
TOO BAD I WAS
AN ONLY CHILD, RIGHT?
I WOULDA ROCKED THAT SHOW.
GO THANK YOUR MOTHER
RIGHT NOW FOR NOT TAKING YOU.
GO THANK YOUR DAD.
FOR WHAT?
I DON'T KNOW.
AN ADVENTURE?
(scoffs)
HE WAS USING HIS KIDS
TO PROVE TO THE WORLD
HE WASN'T A LOSER.
REALLY?
ON A TV GAME SHOW?
WHAT DID YOUR FATHER
DO FOR A LIVING?
HE, UH...
(chuckles ) HE OWNED
AN INSURANCE AGENCY.
YOU PLAY GOLF
AS A KID?
YEAH.
LET ME GUESS:
THE WILLOW GLEN COUNTRY CLUB?
AND I BET YOUR MOM
BOUGHT HER ROAST BEEF
FROM MY DAD
AT THE ALBERTSON'S
ON HIGHLAND AVENUE.
THINK SHE EVER NOTICED HIM?
WE WEREN'T BETTER
THAN YOU, JUNIOR.
WELL, I'M NOT SO SURE
YOU KNOW WHAT IT FEELS LIKE
TO BE A FAILURE.
YEAH?
( laughs)
WELL, YOU DON'T KNOW ME.
AND I'M GUESSING
YOU DIDN'T KNOW
YOUR DAD, EITHER.
HI, I'M STAN TALMADGE,
AND THIS IS MY SON BART
AND HIS TWIN BROTHER BRET.
AH, TWINS. HMM.
WHAT? JUST FRATERNAL.
OH.
WELL, BRET AND BART,
JUST LIKE THE MAVERICK BROTHERS.
WE ARE A TV FAMILY
THROUGH AND THROUGH.
OKAY. SO WHO'S
THE REST OF YOUR TEAM?
UH, NEXT TO BRET IS, UH,
IS HIS WIFE POLLY...
HI!
AND, UM,
AT THE END HERE
IS MY DAUGHTER, JUNIOR.
JUNIOR.
HI. IS THAT A--
A NICKNAME OR...?
WELL, N-NO.
JUST A NAME.
I MEAN--
I MEAN, NOT REALLY, UM,
SHE WAS SUPPOSED
TO BE A BOY, BUT...
YA KNOW, WELL, WHO KNEW?
IT STUCK.
( chuckles )
YEAH.
STAN.
LET ME BE FRANK. UH...
OH, GO AHEAD
AND SIT DOWN.
THIS IS
BEAT YOUR NEIGHBOR.
WE'RE A CLASS ACT.
AND THE NUMBER ONE GAME SHOW
IN AMERICA.
WE HAVE HIGH STANDARDS,
AND WE EXPECT OUR PLAYERS
TO UPHOLD THOSE STANDARDS.
THAT'S WHY WE'RE HERE,
MARTY.
Bart: THAT'S RIGHT, DAD!
Polly: THAT'S RIGHT.
( chatter, phone ringing )
( studio audience
applauding )
HI!
( sighs )
( music playing on radio )
OH, FUCK IT!
OH. OHH!
OHH....
( exhales )
OH, FORGIVE ME, STAN.
OHH.
( sighing )
( sniffs )
( low nervous chatter )
Marty: HMM.
JAMESON FAMILY,
MARTINO FAMILY--
CONGRATULATIONS.
( cheering)
YES!
THE REST OF YOU,
THANK YOU FOR COMING.
WHAT?
NO WAY, MAN.
THAT'S NOT FAIR!
JUNIOR!
YOU GOTTA SAVE US. WHAT?
MARTY. I THINK HE HAD
A BIT OF A...
HE LIKES YOU.
JUST TALK TO HIM.
CHANGE HIS MIND.
WHAT?! DAD!
DO IT FOR ME?
COME ON.
EXCUSE ME.
EXCUSE ME, SIR.
OH, IT'S MARTY.
MARTY.
HI.
UM, WHY ARE YOU
SENDING US HOME?
OH. WELL, SOMETIMES
YOU JUST KNOW, SO...
NO, BUT YOU--
YOU
CAN'T
DO THIS
TO MY DAD.
UH, WHY NOT?
HE WANTS SO MUCH
FOR US TO BE ON TV.
AND YOU?
WELL...
I CARE ABOUT MY DAD.
(low) ENOUGH TO HAVE DINNER
WITH ME TONIGHT?
OKAY.
MR. COOPER.
CALL ME MARTY.
I'LL GO CHECK ON
THE ROOMS.
I TRIED TO GET
ALL CONNECTING ROOMS,
BUT NO GO.
YA KNOW, MAYBE IF YOU BOYS
HAD WORN TIES...
COME ON, MAN.
Stan: WELL,
WHAT DO YOU SAY, MAUDE?
WANT TO HEAD TO THE ROOM?
Junior: GET IN,
I'M DRIVING.
Maude: HE'S THE PRODUCER
OF THE SHOW?
JUST SMILE AND WAVE,
MAUDE.
ALL RIGHT!
I LIKE A WOMAN WITH BALLS.
NICE. YEAH, GO AHEAD,
OPEN IT UP.
( gears grind )
YEAH--
YEAH, THIRD GEAR'S
STRAIGHT UP.
YEAH.
WHOO! IT'S FUN.
YEAH, RIGHT.
COOL.
YOU LOOK GOOD IN A PORSCHE.
OH, YEAH?
YEAH.
WELL, WE TRIED, HUH?
I'M JUST GLAD TO BE
SPENDING SOME TIME WITH MY KIDS.
( sighs )
HERE'S TO
JUNIOR'S SUCCESS.
OH, MAN.
THIS IS WHAT I CALL
A FAMILY VACATION.
( chuckles )
YOU GET HIGH?
I'M GONNA INVITE
YOUR FAMILY BACK.
REALLY?
YEAH.
THANK YOU.
IT'S JUST AN AUDITION.
YEAH...
I THINK IT'S A SHAME
NOT TO SHARE YOU WITH
THE AMERICAN PUBLIC.
HMM.
BUT I DON'T KNOW
ANYTHING ABOUT BOTANY.
NEITHER DO I.
SEE? WE ALREADY HAVE
A LOT IN COMMON.
( sighs )
TELL AMERICA A FAVORITE WAY
OF GETTING AROUND TOWN!
OH!
( bell ringing )
TAXI!
YES!
AMERICA SAYS?
( excited laughter )
GO, BROTHER!
YEAH!
Marty: OKAY.
TELL AMERICA SOMETHING
THAT COMES FROM THE SOUTH.
( bell rings )
COLORED PEOPLE.
OH.
Did he say
"colored people"?
JUST KIDDING.
UH...TOBACCO?
AMERICA SAYS?
YOU WERE SO GOOD, BABY!
CAN YOU BELIEVE DAD?
Junior. Junior.
Walk--walk slower.
Maybe Marty'll--
UH,
MISS TALMADGE?
Told you so.
THE, UH, OTHER PRODUCERS
AND I HAD SOME QUESTIONS--
GOD, HOW DID WE DO?
NO SO GOOD, HUH?
GOD, I COULD
LOSE MY JOB FOR THIS.
UM...MEET ME
ON THE SIDEWALK, OKAY?
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT.
THAT'S
MY LITTLE GIRL.
( sighs ) GOD,
DAD, I DON'T KNOW,
I MEAN, COULDN'T WE GET
KICKED OFF THE SHOW FOR THIS?
IT'D BE WORSE FOR HIM.
REMEMBER THAT, JUNIOR.
YOU HAVE HIM HOOKED.
JUST...GO IN FOR THE KILL.
( elevator bell rings )
GO IN FOR THE KILL....
GO IN FOR THE KILL.
YA KNOW,
WHEN I WAS IN COLLEGE,
I, UH...
I SPENT SUMMERS WORKING
AS A FLY FISHING GUIDE
ON...ON THE MIDDLE FORK
OF THE SALMON.
YOU KNOW IT?
IT'S OUT BY DRIGGS?
RIGHT UP-- ANYWAY.
( both laugh )
THERE WASN'T MUCH TO DO
AT NIGHT,
SO ME AND THE GUYS,
WE'D JUST SIT AROUND THE CABIN
AND TIE FLIES.
THEY'RE SO BEAUTIFUL,
THOSE LITTLE FLIES,
IT'S...
IT'S ALMOST A SHAME
TO USE 'EM TO CATCH
SOME UGLY FISH.
BECAUSE EVEN IF YOU DON'T
CATCH THAT BIG FISH,
YOU STILL END UP WITH
A MANGLED FLY.
I HATE TO FISH.
BUT YOU DIDN'T MIND
BEING THE BAIT?
YOU KNOW, THE THING IS...
MY DAD DIDN'T BELIEVE
HE COULD WIN ON HIS OWN,
SO HE USED US,
HE USED HIS KIDS,
AND...
WELL, I REALLY WANTED
TO BELIEVE IN HIM.
SUPPORTIVE DAUGHTER,
HUH?
I GUESS I THOUGHT
IT WOULD SHOW EVERYONE
WE WERE A REAL FAMILY
WITH A... A REAL DAD.
A REAL TV FAMILY,
WITH COMPETITIVE BROTHERS.
COMPETITIVE?
THAT'S A NICE WAY OF DESCRIBING
THOSE GREEDY BASTARDS.
RIGHT.
SERIOUSLY.
ALL THEY HAD TO DO
WAS HOLD IT TOGETHER
FOR ONE MORE DAY.
TV:
...THE BASEBALL GOES DEAD.
NO WONDER THAT GUY
CAN'T RUN TO FIRST BASE.
INSTEAD OF BASEBALL SHOES,
HE'S WEARING....
( laughter )
( Polly laughs )
( TV continues,
indistinct )
WHAT IF HE DRINKS?
WHAT IF HE'S BOMBED
AT THE NEXT AUDITION,
OR WORSE, ON THE SHOW?
WE COULD LOSE BIG-TIME!
HE WON'T GET DRUNK.
HE BARFED AT
HIS OWN WEDDING.
YOU WANT TO GAMBLE
OUR FUTURE ON THAT?
THAT POOR LITTLE FLOWER GIRL.
WE NEED FIVE, RIGHT?
DUH.
WHAT IF HE WAS DEAD?
BART, PEOPLE WOULD KNOW
IF WE DID THAT.
WHAT? WHAT?!
WHAT?
WHAT?!
AFTER THE SHOW TODAY
I ASKED BART...
"HOW'D IT FEEL
BEING ON THE SET, SON?"
DO YOU KNOW WHAT HE SAID?
YEAH.
NO, YOU DON'T.
NO, I DON'T.
HE SAID...
"IT WAS LIKE BREATHING, DAD.
EASY."
YOU DON'T HAVE ANYTHING GOOD.
UH...YEAH,
CHECK THIS OUT.
UM...
SOMEBODY SAID TO BUY--
THEY'RE BRITISH, I THINK.
YOU THINK?
( laughs )
( up-tempo rock song
playing on stereo )
YOU KNOW, YOU COULD
BE AN ACTRESS.
( laughs )
I, UM, I BET YOU
TELL US ALL THAT.
"US"? NO.
SO, UH....
IF NOT AN ACTRESS,
WHAT DO YOU WANT TO BE?
I WANT TO BE A CHEF.
A CHEF.
ISN'T THAT LIKE
BEING A MAID?
YOU SOUND
JUST LIKE MY MOTHER.
WHAT DOES YOUR DAD SAY?
MY DAD. UM...
MY DAD PUT ME UP TO THIS.
PUT ME UP TO YOU.
AH.
I LOVE THIS SONG.
SO, IS THAT WHY
YOU'RE...HERE,
FOR YOUR DAD?
I'M HERE TO DANCE.
OH, UH, OKAY.
♪ I'M LOST IN THE SUPERMARKET
♪ I CAN NO LONGER
SHOP HAPPILY ♪
♪ I CAME IN HERE
FOR THAT SPECIAL OFFER ♪
♪ A GUARANTEED PERSONALITY
( laughing )
♪ IT'S NOT HERE
♪ IT DISAPPEARED...
( new song, slower tempo )
♪ AND YOU MIGHT NOT
KNOW WHO ♪
♪ YOU SEE,
SOMEBODY NEEDS YOU ♪
♪ YEAH, BABY
♪ YOU MIGHT NOT KNOW WHO
♪ I'M GONNA SAY
SOMEBODY ♪
♪ SOMEBODY, SOMEBODY
♪ SOMEBODY LOVES YOU, BABY
♪ I WANT TO SAY SOMEBODY
♪ SOMEBODY, SOMEBODY
♪ SOMEBODY LOVES YOU, BABY
♪ HOO HOO, HOO HOO
HEY.
YOU'RE UP.
GOOD.
MORNING.
UM...
YOU HUNGRY? YOU WANT ME
TO MAKE YOU SOMETHING?
I, UM, I MAKE REALLY,
REALLY GOOD BREAKFASTS.
UM, EGGS AND TOAST AND...
MARTY?
I'M LATE FOR WORK.
I CALLED.
THERE'S A CAB
WAITING OUT FRONT.
OH.
OKAY, WELL...THANKS.
UH, WE TAPE TOMORROW MORNING,
ELEVEN A.M.
DON'T BE LATE.
WHAT?
WE'RE ON THE SHOW?
YEAH.
TOMORROW AS IN, LIKE,
THE-DAY-AFTER-TODAY TOMORROW?
AFTER THAT I NEVER
WANT TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
( laughs )
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
JUNIOR, I COULD HAVE
LOST MY JOB.
MY CAREER.
YOU USED ME TO GET ON
A TV SHOW.
YEAH, BUT...YOU GOT
WHAT YOU WANTED, TOO.
WELL, WE'RE EVEN.
CONGRATULATIONS.
WHAT DOES IT MATTER
HOW WE MET?
GOD, I DON'T EVEN WANT TO BE
ON THIS STUPID SHOW.
I JUST-- I-I WANT TO
GO TO DISNEYLAND.
AND I...
I ONLY DID THIS
BECAUSE I THOUGHT
YOU WERE CUTE.
LOOK, IF YOU DON'T WANT TO
HAVE US ON THE SHOW,
I UNDERSTAND.
I'D RATHER HAVE YOU.
I'D RATHER
YOU WERE ON THE SHOW.
JUNIOR!
JUNIOR,
ARE YOU IN THERE?
HEY, JUNIOR,
I NOTICED THAT, UM...
YOU'RE NOT WEARING
YOUR RING.
HOW COME?
MAUDE, I'M SUCH
A TERRIBLE PERSON.
I SPENT THE NIGHT
WITH MARTY.
HONEY, THAT DOES
NOT
MAKE YOU A TERRIBLE PERSON.
IT MAKES YOU A SLUT.
( sobs )
GOD, I JUST WANTED
TO MAKE DAD HAPPY, YOU KNOW?
I WANTED TO BE HIS HERO.
AND IT DIDN'T MATTER ANYMORE
THAT WE NEVER GOT TO
SEE HIM AS KIDS.
HE'S MY DAD.
AFTER THE CANCER--
HE DOESN'T HAVE CANCER,
JUNIOR.
WHAT?
MAUDE, I NEVER KNOW
WHEN YOU'RE TELLING THE TRUTH.
HE LIED. TO YOU.
TO US. TO ME.
OF COURSE HE DID.
YEAH.
IT'S NO PARK WALK
THINKING THAT YOUR HUSBAND'S
DYING OF CANCER,
LET ME TELL YOU.
BUT LOOK, JUNIOR,
IF I LEFT EVERY MAN
OR EVERY DAD
EVERY TIME
HE DID SOMETHING TERRIBLE,
I WOULD BE
AN ALONE WOMAN.
THAT'S LIFE.
IT'S A BUNCH OF CHOICES.
BUT JUNIOR,
WHAT I DO KNOW,
YOUR DAD'S GOOD,
IT'S MORE THAN HIS BAD.
THAT'S WHY I STAY WITH HIM--
FOR NOW.
THAT SELFISH
SON OF A BITCH!
HOPE YOU'RE NOT
TALKING ABOUT ME.
( laughs )
( imitating Three Stooges)
NYUH NYUH.
AH.
WHAT'S IN THE BOTTLE, DAD?
TIME.
YOU TOLD US
YOU WERE
DYING.
NO, YOU JUST
BELIEVED THAT.
I TOLD YOU
I HAVE CANCER.
A MOLE THAT
DR. OLSON REMOVED.
YOU LIED ABOUT THE MOTORHOME,
THE SHOW, THE TRIP--
EVERYTHING.
HONEY, IT WAS THE ONLY WAY
THAT I COULD HAVE TIME
WITH MY LITTLE GIRL.
I'M NOT YOUR LITTLE GIRL!
OKAY, I KNOW.
I KNOW.
BUT IT WAS REAL IMPORTANT TO ME
THAT YOU DID COME...
AND THAT MAUDE AND ME
GOT SOME TIME WITH YOU
AND THE TWINS.
NO. IT WAS IMPORTANT TO YOU
THAT YOU WERE ON
THAT RETARDED SHOW!
YEAH, YEAH,
BUT NOT TO BE
ON
THE SHOW;
TO BE A
FAMILY--
TOGETHER.
TO BE A FAMILY
THAT WINS TOGETHER.
( scoffs )
SO WHAT?
YOU KNOW HOW MANY MILES
WERE ON THAT CAMPER
WHEN GRAMPS DIED?
TEN. TEN MILES.
THAT'S THE DISTANCE
FROM THE DEALERSHIP
TO THEIR HOUSE.
THEY OWNED THAT MOTORHOME
FOR A YEAR,
AND THEY NEVER
ONCE
USED IT.
I'M NOT GONNA MAKE
THE SAME MISTAKE AS MY DAD.
MAYBE YOU JUST LOVED STAN MORE
THAN HE COULD LOVE YOU BACK.
WHAT WOULD YOU
KNOW ABOUT IT?
YOUR MOM CALLED YOU
EVERY DAY, ANDREW.
WHAT DOES THAT MATTER?
CLEARY,
SHE LOVED YOU TO DEATH.
MOM KILLED HERSELF, OKAY?
YOU HAPPY?
OHH...GOD...
NO.
SHE SHOT HERSELF.
IT WAS HER BIRTHDAY.
OH, ANDREW.
I'M, UM...
I'M VERY SORRY.
IT'S OKAY.
SHE, UM...
SHE LEFT A NOTE.
IT SAID, UM...
IT SAID, "I'M TIRED."
I KNOW WHAT SHE MEANT.
DO YOU?
I MEAN, DO YOU?
BECAUSE I'M...
I'M HERE EVERY TUESDAY
TRYING TO FIGURE IT OUT.
MAYBE THAT'S WHY SHE'S HERE
AND NOT DRIFTING OVER MANHATTAN.
YOU OKAY?
I JUST...
I KEEP ASKING MYSELF
WAS IT MY FAULT, YOU KNOW?
WE ARE
NOT
RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE WAY THEY TREATED US.
DO YOU WANT THAT?
NOT LIKE IT'S GONNA
DO ME ANY GOOD.
Bret: DAD.
WE NEED TO TALK.
ME AND BRET AND POLLY
HAVE BEEN TALKIN',
YOU KNOW,
ABOUT THE SHOW--
DAD, SINCE YOU ALREADY
WON ONCE IN A GAME SHOW,
WE THOUGHT--
STAN, WHAT SHOW
WERE YOU ON?
MAUDE, SHUT UP.
MATCH GAME,
MAUDE.
HE WAS ON
THE MATCH GAME.
HE WAS?
I THOUGHT YOU MADE THAT UP,
STAN. CONGRATULATIONS!
WHAT, MAUDE?
LET'S--LET'S TALK LATER,
OKAY, BOYS?
WHAT IS
WITH YOU?
PICK UP THOSE CARDS.
MAUDE, LEAVE IT!
CARDS, BART. NOW.
MAUDE, HOW DID DAD
BUY THAT CAMPER?
LEAVE HER OUT OF THIS,
OKAY?
I'M THE PATRIARCH,
AND WHAT I SAY GOES.
WERE YOU ON
MATCH GAME?
WERE YOU ON FUCKIN'
MATCH GAME,
YES OR NO?
NO. BUT--
GODDAMNIT!
DAD! I BELIEVED YOUR LIES
OVER AND OVER AGAIN,
I FORGIVE YOU,
AND OVER AND OVER AGAIN
I TALKED MYSELF INTO BELIEVING
THAT YOU ACTUALLY
CARE
ABOUT US.
I CARE ABOUT YOU--
WHY DO YOU LIE?!
BECAUSE I DIDN'T THINK
YOU'D BELIEVE WE COULD WIN.
AWRIGHT?
I THOUGHT I NEEDED PROOF,
PROOF THAT I COULD BE A WINNER.
I MEANT WHY DO YOU LIE
ABOUT CARING, DAD.
WE ALL WANTED
TO BE ON TV, DAD.
I-I'M SORRY.
YOU'RE ALWAYS FUCKIN' SORRY,
NOTHING EVER FUCKIN' CHANGES.
WHAT?
ELEVEN A.M.
TOMORROW MORNING.
YOU'RE ON THE SHOW.
( laughing, cheering )
MOM?
Helen:
JUNIOR?
YEAH. (sighs)
CAN YOU COME PICK ME UP?
BART.
AAAH!
OH!
OH! UM...
BART!
OH, WHAT THE--
WHAT THE HELL, JUNIOR?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
WHO...WHO ARE YOU?
THIS IS BREEZE.
HI.
UH, I'M GONNA GO.
WELL, JUNIOR,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
I CALLED MOM.
I--
I DIDN'T KNOW WHAT TO DO,
AND I REALLY
DON'T WANT TO STAY HERE,
AND NOW SHE'S ON HER WAY--
WAIT, WAIT.
MOM'S COMING HERE
TO CALIFORNIA?
YEAH.
WELL, JUNIOR, LOOKS LIKE
COLLEGE ACTUALLY DID
PAY OFF FOR YOU, HUH?
SO YOU THINK MARTY'LL
LET US SWITCH THE TEAMS?
UH...
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
MOM INSTEAD OF DAD.
HEY! I THOUGHT
YOU WANTED
ME.
THAT'S NOT WHY
I CALLED HER--
JUNIOR...
DAD CUT US
OUT OF HIS LIFE.
NOW, THIS WOULD BE
A VERY SMART TIME FOR US
TO CUT HIM OUT OFOURS.
SO THAT YOU COULD BE ON TV.
SOMETIMES YOU GOTTA
CUT OFF THE BIG TOE
SO YOU CAN SAVE THE FOOT.
OKAY, BART, WHAT IF
EVERYTHING ABOUT DAD WAS WRONG,
WAS A LIE?
WOULDN'T YOU STILL
WANT
HIM?
I MEAN, WOULDN'T YOU RATHER
HAVE A DAD THAN NOT AT ALL?
NO. I WOULD RATHER
HAVE THE PRIZE MONEY
THAN TO HAVE HIM AS A DAD.
WHY DO YOU HATE HIM
SO MUCH, BART?
I HATE HIM BECAUSE
HE LIES TO US, JUNIOR;
HE ALWAYS HAS.
THIS WHOLE THING
WAS PLANNED OUT BY HIM.
I WOULDN'T BE SURPRISED IF
THE SON OF A BITCH WAS LYING
ABOUT HAVING CANCER.
WHAT?
JUNIOR,
DOES HE HAVE CANCER?
I-I REALLY HAVE TO GO.
Breeze: NICE TO MEET YOU.
JUNIOR!
HE DOESN'T HAVE CANCER,
DOES HE?
NO.
WOW.
( glass shatters )
THAT FUCKIN'
SON OF A BITCH.
BART, I--
THAT FUCKIN'
SON OF A BITCH.
( door slams )
( indistinct chatter )
( sighs )
SO DAD,
I'VE BEEN THINKING
ABOUT THE SHOW, AND--
Polly: MORNING!
MORNING.
THREE GENERATIONS
ALL HERE.
DAD, LET'S JUST SKIP THE SHOW
AND GO TO DISNEYLAND TODAY.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
OH, JESUS, MARY AND JANE,
I HOPE YOU LIKE THIS.
DAD, WE NEED TO TALK.
YEAH, LET'S
TALK.
BRET, DON'T DO THIS.
WE NEED SOMEONE
WE CAN COUNT ON
NOT TO LOSE IT.
WE NEED SOMEONE
WE CAN TRUST.
WE CAN TRUST, STAN.
DAD.
TELL AMERICA THE TOP
300 OTHER PEOPLE WE WOULD
RATHER HAVE ON THE TEAM.
SURPRISE!
DON'T ACT SO EXCITED, STAN.
MOM. MOM'S WHO WE NEED.
OH, GOD.
YOU WANT TO CUT ME?
THE
DAD?
FROM THE TEAM?
MY TEAM?
MY FAMILY?
( laughs/snorts )
AND YOU WANT...
AN
OUTSIDER?
OH, AN OUTSIDER?
I HAPPEN TO BE THEIR MOTHER,
AND I'M A LOT SMARTER THAN YOU,
STAN.
OKAY, MOM, THAT'S REALLY
NOT NECESSARY RIGHT NOW.
HELEN'S A ROCK.
DO YOU HEAR THAT, STAN?
I'M A
ROCK.
YEAH...WE NEED
A ROCK, DAD.
( chuckling )
HELEN'S A ROCK?
A
ROCK.
A ROCK!
AAAH!
STAN!
A ROCK!!!
A ROCK! DAD!
A ROCK?!!!
A
ROCK?!
STAN! STAN!
A ROCK?!
STAN! NO.
STAN, JUST--JUST STOP IT.
YOU THINK YOU
CHANGED THEIR MINDS?
ALL YOU DID
WAS SHOW THESE KIDS
HOW FUCKIN' NUTS YOU ARE.
GOD, MOM, JUST GO!
GO!
JUNIOR, LET'S GO. NOW.
Bart: COME ON, JUNIOR.
WE NEED YOU ON THE SHOW TO WIN.
JUNIOR, GO WITH 'EM.
NO.
JUNIOR, HE'S A LOSER.
YOU'RE NEVER GONNA
AMOUNT TO ANYTHING,
YOU KNOW THAT?
YOU COULDN'T BE ON A GAME SHOW
IF YOU WERE THE LAST
CONTESTANT ON EARTH.
FACE IT, OLD MAN,
YOU'RE WORTHLESS
AND YOU'RE STUPID.
LET'S GO.
MOM, JUST GO.
I
AM
GOING.
♪ DREAM ON
♪
WHAT ELSE
ARE YOU GONNA DO?
♪ LOVE'S GONE
♪ AND LEFT YOU
WITHOUT A CLUE ♪
♪
DON'T LET IT GET TO YOU ♪
♪ TALK YOURSELF
OUT OF THE BLUE ♪
♪ AND DREAM ON
♪ NOBODY TOLD YOU
♪
SO YOU'VE HAD TO
WORK IT OUT ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN SO LONELY
♪ I KNOW THAT
YOU'VE HAD YOUR DOUBTS ♪
♪ BUT NOW YOU'RE ON YOUR OWN
♪ WALKIN' INTO THE LIGHT
♪ LOOKS LIKE
YOU'VE ALWAYS KNOWN ♪
♪ HUSH NOW, BABY,
DON'T YOU CRY ♪
♪ KISS THOSE
SAD OLD DAYS GOODBYE ♪
♪ AND DREAM ON
♪
KISS THOSE
SAD OLD DAYS GOODBYE ♪
♪ AND DREAM
♪ ON
I HAVE SOMETHING
I WANT TO SHOW YOU.
MAUDE SENT IT.
( chuckles )
WHOA.
WHAT'S ALL THIS MONEY?
EVIDENTLY HE WON IT
ON ONE OF THOSE LOCAL
CABLE ACCESS CHANNELS.
A GAME SHOW?
REALLY.
I GUESS TWIN FALLS
ROTARY CLUB DOES IT.
I'M SURPRISED
YOU HAVEN'T SEEN IT
BECAUSE IT'S CALLED
FISHERMAN'S FORTUNE.
SAYS IN THE NOTE.
( laughs )
FISHERMAN'S FORTUNE.
HOW DO YOU PLAY?
HOW THE HELL DO I KNOW?
HE DIDN'T EXACTLY
KEEP IN TOUCH, DID HE?
DID YOU?
I SENT HIM CHRISTMAS CARDS
SOMETIMES. I...I DON'T KNOW.
WHAT HAPPENED?
I
GOT TIRED.
JUNIOR...
JUNIOR.
STAN LEFT YOU, LIKE,
TWO THOUSAND BUCKS HERE.
DOES THAT MEAN HE CARED? YEAH.
THIS PRIZE MONEY
WOULD HAVE MEANT
THE WORLD TO STAN.
HEY!
JUNIOR TALMADGE.
LISTEN, I WAS THINKING,
UM...
WELL, YOU KNOW,
SINCE YOU HAVE
ALL THIS MONEY NOW,
I WAS THINKING THAT MAYBE,
UH, YOU'D WANT TO BUY ME LUNCH.
WELL, UM, MAUDE, UH--
IS SHE OKAY?
OH, YEAH. I MEAN,
SHE'S IN THE HOSPITAL, BUT--
WELL, AT LEAST SHE WAS
WEARING HER SEAT BELT--
BUT SHE HAD ASKED
IF I COULD
GET HER KNITTING
OUT OF THE MOTORHOME.
HMM.
THAT'S GRIM.
YEAH.
( laughs)
UM...
THANKS FOR SPENDING
MY DAD'S FUNERAL WITH ME.
( sniffling )
OH.
( laughs )
WOW.
HAVE YOU EVER BEEN TO THE TOP
OF THE EMPIRE STATE BUILDING?
♪ YOU MAKE ME
WANT TO WEAR DRESSES ♪
♪ YOU MAKE WE WANT TO
WEAR DRESSES ♪
♪ YOU LOOK AT ME SO FRAGILE
♪ YOU MAKE ME THINK ABOUT
NOTHING ♪
♪ IT FEELS SO GOOD LIKE THAT
♪ YOU LOOK AT ME SO FRAGILE
♪ SO FULL OF DESIRE
♪ WIDE, WIDE OPEN SPACES
♪ YOU MAKE ME
WANT TO WEAR DRESSES ♪
♪ WIDE, WIDE OPEN SPACES
♪ YOU MAKE ME
WANT TO WEAR DRESSES ♪
♪ YOU MAKE ME WANT TO
WEAR DRESSES ♪
♪ YOU LOOK AT ME
SO FRAGILE ♪
♪ WIDE, WIDE OPEN SPACES
♪ WIDE ,WIDE
OPEN SPACES ♪
♪ TAKE ME TO YOUR CASTLE
♪ IT FEELS SO GOOD IN THERE
♪ MUCH, MUCH SAFER
IN YOUR CASTLE ♪
♪ MINE GOT LOST SOMEWHERE
♪ YOU MAKE ME
WANT TO WEAR DRESSES ♪
♪ YOU MAKE ME WANT TO
WEAR DRESSES ♪
♪ ITS MUCH, MUCH SAFER
IN MY DRESSES ♪
♪ YOU MAKE ME
WANT TO WEAR DRESSES ♪
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/aj4js
Help other users to choose the best subtitles