A long time ago,
two friends took part
in an incredible race.
And together, they won first prize,
a red dune buggy with a yellow soft top.
Given that sharing it equally
was out of the question,
they wagered it
on a beer and hot dog eating contest.
But at the crucial moment,
a bad guy who was terrorizing the area
destroyed the bar they were eating in
and set fire to the dune buggy.
And so the two friends got mad,
and after smacks and slaps,
punches and blows,
the bad guy ended up buying them
two brand new dune buggies.
One each. Red with a yellow soft top.
But one of the dune buggies caught fire,
so only one remained.
And given that sharing it equally
was out of the question,
our two heroes kept fighting
over that dune buggy.
You're always so stubborn.
It was all your fault.
You know very well that isn't true.
You crashed into me.
I crashed into you...
I was only distracted for a second.
- Looking at that woman.
- What woman?
Nobody moves from here
until this is resolved.
Okay. Shall we play cards for it?
With a cheater? Let's arm wrestle instead.
- Now you're offending me.
- I'm too strong for you, huh?
Yeah, you wish!
How about we sort this out the usual way?
Beer and hot dogs?
No, not this time.
Let's have another race.
A race? You really want to lose, then.
If a car hadn't crashed into me,
I would've won.
Dad, are you gonna be long?
- Not now!
And don't you dare touch the car!
You're always making excuses.
Hey, come here!
But this is a dune buggy.
1200cc engine, 41 horsepower.
This goes over 140 km an hour.
Oh yeah.
What are you doing? Get out!
- Or what?
- Or Dad'll get mad.
He's already mad.
It doesn't matter.
Besides, this isn't our car.
"This isn't our car."
I don't talk like that!
- "I don't talk like that."
- Will you stop?
"Will you stop?"
Stop!
What if I let you drive first?
Where are you going? Get back here!
I said not to touch it!
I'm gonna kill them.
NETFLIX PRESENTS
I wouldn't stop.
- What if it were me in trouble?
- Do I have to answer that?
Thanks, guys.
We've run out of gas.
Nice car.
Aren't you too young to drive?
Aren't you ashamed
of driving around in that wreck?
The bike has a name. Bolt.
And nobody bad-mouths Bolt.
- Can I have a go?
- No.
How about this...
If you win, Bolt is yours.
What are we meant to do with a two-stroke?
- Let him finish.
- Get off me.
If I win, you let me
take a ride in your car. You in?
- No.
- Deal!
Okay, the Virgin Mary wins,
St. Anthony and St. Januarius lose.
Watch.
At least pay attention.
This one loses.
This one wins.
Saint Anthony loses.
Does this win or lose? I can't remember.
This one wins.
Where's the Virgin Mary?
I think you're out of luck.
Get I...
The dealer always wins.
You only had to pay attention!
He'll be back.
Yeah, for sure.
MANY YEARS LATER
STROKE
Nice doggy.
Hi, doggy.
Hey, karasho.
At least you have a friend. Lovely.
Come here, Geremia.
My goodness, so grumpy. Like a bear.
- How much?
- Fifty.
Fifty?
What a thief.
I'm a thief?
Okay, here you go.
Fifty.
The Cobras.
Fuck, the Cobras!
- It's the Cobras!
- Run away!
WOLAND CIRCUS
CRAZY 4 RALLY
FIRST PRIZE: DUNE BUGGY
Where are you going?
Let me go!
- I like feisty women.
- Oh yeah?
Does your boyfriend know?
You have two days to sign and leave.
Torsillo has lost his patience!
Two days!
Two!
Hey.
I've had it with you too.
Hey, fatso. You heard what I said, right?
Hurt him, Scajo!
Let me go.
Now he'll batter him.
Kill him!
Where are you going?
I'll get the money next time.
Let me go!
The coward runs away!
Thanks, you can drop me here!
You thought you could cheat us?
Next time, you're dead!
SMILEY
Ta-da!
I'm good. How are you?
Not even a hug?
Come on, come here!
I get it. You don't want to talk to me.
But I'm convinced
that you've seen it too.
We can get it back together, you and I.
Isn't it a great idea?
But why?
Is that how things are?
Fine, I'll win the buggy alone!
And if I win,
I won't give it to you! It'll be all mine!
I'll keep the kart for myself!
And welcome to Crazy 4 Rally!
A cutthroat race.
A blaze of insanity,
gas, and testosterone.
How pumped are you, folks?
Remember why we're here.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the man who needs no introduction.
A man blessed
with the divine gift of charisma.
A man so handsome
that when he looks in the mirror,
he'd kiss himself!
What's this guy on about?
Basically, let's give a big round
of applause for Flavio Torsillo!
Enough.
Hi. Go for it.
Good luck. May the best man win.
Is he dense?
Good luck.
And this race is even more special
because of a spectacular prize,
a 1974 dune buggy!
Who will win?
Who will be the most reckless driver?
So, are we ready to rumble?
Five,
four,
three,
two,
one!
Come on!
Damn it!
See you later!
How pumped are you?
Perfect! That's the spirit!
It's stuck, for fuck's sake!
No, he's hopeless.
Scajone, let's go.
- Aren't you gonna watch your son?
- What's there to see?
Put your hat on. Open the door.
Wow! Insane!
I cannot believe my eyes!
Plot twist, folks!
The cars have rolled over.
Where are the drivers?
Damn it.
There they are!
They're continuing on foot, folks!
The first race without cars!
And without an audience!
I'm the only one still here.
Unfair shouldering! A few meters to go!
Here they are,
about to reach the finish line.
They've done it, folks!
Mine!
Champions!
Super champions!
So, how does it feel
to win a 1974 dune buggy?
Exactly! That's the spirit!
I don't want to destroy these emotions.
I'll go and get the champagne.
Champions!
Good, keep working.
It was all set up for me to win.
All the cars were the same,
only my engine was souped-up.
I really don't know how I lost.
What did you say?
- That the cars were the same.
- No, after that.
I said that mine was souped-up.
After that.
After that...
What did I say after that, Dad?
From the outside, someone may
have got the impression that you lost.
But that's only an impression.
No. But I really did lose, Dad.
You were there too.
In a race, fairness doesn't count.
Only the result counts.
A Torsillo never accepts losing.
That's why we always win.
Come with Dad. Come on.
Those guys have the car?
So you go and take it.
They won't just give it to me.
They'll never give it to me.
Of course not.
It's not like you go and say,
"Excuse me, can I please have it?"
Just mention the name Torsillo,
and they'll shit themselves.
And it's more fun getting things
when you don't deserve them!
"Torsillo."
Raniero, your father
is in a similar position.
He wants the land.
They won't give it to him.
Sure, it's their land.
So, what does Dad do?
Alfredo, how are you?
I can't feel my feet anymore.
Of course, honey. You've been locked
in a fridge for two hours.
It's best you accept quickly,
before your brain freezes.
I'm not selling.
That's my home.
When I say a clean job,
I mean a clean job.
Right.
I'll have to throw all the meat out
if he infects it with his germs.
- Right?
- Right.
What is it?
Excuse me.
- The cold, I don't know.
- Who did he take after?
Who'd he take after? Go on, close it.
No!
But why? I only wanted to take a ride.
Why?
Because until we resolve this,
the kart isn't moving from here.
- Oh yeah?
- Oh yeah.
You know I can take it
even without the keys if I want?
Really?
Go on, then.
Hold up.
If you find the joker, the buggy's yours.
Once was enough for me.
I don't play with cheats.
Watch it, I might get offended.
What if we settle it like the old days?
Like the old days?
I'm on a diet.
Hang on.
Fine, I get it.
- But what kind of diet?
- Dissociated.
Like you?
How long's it been since you cleaned?
This place is lacking a feminine touch.
Are you seeing anyone?
- Geremia, it's ready!
- No, apart from Geremia, I mean.
All right. I'm in.
Like the old days.
Just stay quiet. And still.
All right. But I'm driving.
They came back again.
Goddamn Cobras.
You've changed the decor.
What can I get you?
So, let's see...
Twenty pints and 20 hot dogs.
And 40 hot dogs.
And a vanilla ice cream. Thanks.
Ice cream cleanses.
Miriam.
Karasho!
They trashed everything.
They trashed the circus,
and you're here eating würstel?
What kind of man are you?
You're worse than the Cobras.
Don't let me see you again.
What are you looking at?
You must be a thief.
A thief? Me?
'Cause you've stolen my heart.
Oh my God.
How sweet.
- Shoot yourself.
- There we go.
She'll be the mother of my children.
Let's take a break.
The heart wants what it wants.
And you're all dirty here. Look.
If you quit, I win.
I'll be a minute.
I'm going to get my heart back.
What is this, a joke?
Look, it's nothing to do with me.
Change targets from time to time.
- Where is it?
- I don't know.
They stole it though.
SORAYA THE TIGER
WOLAND CIRCUS
En place.
So ray a.
She's so good.
I don't know. I smell something off.
That'd be the camel.
Don't worry.
These people love to haggle.
But I have a plan. Trust me. I'll sort it.
Stroke.
So ray a doesn't eat meat
unless I cut it first.
- Your friend's called So ray a? Cute.
- Shall I cut?
- No.
- Go on, cut.
No, don't cut. No.
- What are you doing here?
- The kart you stole is mine.
- Ours.
- Stole?
- Yep.
- We aren't thieves.
Nobody meant to imply
that you're thieves. No.
- Then get out of here.
- All right.
We have enough problems as it is.
Who do I need to talk to?
Armandino might know something.
But I'm warning you,
you'll need a translator.
Okay.
This is Armandino, my cousin.
Not so little, is he?
For 50 bucks, I'll translate.
- Fifty?
- Fifty.
Go on.
Armandi, come talk to these guys.
Hello, Mr. Armandino.
We have nothing against
your work as a thief.
Nice one.
Since you seem like
a distinguished, sensitive person,
you'll understand why we want it back.
He says I'm really pretty,
and he wants to bang me.
Tell him if he wants to die,
I'll sort that right out.
Tell him!
I'll tell him.
Listen, my cousin is mortified.
Really very, very sorry.
Yes, he stole your kart,
but he won't give it back.
- I won't give it back.
- He won't.
- He won't give it back.
- No?
- No.
- But smile!
He'll think you're disrespectful.
- Well done.
- Come on.
Why's he smiling?
He says I'm cheap but worth it.
I think they're trying to swindle us.
You're disrespecting me.
You're disrespecting my cousin!
Nobody talks about my cousin like that!
Nobody talks about my family like that!
- He says, "The kart is mine. Only mine."
- Mine!
- I'll never give it back!
- Never!
- I'll discuss it with the gentleman.
- Sure.
He says, "Give me the girl,
or I'll tear you apart."
Joseph, Mary, pizza, rabbit!
Fatty fatty, phone home.
Kara-karasho!
Fatty fatty?
He means you.
It doesn't hurt.
This is our tradition.
This is how we solve problems.
Good, isn't it? Come on.
Place your bets!
Twenty-five bucks on the first to fall!
The bet is 25 bucks on the first to fall.
No. I'm warming you up.
Get pumped. Let's go.
Come on.
Like in the American movie Over the Top!
Crush him!
No.
I'll whip your ass.
Armandino? Get up, my love.
Give me a hand.
- Good, huh?
- Good how?
- Ah, so that means you bet on...
- No.
- No?
No?
Freeze!
We need to talk business, you and I.
If you don't let go,
I swear on your old skank
of a mother I'll smash your face in.
My mother isn't old.
It sure is nice here.
I think I could get used to circus life.
No.
We're gonna make a "pacto."
I'll help you find the kart,
and you'll do something for me.
- Is the spit thing necessary?
- Necessary.
If it's necessary...
It was Raniero.
Torsillo's son.
I saw him leaving the bar.
His father is a very powerful man.
He has it all, and always wants more.
He wanted to take your kart.
He wants to take our land.
That's why he sends the Cobras
to threaten us.
But you could leave.
Aren't carnies drifters?
- No!
- No.
This is our home!
Five generations, it's our home!
You're causing all this fuss over a kart,
and I should leave my home?
Firstly, calm down.
Secondly, it's not just any old kart.
It's my father's kart.
So you see, we want the same thing.
Oh yeah? We want the same thing?
Thanks for the information.
Hey!
We have a "pacto."
We have "pacto."
Torsillo sure is a megalomaniac.
Look who's talking!
What's wrong?
I don't like it. I'm going back.
Where are you going?
You'd let me go alone?
- You're crucial to the plan.
- What plan?
- Mine.
- Right, exactly, yours.
You don't know Torsillo,
and I don't trust carnies.
- You're scared.
- Yeah, so scared!
Know what? If you hadn't stopped
to help those guys when we were kids,
the buggy would still be ours!
What did you say?
I said that if you hadn't stopped
to help those guys when we were kids,
the kart would still be ours.
- Really?
- Yeah.
You're the one
who wagered it on cards, dirty cheat!
"Dirty cheat."
- I don't talk like that.
- "I don't..."
- Stop it.
- "Stop it."
I know you.
Again.
Know what?
- I don't feel like fighting.
- Fine.
Help!
Fine.
I'll go on my own!
But if I find the buggy, it's mine.
What a hovel. Morning.
Always this one. Trust me.
Gentlemen,
I'd like to speak to Torsillo.
I wanted to bring my brother,
but he gets wound up too easily.
But I told him,
"You'll see. There are only
good people in there."
So, if anyone here is the boss,
step forward.
I felt that one.
That one too.
What do you want with Mr. Torsillo?
You wanna offer him a deal, right?
Getting warmer.
Torsillo Tower.
Boutique, spa, heavenly beaches, clubs,
and all this on zero-cost land.
With guaranteed building permits,
colluding police
who are ready
to turn a blind eye to laundering.
Mr. Tanaka wants to know more
about the land transfer.
Mere details.
Some residents still haven't signed
the transfer documents,
but I assure you
the local administration is on my side.
Mr. Tanaka.
If you aren't happy, you can leave.
The door is there. Know what I mean?
Please excuse Raniero.
You'd never know it, but he's my only son.
What the hell?
Sorry. You said to be meaner.
Sure, especially with them!
Kids today. He's young.
He's a dickhead.
So,
will you tell me one last thing?
Yes.
- He doesn't like motorcyclists.
- He who?
These are bad for you.
What's going on, Scajone?
I wouldn't wake him.
May I?
Excuse us for interrupting your meeting,
but we need to resolve a little issue.
Your son stole my kart.
Excuse me, our kart.
A red dune buggy with a yellow soft top.
Yes, to be exact.
Please excuse me for a moment.
We're fine here, thanks.
If you give us our kart back,
we'll leave as if nothing happened.
- All right, Dad, let's give them...
- Hey!
Or what?
I hadn't thought of it.
He hasn't thought of it.
Normally, I would've slit your throats.
But you're lucky.
I have other things to do right now.
Now go before I change my mind.
I'll give your little car back
at noon tomorrow.
Fine.
To my garage.
Oh, I forgot.
Sorry, something very important.
The carnies aren't leaving.
Goodbye. Thank you.
I'll leave this open.
Workers!
Staff these days are so unpredictable.
Translate.
There.
You know, you won't make it
to old age like that.
You won't make it to tomorrow.
What's the matter with you?
If it's about the carnies thing,
about me stealing that plastic...
Sorry I didn't tell you.
We were only meant to think of the car.
But if I hadn't made the pact with Miriam,
we wouldn't have found out.
- Really?
- Yeah.
You always think
you're the smartest guy around.
- But you're always first to get screwed.
- Not this again? I was 13!
If you'd really grown up,
you wouldn't make pacts with carnies.
First they take your finger,
then your arm, then...
There, exactly.
Brought my heart back?
Can I have a word?
You should've seen me. I kicked
the door in, knocked a couple out.
Then I took the model,
put it under my arm,
and said, "The carnies aren't leaving."
I did good, right?
Yeah.
Yes, but the war isn't over.
Torsillo needs to understand
this land is ours.
Yeah, I get it, but war seems
like a bit of an exaggeration.
I'm just interested in my kart, and...
I wouldn't want to complicate things.
- Adieu.
- What do you mean, "Adieu"?
Yeah, I wouldn't
want to complicate things.
What are you doing?
Waiting.
But it's midnight.
So go to sleep.
You have a long day ahead of you tomorrow.
- Me?
- Yeah.
Why?
Because you're leaving.
Breakfast?
Red dune buggy with a yellow soft top.
Indeed.
- Oh yeah.
- That's it.
What did I tell you?
Check it out.
- Beautiful, isn't it?
- Yeah.
- The line.
- Yeah, really beautiful.
It's just that I...
I remembered it a bit...
a bit...
- Bigger.
- No.
- No?
Mr. Torsillo.
Thank you. It's perfect.
Thank you.
It's just that there's
a little scratch here on the hood.
A little scratch remover,
it'll be good as new.
Scajone, this time
hurt them for real. Let's go.
Scratch remover?
That's it, though.
- Oops!
- Let's go, Raniero.
Here we go.
Come on. Let's go.
We made complete fools of ourselves.
You dickhead!
Go on, take it!
Stop him! Run, for fuck's sake!
What a cute little doggy.
Come here, doggy.
Don't touch Geremia!
Don't you dare!
What did that ugly brute do to you?
The bike!
And so, Smiley and Stroke
became two unlikely heroes.
"The Cobras won't be a problem anymore,"
said Smiley.
Woland Circus and all the inhabitants
of Tortuga were saved.
Torsillo was defeated and forced to flee.
The Cobras were destroyed,
and they all lived happily ever after.
The end.
What ending, Scajone?
I decide when it ends.
Is that clear?
I'm sorry, boss.
You're sorry?
I screwed up, Dad. I'm sorry.
Never apologize, ever!
Weaklings do that.
Dogs come crawling,
tails between their legs,
for shitting on the carpet!
Are you listening to me?
What are you thinking?
About dogs.
We could get a dog.
Get a...
- Have you hit your head?
- What? No.
Are you suffering from a form
of early-onset dementia?
I just think that
if we give them back the car,
they'll leave us alone. Get it?
No!
- Why not?
- That's your car!
Use it, sell it, destroy it!
Do whatever you like!
But first, teach those two hicks
who's in charge. Got it?
Yeah, got it.
But why should I sell it, sorry?
Do you know how many times
I've asked if you understand me?
- Many.
- Many!
Go and play with your little car.
Daddy'll sort it tomorrow.
Dickhead.
Don't take it personally.
That's just how he is.
He's been treating me badly for years,
but it's his way of showing affection.
Listen, I know how to be mean.
Yes, but just remember
that there are no laws stating
that kids have to follow
in their fathers' footsteps.
If you haven't got it,
you haven't got it.
Let him handle those two.
- Get the Cobras and follow me.
- What you got planned?
I'm gonna be mean.
I'm gonna be so mean, I'll scare myself.
Rani. Raniero!
Just don't say any stupid shit.
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to Woland Circus!
We're going to kick off the show
with our elephants!
Bravo!
Miriam!
Well?
Are you enjoying yourselves?
Brava!
- She hasn't done anything yet.
- You'll see.
Now,
Woland Circus's most dangerous act,
knife throwing.
But
I need a volunteer.
A man who's fearless,
brave,
ready to risk his life.
Me!
A round of applause.
You're good, right?
- First time.
- You're kidding?
No.
You aren't kidding?
I never kid.
If you don't kill me, I'll marry you.
She can't do it.
Brava!
- You didn't kill me.
- I don't like you.
Oh no?
The kart!
That's it.
You wanted your kart, right?
Here's your kart!
No.
Do something!
The kart!
What do...
- What do we do?
- Let's go!
- Head for the sea.
- No, I'm going to the garage.
- No!
- Yes, the sea will rust it.
I said no!
Go!
Here! Take this!
Get some jugs!
I told you, Scajone.
I'm scaring myself.
Right, boss.
Well, it could've been worse.
Geremia.
Geremia!
Sorry for leaving you alone.
You're burning, huh?
Maybe we're still in time to help Miriam.
Come on, let's go.
I'm not going anywhere.
What, sorry?
"What, sorry?"
Who helps me?
Nobody.
Know what?
I don't help anyone either,
especially you,
who always ruined everything as a kid
and still does now!
Look what you've done!
What did you expect? You'd fix everything
with a smile and a few jokes?
Know what?
I'm not mad at you. I'm mad at myself
for always saying yes
when I should always tell you no!
This time, it's a no!
Fine. I took a gamble, and I lost.
I'm sorry. One and for all, I'm sorry!
But you were there.
I didn't hold a gun to your head.
So accept your share of responsibility.
You can keep your precious kart.
I've always hated it anyway.
And I hate you!
Cousin.
So ray a the tiger ran away.
What do we do?
We'll find her.
Carnie friends, the game is simple.
Pay attention. The joker wins.
- Wins.
- The aces lose.
- Okay.
- Okay, Armandino?
- The joker?
- Wins!
- The aces?
- Lose.
Lose.
Shall we begin?
- This one.
- This one?
Olé!
I win!
Now do it again, but slower.
Slow! Like a snail.
- Got it?
- Got it.
Okay, gents. I'll remind you.
- The joker...
- Wins!
- The aces.
- Lose!
- This one!
- This one?
Who wins...
- No!
- Yes, I win!
- Hey!
- What's wrong?
I can explain.
Son of a bunny!
I'm gonna kill you. I'm gonna punch you.
I can explain.
What's up?
Pardon, madame.
Ah yes.
I'm not giving you 50 bucks.
It's not about the 50 bucks.
You're going the wrong way.
Torsillo's mansion is that way.
I'd put him down.
Unfortunately, we need him in one piece.
You were lucky today.
Thanks.
Know what? I've thought about it, and...
something's not quite right.
- Right?
- Right.
It needs the soft top.
- Yeah, because we liked it yellow.
- Yeah.
- We liked it yellow.
- Yellow, yeah.
It looks kinda...
smoky.
- Flambé.
Shall we go and tell him?
- I'd say so.
- You drive, though.
Well, what are we waiting for?
Karakasho!
- Karakasho!
- Yeah!
Karakasho!
Grab the money. Come on, let's go!
Karakasho.
Thank you. Thank you all for coming.
Let's go.
Dear friends and business partners,
I'm delighted to see you here
on such an important day.
As you know,
the flames burned high all night.
But opportunity can rise from a tragedy.
Although we weep over the terrible fire
that destroyed Woland Circus,
we also rejoice
for the wonderful flow of concrete
which today the trucks of our...
No!
Sorry. A glitch in the program.
Where was I?
Before the interruption,
you said, "of our..."
I don't know what...
Although we weep over the terrible fire
that destroyed Woland Circus,
we also rejoice
for the wonderful flow of concrete...
- You've already said that.
- Of concrete. Crete!
Scajone, go check it out.
No!
You again!
Yeah. The kart you gave us is no good.
The soft top is missing. It's strange.
- That's true.
- See? It's not yellow.
- It's not yellow.
- We want a new one.
What will you do otherwise?
- Otherwise...
Otherwise we'll get mad.
Oh yeah? I'd love to see that.
Ouch!
Stop! Stomach, rabbit, shark, pea?
Charge!
Idiots. Come on, let's go!
Take off that damn frock!
Drop dead. What is this, Carnival?
I'll show them.
Torsillo!
It's over.
Really?
Oh no!
It really does work, Dad.
Ah yes, this is the real end of our story.
The circus was reconstructed,
the carnies had their home back,
and everything went back to normal
for the residents of Tortuga.
Even the red dune buggy
with a yellow soft top
was returned to our heroes who, however,
had a minor outstanding issue to settle.
How do you manage it?
It's genetic.
Keys on the table.
Hey, guys. Payment in advance, yeah?
Fair enough. Pay up.
Well...
Good.
You ready?
Ready! We're all starting the game!
Everyone for Paul Newman raise hand!
Three, two, one!
Freeze!
No.
You burned down my circus with that kart.
We have "pacto."
I'm playing too.
No. This is between me and him.
If he wins, and he won't win,
you two can sort it out.
Okay.
Bonadei, honey.
Bonadei...
Take care, karasho.
The fight's about to begin!
Three, two, one!
No!
What a woman!
Ah yes. Like all great stories,
this one doesn't have an end.
The dune buggy will probably
never really belong to anyone.
There, look what they've done.
Everything destroyed. Everything smashed.
Look what you've been reduced to.
It was a big cat.
I punched it in the head. I crushed it.
But it can't end like this.
Otherwise, what will we do?
Otherwise we'll get mad. We will.
Right!
Are you sure?
What horrible anxiety.
Action!
Go on.
- Oh, it won't break.
- Action!
Go on!
Hang on, I burned myself.
I know you.
Again!
You know what?
- I don't feel like fighting.
- Fine.
- Me? Let me try De Sica.
- Try De Sica.
- Start rolling.
- You again?
Yeah. The kart you gave us is no good.
- It has scratches on the side.
- Yes, and it hasn't got the soft top.
We want a new one.
Hang on.
What will you do otherwise?
- Otherwise...
We'll get mad.
- Cut.
- Was that a false start?
That hurt.
- Me too.
- Cut!
- Now!
- Brava!
Why did you talk? I have to say "brava."
Brava!
- If he hadn't...
- And now, our most dangerous act.
- Knife throwing.
- Hey!
It's because he came in...
Otherwise, what will you do?
- Otherwise...
Are you sure?
What horrible anxiety.
Look at this guy.
Hang on. Let's do another take.
Fine. Give me a good one.
Three, two, one!
How do you mean?
From the top!
Action.
- Otherwise...
Otherwise we'll get mad.
We were one voice, one being.
Subtitle translation by: Jaclyn McLoughlin