START
When they say it's a boy,
I feel strong,
and backed up.
When they say it's a girl,
the walls fall down on me.
I can hear you singing.
You always sang that song.
You always used to say that
giving birth to a girl
means lifelong worries.
Why is giving birth to a girl
a lifelong worry?
Why should I be afraid of my body,
and cover it up?
Be afraid of my voice, and lower it,
and be afraid of my laughter,
and suppress it?
Why should I be afraid of love?
Because love is forbidden.
You used to say,
''You can hang your diploma
on the kitchen wall.''
The best place for a woman
is her husband's home.
A girl is trapped inside this circle.
She is being sexually assaulted.
Right now,
four hands are inside her pants.
Four more inside her blouse.
Ten men are pulling her
in all directions.
One of them is now taking
her shoes off,
so that his friend
can strip her from her pants.
One is grabbing her,
saying he's protecting her.
In fact, he's one of them;
his hand is now inside her underwear.
One is taking his pants off
to give to her.
Another his jacket,
a third is covering her.
But tens are trying to prevent them
with knives.
She can't breathe
from the shoving and pulling.
She is fainting.
But Thank God,
she has no scarf,
like the girl who nearly got choked,
or the one who got a knife inside her,
and the others who were kidnapped.
but who managed to escape.
Or like the mother assaulted
before her kids.
Those girls were publicly gang-raped.
First of all,
I'm a friend of Yasmine,
who was sexually assaulted.
Are you the owner of this red shirt?
Yes.
I'm using a fake name,
because, to society I am a disgrace.
I won't go into details
about what happened
because it happened to many girls,
and is still happening every day.
This reality is the result
of a sickness in our society,
which has stayed silent
for many years.
Women are not even allowed
to exercise their rights.
I feel ashamed of being Egyptian.
I feel disgusted and oppressed.
What's happening to women
is a crime,
a heinous crime.
It is happening to girls
as young as 14 years old.
Raped in the middle of Tahrir Square,
and society
still puts the blame on them.
Since there is no law,
no police to protect us,
and no society to take our side
and protect our rights,
I and many other women
have decided
to defend ourselves,
in any way we deem fit,
against sexual harassment.
That's my best friend talking, Mamma.
I think if I had been in her place,
I would never have told you.
Because, you would have blamed me,
and said, ''Why did you go there?''
You were there at the beginning,
but assaults gradually increased,
and got harsher.
Each story I hear
is uglier than the other.
when I arrived...
Well, in most cases
when you reach the girl,
struggling your way,
she'd already been assaulted.
But you try to get her out
before it gets even worse.
When I arrived,
it was over
They had raped the girls.
In the attack that I saw,
they didn't take girls
from a group.
A group of thugs
attacked the tents
in Omar Makram garden
in the middle of the sit-in.
People were attacked
during the sit-in.
The thugs started grabbing girls
and sexually assaulting them.
I had one thing in my mind:
I wasn't going to leave
without those girls.
I suddenly heard calling,
''Anyone needs an ambulance?''
It was impossible
to get the girls out.
There were several of them.
Were they stripped off?
The one that was with me,
she was stripped off,
but a boy gave her a jacket.
Her pants were not torn off.
they slit open her pants
and managed
to rip her panties off.
Her bra was ripped off.
It was in shreds.
Her top was shredded.
It was hanging off her body.
The ambulance arrived,
and we managed to move the girls out.
I was helping the guy out.
I said, ''I am with them
I am in charge of them.''
There was this man yelling,
''Get out of the way!''
He acted like he wanted to help,
but I could feel his hand on me.
I said,
''Are you assaulting me or what?''
''Are you trying to help me
or assault me?''
I started to scream at them,
that I didn't want any help,
or anyone coming near.
We finally got into the ambulance.
I thought we were safe.
But no...
What happened next
was another battle...
Getting out of the ambulance...
Everyone jumped onto the ambulance.
The only hope was to go to hospital.
Because it is a secure place.
Anyone hanging onto the ambulance
would run away.
They couldn't follow us
into the hospital.
It was good and bad.
Good because we escaped the crowd,
hanging onto the ambulance.
Bad, because we had to deal with
security forces and military police.
The girl said ''I want to go to the bathroom''
''I want to be sure I'm still a virgin''
''Sara, I need to go to the bathroom.''
I said, ''OK, calm down.
We will go now.''
She said,
''They put their hands inside me.''
''Their fingers went inside me.''
I said, ''Calm down''.
''You don't have to tell me
what happened now.
''Calm down first,
''then we can talk.''
Then she said,
''Thank God, my sister was out.
''Just before the attack,
she went to get food.
''Thank God...
''I want to call her
and tell her not to go back.''
I lent her my phone
so she could call.
She said, ''I'm fine,
nothing happened to me.''
Her sister said,''What's wrong?
I heard what happened!''
She said, ''I'm fine,
nothing happened,
''Nothing happened to me, I'm fine.
''Just don't tell Mamma.
Don't say anything.''
So...
there was someone from the Security,
some informant I guess.
And also military police officers.
They said they wanted to talk to us.
They asked if something
had happened to us.
They suspected
something had happened to us.
Not just to the girl.
She stayed quiet.
I was the one talking.
I said nothing happened.
He said,
''You don't want the test?''
I said,
''No, I don't, what for?''
- What test?
Virginity test
I said, ''No, nothing happened.''
So the police put you
into a room at the hospital because...
I think they knew what was happening.
That's why I think it was organized.
They understood what was going on.
When we finally left,
I told her in the car,
I'm not telling you
to write your testimony or anything
But when you feel ready to write it,
the way you want,
or to talk about it,
I'll help you.
And then,
I was so glad, because on the 25th of January
I was in the Shobra protest,
she was at Mostafa Mahmoud
She saw Hazem
and told him, ''Tell Sara
I went back to the streets again.''
I was so happy...
Because when I went out on the street,
that's what I wanted to see.
They need to know
they won't break us.
We will keep coming back.
And we did.
We know this a form of repression.
But they will fail,
because we're not a disgrace.
Maybe we haven't accomplished
the goals of the Revolution yet,
but, a big part of it
was to show people
how important our role is.
That we are not afraid.
And that the Revolution
without women is...
I don't want to say nothing but...
It can't continue without us.
The biggest proof is when
they tried to destroy the Revolution,
they targeted women.
That's it...I have nothing to add.
My God, you are strong, Sara.
You made me cry.
The image is powerful.
It's proof.
It's difficult to erase
from ones memory.
That's why
I used my camera as a weapon.
To protect myself...
and face myself at the same time.
Want to grab that beautiful ass.
What do you want to grab?
-What do you want to grab?
-The bag.
-Why?
-Be quiet she's filming.
-You're filming?
-Yes.
Sure I'm filming.
So when I am harassed in the street,
I'll have proof.
If I want to sue,
I have evidence.
Understand?
Can I feel your tits?
God give me patience!
If you go out dressed like that,
I'm sorry, but
anything could happend to you
You must be careful.
You need to protect your self.
Because no one else will.
Nowadays, boys watch satellite TV,
they watch porn on the internet.
They're already aroused.
Don't arouse them even more.
That's all I'm trying to say.
The woman is like a diamond.
Her place is in the home.
Is that wrong, or what?
I wonder what your life
would be like without women.
If God had wanted to create man
without woman, he could have.
God created the woman
from Adam's rib.
-From the rib of a man.
-How's that?
-How was she created?
-You were born from a woman.
Your mother,
who bore you, gave birth to you.
Woman came out of Adam's rib.
Why don't they still come out
of his rib?
That's God's will.
That was the beginning of creation.
Boys don't bring disgrace, girls do.
A girl can bring to her family...
You know.
-Disgrace.
-Isn't it so?
If I had a 100 boys,
they wouldn't worry me
as much as one girl.
What's your name?
My name is Samaher.
-Samaher?
-Yes. Stand still.
Then I can stand still.
You think you're right,
you're not doing anything wrong?
What am I doing wrong?
When you walk like that,
showing your legs.
Surely some guys
will say somethings...
There are men who wear shorts.
Why is it permitted for them?
They are men, we are women.
A woman's body is shameful.
A woman's voice is shameful.
-Did you learn that at school?
-Yes, we learn it at school.
-Why is your face covered?
-Because of my husband.
Your husband?
This is our environment.
I mean no offense, but you're
from a different environment.
You live in Heliopolis.
I live in the countryside.
By the way,
I wore the headscarf for eight years.
But then you tried to change.
Because faith is in the heart.
You were able to change.
Here, if a woman is loud in public
her husband divorces her.
If your wife didn't wear a headscarf,
what would you do?
What we would do in the countryside,
divorce her.
After a man divorces her,
the woman is homeless.
They say you are going to hell.
-Me?
-Yes.
-Why am I going to hell?
-Because you have revealing clothes.
What do you mean?
Your dress is short.
And your hair shows.
-And what do you think?
-I think everyone is free.
You are beautiful.
I feel I want to go back in time
-there.
How strange.
When I exit the picture,
and look at it from the outside,
I can see you
in every part of the house.
In every corner.
I sense you around me.
You were 16
when you got married.
Like your daughter,
and your grand daughter.
It was my big sister
Manal's wedding.
I replayed the tape over and over,
looking at you.
Your face is beautiful.
You look so young.
I was 13 years old.
It was the first time in my life
that you didn't braid my hair.
You told me to let my hair
down on my back.
You said,
''It will soon be your turn
to get married.''
I thank my memory
for not failing me yet.
It is the only way,
to save the picture.
Silence your phones, guys.
OK...
auntie, start from here.
This is your mark, auntie.
And you stop here.
What's the matter?
What are you doing?
Let's start again.
When I say ''Action''.
How many times do we have to do this?
What's wrong? You're still here?
Still sitting here?
The groom and his family
are waiting for you.
This is shameful.
We'll make you do all the housework.
No friends, no school, nothing.
I never stopped to think of
the childhood I was in.
It wasn't a dream.
Everything was real.
From her soft nails
With marriage she is crowned
They said,
''The Constitution is our Koran.''
As if our Constitution
is something wonderful.
The Imam El Banna,
peace be upon him,
said,
''The Koran that is our Constitution.''
-The Koran is our Constitution!
-It was and it will be!
The Koran
will always be our Constitution!
The Koran is our Constitution!
And the Prophet is our leader!
The Prophet is our leader!
And Jihad is our path!
Jihad is our path!
Egypt will only see
rebirth and revival
through Islamic Sharia law.
Where are you from?
Step back a little.
From Egypt.
-From Egypt?
-Yes.
-What's your name?
-Zein.
Where do you live?
In downtown.
Are you originally from Egypt,
or from another country?
Another country but...
Where is Mamma from?
-France?
-Mamma, where am I from?
You're from...
You're from Downtown...
to Downtown...
I am from Palestine.
-You're from Palestine.
-Yes.
Next to the Downtown.
It's not next to the Downtown.
Come inside, Mamma!
Why are you crying?
Those are crazy people.
-Crazy people.
-But why are they doing that?
Because they're crazy.
They are fighting each other.
-Please don't cry.
-Now it will be fixed again.
-What my dear?
-The coffeeshop.
Why are you crying? Please don't cry.
Because I don't know what's happening.
Don't cry my love.
I don't know anything.
Just relax inside.
Unbelievable...my son is terrified.
Don't be scared, they're crazy.
I'm scared.
They're just nuts,
they don't know what they're doing.
They are crazy.
Why...Because the bad guy here...
Because they're fighting like that.
We don't like that.
I want the iPad.
Let me read you a story instead.
SEXUAL HARASSMENT HAPPENS HERE
BECAUSE THERE ARE NO LIGHTS.
Janet, why did you choose
Sadat metro station?
On January 25th, 2013...
A girl got trapped
in front of that gate,
the gate you see there.
She was raped here
because there was no light.
Here it is, Samaher.
You had done a big poster.
Exactly.
-I remember.
-Remember that girl?
Of course.
Did you see the video
with the red circle?
Yes, Aïda's film.
This is the girl
who was in the red circle.
Her hymen was lacerated.
The doctor said she had wounds,
ulcers and boils,
because she didn't see
a doctor right away.
She went about a week later.
Because she had persistent fever.
Caused by the dirty fingers and nails
that went inside her.
Like dirty dogs that snatched her.
Her hands still shake
as a result of the trauma.
A little pat makes her jump away.
Even when she knows
it's you patting on her shoulder.
She can't bear anyone touching her.
Neither a man nor a woman.
We must consider a woman
as a human being
in order to respect her.
As long as she's seen as merely meat,
veiled or not,
she's only meat.
If a woman is looked at as an object,
then she can be treated like this...
Or like this.
She's just an object,
with no feelings.
Society also looks at her
as an object.
From her father's house,
to her husband's, to the grave.
That's how we see women here.
The campaign we are working on,
where women must take part,
is to boycott elections.
They are always praising women
when they line up to vote.
And stand in line
and add their voice,
and take part
in the political process.
Since I have an active political role
as a woman,
as confirmed by statistics,
sixty percent of voters are women,
why can't I be elected?
Why are you asking for my vote
if I can't sit in Parliament?
You need my vote
to sit in Parliament,
while it won't get me there.
If I can't be a candidate,
you don't deserve my vote.
If I have no right to be elected,
you have no right to ask for my vote.
The problem is much larger
than sexual harassment.
The real issue
is how men think of women.
It has to change.
We need legislation.
Even if we have a law, some people will still
consider us as a thing.
Pass as many laws as you want,
men will still view women as objects.
something inferior to them.
We have to change.
That's my point.
We, the women
have to change ourselves.
When women change,
society will change
If we are able to grow these ideas
in the minds of every women,
then, believe me, society will change.
Of course, there are
a lot of shitty things
but I think this is easy.
It's not hard. Women are strong.
Women are not weak.
I mean, I'm sure,
when you were inside that red circle,
and in the tent and in the ambulance,
I'm sure that a part of what
prevented you from being attacked
like the girl that was with you
was your confident reaction.
how you were brought up
and your background
made you react
in a certain way to that situation.
And by the way, when I was...
When our friend told us
what happened to the girl,
we were all moved.
For a long time,
I was imagining this happening to me.
I mean for weeks.
When I'm in the street, and you know
I'm as strong as seven men,
But deep inside I'm afraid.
I have fear inside.
But I try not to show it.
Because if my fear shows,
I'm finished.
I'd be an easy target.
It's better to meet at the protest.
-Are you alone?
-I can go meet her.
Do you prefer to come with us?
instead of going alone.
All right then.
Ok dear, bye.
I'll take my bag.
And put the knife in my jacket.
Look, she's filming us.
Watch out, driver. Watch out!.
It's because of
the harassment incidents?
Not only I will carry a knife.
Many girls will.
So attackers
will get a knife in the guts.
Uncivilized behavior is spreading.
Sexual harassment is not new.
But we never talk about it.
If every girl defends herself...
A lot of girls will carry weapons,
and we'll see who can get near them.
From now on, I will carry a knife.
They say a woman's voice
is shameful!
A woman's voice is revolution!
They say a woman's voice
is shameful.
A woman's voice is revolution!
Raise you voice louder and louder!
Make women's voices heard
in every square!
Hey harasser, take off your hand!
Hey harasser, tell your master
We will cut your hands!
If you are asking who we are,
we are the women of the Revolution!
Down! Down!
With the brotherhood government !
Down with the Morshid!
-The Muslim Brotherhood?
-Illegitimate!
-And the Constitution?
-And the election?
-Illegitimate!
-And sexual harassment?
Egypt's women are a red line!
We cannot be disrespected.
Egyptian girls are
the strongest girls in the world!
No one can touch them!
Or dishonor them!
We are strong! We are not weak.
Do you hear, Egyptian men!
I say to all women,
''Carry a kitchen knife in the street,
don't let anyone get near you.''
Keep your head high!
You are more honorable
than your oppressor!
They say a woman's voice is shameful!
A woman's voice is revolution!
Why were we born dominated, Mamma?
Imprisoned.
Stifled.
Mamma, what's this diploma?
It's when I was young.
What did you study?
Nutrition.
-You studied nutrition?
-Yes.
-Really?
Don't film me,
I'm uncovered,
You're not uncovered, come on!
We only see your head.
You're wearing a sleeveless top.
But you wouldn't let us
wear cut
-Why can't we?
-I wore it once for the photo.
You now have a great granddaughter.
She looks like her father.
How does it feel like, Manar,
to be a mom?
An amazing, indescribable feeling.
He didn't attend the wedding it seems.
Did he attend?
Why didn't you go daddy?
Because I was against it.
She is still young.
They arranged a marriage for her.
They married her off,
and she is still young.
Are you happy that you're a mom?
Or do you think it's still early,
or just normal?
It's nice.
It's nice and not nice.
Why is it nice?
And why is it not nice?
It's nice because it keeps you busy,
when you have nothing to do.
And not nice because...
I'm still young, and not used to this.
That's true.
-Come here.
-You want to film my stomach!
You are the pregnant grandmother!
-Step back so we see you're pregnant,
carrying you daughter's daughter.
Turn this way...how lovely!
Manal, you became a grandmother!
In this picture,
grandma looks so much like you.
Is there anything else
you wanted to do, Mamma, but couldn't?
-Samaher, take out your camera.
-I already did.
He's going to block the way.
He'll ask you why you're filming.
He's an officer.
Let me see what you filmed.
Why are you harassing us?
-I'm not talking to you.
-I am the one who's filming.
Can we see your ID?
Your zipper's undone, by the way.
So what? I like feeling the air.
Give me the camera.
I won't give you the camera.
-Really?
-No, I won't.
Bring me the camera.
Stop the cars.
Go ahead and stop all the cars!
I won't give you the camera.
Your zipper is open,
and you want my camera?
Why are you following us?
-Want to know why I am filming?
-Why?
The guys behind were harassing us.
-Who was harassing you?
-You are one of them.
We were on the road, sweetheart.
Get lost!
Go, go!
Careful
Strong girl!
Yes!
You are unbelievable!
I never saw something like that!
I did it!
Yes!
Crazy, crazy, crazy,
We are crazy.
Did you see?
It is a revolution to question
what it means to be a woman.
The issue is the wrong understanding
of femininity.
To me the issue is what it means
to be a man or a woman?
That was my point.
Why does our identity as women
make us feel weak?
Because we suffer from constant
gender oppression by men,
in our society.
So a lot of our energy
is going into opposing men.
I am stared at
because of my tits and my ass?
Because of my top?
Well, let a man come and show me
what he's going to do about it!
You, Samaher, Salma, Rasha, and I
are resisting.
We're being very courageous out there.
We are not afraid.
It's as if we are fighting,
because we are women,
for something we didn't choose to be.
Something we can't change,
because this is who we are.
The issue is not
being a man or a woman.
It is about being a human being.
That's all.
Here I am theorizing!
How the hell did it flip over?
How did this happen?
-Was there anyone inside?
-No. No one.
-Hello.
-Hi.
Hi, how are you?
Wow, nice!
-This is new, right?
-I love this one.
Yes, this is new.
Your drawing about sexual harassment,
it's very powerful.
It stirs your feelings.
This reminds me
of the Sayeda Zeinab demonstration.
When women went to the protest
holding knives.
Every drawing you were making...
No flattery...
Every drawing made me feel
like we were on the right track.
This is what made me start my project.
I felt a change was possible.
You did the drawings,
another talked about her experience.
Other girls started taking photos.
This is the beginning
of something great.
The women's rage is beautiful.
-It is full of hope
-Yes.
I'm just thinking about the idea of...
Feeling the need to have a shawl on
when you go out.
At first, we feared
they would impose the hijab on us.
But, this is not what worries me most.
It's rather the idea that we'll end up
wearing it without even noticing.
Five years ago,
I used to go out bare-armed.
Now, I put on a shawl instinctively.
Then gradually,
I'll start covering my hair,
and my face.
And not leave the house
-without even noticing.
I never felt so vulnerable before.
To me it was a shock,
as I suddenly realized
what it meant to be a woman,
in this country,
but also in general.
It is destabilizing
when you start thinking about
something self-evident.
As if you 're forced to think
about having five fingers
I AM WITH THE ARAB
WOMEN'S REBELLION
BECAUSE WE ARE
THE REVOLUTIONARY WOMB
WOMEN OF THE WORLD
GIVE BIRTH TO CHILDREN
EGYPTIAN WOMEN
GIVE BIRTH TO HEROES
We were at the
Attorney General's office,
to submit complaints
against the President
for his shameful silence.
It is a disgrace.
It is an insult to remain silent
in the face of violence against women.
The more they will attack us,
and attack our bodies and our rights,
the more we will escalate back
to reclaim our rights.
We won't stay silent any more.
What will we say to Morsi?
Resign!
We will not forget that tomorrow,
March 9th, is the anniversary
of all the brave girls,
who stood against the police,
and who were virginity tested.
What will we say to them?
I'm not afraid
like I was in the past!
There are still women in the squares!
The women have said their word!
They will trample the Morshid!
The women said it loud!
We don't want the Brotherhood!
Yes, I'm chanting
against the Morshid!
No matter how,
we will bring Morsi down!
I was in the middle
of all those women, Mamma,
I felt strong and brave.
and tore out all the anger
that's been inside me for years.
I was among them,
and with them.
And thanks to them,
I went deep inside myself.
Here...
...in this hallway,
your screams echo in my head,
that day when your son dragged me,
holding a knife in his right hand,
and pulling my hair with his left.
That day is engraved in my memory.
You wanted to kill me
because of a photo.
I remember very well.
I spent 3 days
sleeping under the bed from fear.
A whole year locked down in the house.
Six months of silence,
You used to say to dad,
''You spoiled that girl.''
Why did he spoil me?
Because he never
lifted his hand against me?
Or is it because he thought
girls should be educated.
DEAR SAMAHER,
CONGRATULATIONS.
YOU HAVE BEEN ACCEPTED
BY THE EGYPTIAN HIGHER
INSTITUTE OF CINEMA STUDIES
She wants to travel?
If she mentions travelling
and study again, she's dead.
Where does she think
she comes from?
Calm down. It's God's will.
She's listening to you,
and I will also talk to her.
I told myself in order
to survive
I had to escape and fly away.
Someday, I'll be
who I want to be
That's it.
Careful with the wing.
Pull!
How did it got tangled up like that?
Great, Rasha!
When the Brotherhood arrests you!
Shout for help, don't be afraid!
Tell the Morshid to go away!
If we are one, ten or a hundred,
we will shout and make it loud!
HONK IF YOU HATE
THE BROTHERHOOD
WE WANT A FREE COUNTRY
NOT A BROTHERHOOD COUNTRY
We are here to prepare
against any sexual harassment
that might happen
on June 30th, 2013.
I'm going to show a short,
three-minute film.
We hope that this won't happen again,
in Egypt, or anywhere on earth.
A girl is trapped inside this circle.
She is being sexually assaulted.
These girls are being gang-raped.
Those girls thought
they will never get out alive.
But we won't keep silent.
We won't be broken.
This revolution is ours,
and we will fight
until our last breath.
The first means for self-defense
is to be strong yourself.
Second,
in your bag is your defense kit:
A deodorant or a perfume spray,
or a Hijab pin.
You use the strap
of the bra for the pin
Like this.
You see.
You wear your shirt on top.
Imagine it under there,
and I'am wearing a shirt on top.
There is the tip that doesn't cut.
If someone is attacking me
from the front or from behind...
And if it is more than one, Janet?
Try to hurt as many
as you can!
You do what you can.
Down with the Morshid!
You sold the Revolution,
Mohamed Badiea!
Sell Sell Sell!
The Revolution ya Badiea!
Down with the Morshid!
Look at these men.
I am filming you.
Three girls are worth a 100 men.
Don't even think of getting near them.
Without them, you are useless.
You are just standing there, watching.
Why don't you chant with them?
If you don't want the Brotherhood,
chant with them.
Come and shoot us with your snipers!
There's still room in my chest
for a bullet!
You can muzzle our freedom!
Shameful Morshid
and lying President.
Write on all the walls!
The President is lying to us!
You pretend to be the Guide!
But you're only a phony President!
We don't want them
to do this to us again.
If anything happens, call.
We'll come right away.
Keep our number with you
I want to go up
Grab her.
I want to.
Wait a minute.
What? Why can't I film?
No no no
Why?
-She should not film.
-Why?
Why shouldn't I?
Don't film.
Why don't you want me to film?
There are all these cameras around...
I'm asking you.
Don't film what's hapenning here.
-Don't film.
-Why not?
I'm asking you.
Don't touch me!
-Look, see!
-Wait, wait!
Yes, I'm leaving.
That guy is one of them.
Instead of telling me
not to film,
go protect the Egyptian women.
If you were true men,
you'd go protect the women!
I want to expose
what these guys are doing.
You are just standing here,
while young women
are being assaulted right there.
Are you real men or what!
Of all the people with cameras,
they picked on me.
I want to go on top of this building
to shoot.
How can I get on top?
Can you see this amazing scene, Mamma?
It was like a dream
but real.
I was very curious,
to go and see what they
do there
inside the red circle.
I felt I wanted to freeze the image
in front of me
In order to be a witness,
and have proof.
In order not to forget.
To be able to decide for ourselves,
and be able to...
That's a surprise.
We didn't know
he was making a speech.
-It's coming from outside and inside.
-A lot louder outside!
Unbelievable!
I shall not tolerate
that we be attacked.
The cafés are empty.
No one's listening.
Egypt will continue
with its legitimate people,
institutions, President, and laws
Resign! Resign!
They're Brotherhood members.
Wait, Zeinab, don't get too close.
I'm scared.
-What if people start to run away?
-We'll also run, that way.
Come on!
Leave me alone!
They're shooting bullets.
You sons of bitches!
They will make the
country fall
The country is falling
because of one man.
They shot real bullets,
and shotgun pellets.
What can we do?
They created chaos.
The army will clean them up.
The Army told the people to come out.
They want the world to know
it's not a coup.
That's what the people want.
I have goosebumps.
They took advantage of the situation.
Once the protesters
got what they wanted, they went home.
The people who are protesting now
are pro-Morsi.
Are you enjoying seeing me like this?
What is happening?
We cant' leave the square!
Sit down.
Our friends are getting killed !
We will return there, calm down.
Let go of me!
Free revolutionaries!
We will complete the journey
We will complete the journey!
Revolution until victory comes!
Revolution in every street!
We won't give up, we won't betray!
We won't leave Egypt
to that dog Badiea.
During the last months,
the armed forces
strived to set an agreement
between the diverse political forces,
including the President.
But the speech of Mr. President,
yesterday evening,
did not fulfill
the demands of the people.
This has lead the armed forces
to consult
with some of the national
and political parties.
The parties agreed
on the following roadmap:
The current constitution
will be revoked.
An early presidential election
will be held.
In the meanwhile,
the president of the supreme court,
will take charge of the country
during this transitional period.
We did it!
The people brought down the regime!
They are doing this
to provoke the army.
If they attack the army,
they'll have to respond
Listen to her.
They are trying to make the West think
there's a military coup.
They, the Brotherhood.
This is why Morsi sent
his supporters to the streets,
to show that he has
as many supporters,
and that people are backing him.
So the army must absolutely not
get involved now.
The army has to let them attack
and cause deaths,
so as to justify its intervention.
The army cannot confront
peaceful protesters.
Look, here they come!
With God's will,
we will vanquish them.
The army is acting very respectfully.
You have to trust the army.
Now,
we need to trust the army.
We were full of hopes.
We could bring mountains down,
and rebuild them again.
Our cry for freedom
reached the sky,
until it broke and shattered us.
As for us women,
we got overwhelmed by our dreams.
And each one of us went a different way.
How many more conversations
we would have had?
Mamma.
A lot of time needed to pass,
but it was too late
for me to be able to talk to you.
I am sad I lost you.
Not only because we weren't able
to have all those conversations,
but also because,
for 60 years of your life,
your lungs never had
a chance to breathe.
You died suffocating, Mamma.
You died not knowing
even one of your rights.
Not the rights
made by courts and laws,
but your rights
as a mother to this earth.
There are things one can't buy.
The right to life,
for the one who gives life.
Can you make the dishes
shine like that?
I don't have the patience.
It's Nabulsi soap,
made from olive oil.
See how shiny it is?
You have nothing else to do.
Look at me, all.
What do you think, Manal?
Careful, the photos!
Each one take a photo and describe it.
There are old photos.
Some are missing by the way.
Look at dad. He was slim.
Where was it?
Father Christmas!
He looks like Amir.
I want this photo!
-Neither of you.
-I want it!
Where have you been?
-I want to go to sleep.
-Go ahead.
You didn't sit with us
when we were looking at the photos.
I don't want to think about the past.
You were so handsome
when you were young
Don't you agree, Soha?
That's me!
This is Mamma.
So beautiful.
So you didn't like the film?
What did you see in the film
apart from me smoking?
Maybe you needed to leave
to find peace.
I wasn't able to see you.
or smell you one last time
-That was the first time, right?
-Yes.
Tell me about it.
It was the first time
I went to the cinema.
Because I'didn't want to upset you.
I was ill.
I didn't want to go.
But I went in order not to upset you.
How did it feel
to be for the first time in a cinema?
I sat and I watched.
The only thing left of you
is your hair.
It was the first time
my mother goes to the cinema.
I had to film her and ask her
what she thinks of cinema.
It was quiet.
No one was talking.
Everyone was quiet, watching.
I took your braid with your bow.
Because your hands
were the last to touch it.
I miss you.
So much.
Man, there goes the neighborhood.
Actually Manal also,
-the maid...
She is for al-Sissi.
Yesterday, she told me
there were protests in Talaat Harb.
It was very big, the police was there,
and all the trucks came.
She told me all the Brotherhood
were in Talaat Harb.
I told her the Brotherhood
never came to downtown.
They don't come to Talaat Harb,
those are revolutionaries.
She said, ''No, there is no revolution,
they were Brotherhood.''
I said, ''Why do you say this?''
She said, ''Because they
were saying 'Down with Sissi'''.
I said, ''A lot of people say this,
not just the Brotherhood.''
Hallo!
Are you filming?
How about the battery?
That just tells you
how much battery is left.
-Two batteries left.
-Two bars.
We need to charge it.
Just a little.
Not now.
-Is Ram there?
-You can move it.
-Is Ram there, Zein?
-I can see him.
I can see him.
It's hard to breathe.
The air won't go into my chest.
You were dying there.
And I was giving birth here.
And in my mind, questions grow.
What future awaits my children?
How will I raise them, and not fall
into the hole I was raised in?
In my womb,
My soul is tied
to your soul.
I gasped,
and created your soul.
It is written,
''I kissed mama, on her eye, her hair,
''and everything. And her leg,
and Ram's leg.''
Wow!
-All this is for you.
-All these kisses for me?
and you can borrow my stuff
-What is it, Mamma?
-The police are chasing them.
They were at the demonstration.
What's a demonstration?
They are running away.
They always run there.
But what's a demonstration?
It's when people...
I'll explain to you later.
The police are running after them.
Move your head
Hey, beautiful.
-What?
-You're beautiful.
-Thanks.
-Very beautiful.
Let's have a quick fuck.
What?
I'll walk behind you,
just like you do.
I'll bother you,
just like you bother me.
I'll stay on your back.
So you can feel how we feel
when you're following us.
-I'll stalk you.
-You can stay forever.
I'm going to follow you.
Just like boys follow girls,
now girls will follow boys.
I won't leave him alone.
I live upstairs, by the way.
-Did anyone talk to you?
-No one talked to me.
-So I'm the problem?
-Go wear decent clothes.
I will wear whatever I please!
Mind your own business!
I am free. I do what I want.
Why should I stop.?
Don't you get harassed too?
It's OK.
No, it's not.
I'll wait for him outside.
I'll follow you till the end of time.
Waiting for him outside.
What do you want?
You're the one who's talking to me.
-She was arguing with a customer.
-Did I talk to you?
-She's making a fuss.
-None of your business.
-I'm a free woman.
-Be polite or I'll beat you.
Did I talk to you?
You'd better be polite
or I'll beat you up in public.
You're going to beat me?
-It's ok, madam.
-You should talk to him.
-Am I wrong to ask her to be polite?
-I'm not afraid of raising my voice!
A women's voice is not shameful.
You are shameful.
-I want to record you.
-Okay, go ahead.
-Do you know what happened?
-Yes.
What happened?
I don't wont to do it anymore.
-I don't want to do that at all.
-Don't take someone to the police.
What?
You don't have to take
someone to the police.
It's not like very, very bad.
You think
it's not bad what he did to me?
I said, it's not very very very bad.
For me, it's very very very bad.
-Okay.
-I don't like anybody to touch me.
I can touch you?
You're not anybody, you're my son.
He's just some guy in the street,
who grabbed me.
Do you think this is okay?
-What?
-Hey, what happened?
Zein thinks it is not that bad so as
to take the guy to the police station.
-This is what he thinks.
-No, I mean...
And he started to cry.
So when he cried I had to leave.
I was scared.
There were 50 or more guys
surrounding me,
I'm grabbing the guy
to take him to the police station.
I beat him in his face.
And everyone was, like,
''It's over, you beat him.''
''Your son is crying, go home.''
''It's wrong that you hit him.''
After he grabbed me from my ass,
he said it was wrong I beat him
I said, ''You're telling me I'm wrong,
but you're not telling him he's wrong.''
It is not okay for some random guy
to grab anybody,
or any of us, especially your mom.
Okay.
If anybody does that again,
you go and you kick him.
-That's what she said.
-Yeah.
Zein asked me, ''Why did he do that?''
What should I tell him?
Because of some stupid,
uneducated idiot?
Who grabs girls asses in the street?
He said,
''Let's go live somewhere else.''
I wanted to record because I got hurt.
And I want my son
to understand what happened.
Why did I get hurt?
I don't want my son to think
I am a crazy woman,
fighting with people in the street
like many people think.
It's not the first time it happened
when he was with me.
The other time he was
a baby in the stroller.
I would yell,
and no one could understand why.
Two things drive me mad.
First, that Zein was with me.
Second, that I'm at home,
while the guy walks away free.
I didn't want anyone
to beat him.
A guy was hitting him.
I didn't want anybody to beat him.
I just wanted
to take him to the police.
Enough.
I don't know if I was lucky
to be born a girl.
But I know that I'm fully aware
of the power and strength I derive
from being born a girl.
And I think, in the end,
that's what makes all the difference.
Resistance and survival
are a blessing.
and Blessing is your name.