(crickets chirp)
(footsteps approach)
(dark atmospheric music)
(moody atmospheric music)
(tense atmospheric music)
(thuds)
(boy grunts)
(door creaks)
- [Woman] Right, it's feedin' time!
Right, come on, don't be shy!
Come on, hustle hustle, there's
starving kids in Africa.
There you go, come and get it.
The faster you eat, the
faster we get to work.
(dark atmospheric music)
We gotta get the runts out more.
- The search needs to
extend past just the boy.
- I know, I've heard it before.
- You know, I was reading that
it says here that there must
be a falling of hope in order
to find the justice in things.
(sighs) You can't have a
hero who's lost all his hope.
It's about the testin' and
then the rebuildin' phase.
You know, being rebuilt, that's justice.
I can't even read this.
It'll probably be some TV drivel soon.
- [Woman] Ah, I can't take this.
(pants)
- It's right where you put it.
- I'm tellin' you, it wasn't there before.
That boy's got a mind of his own.
- Okay, so it's not me you're fixing on.
Blamin' the boy like you allow him
next to this science experiment.
Best be weary of that temper of yours.
It's gonna get you in trouble.
- I know it's around the corner,
but them plants are gonna
need taking care of.
- Yeah, I got the boys out there.
Gotta clear out the dead roots first.
It'll be a good season.
Don't you worry.
- I just...
I don't know why we're
not fl yin' yet, you know?
There's, there's islands out there,
and plants and animals and
we could cash in the crop
and we can take the boys with us,
you can write your own
books and it'll just be
peaceful, all around us.
- You know the walk
between justice and family
is a thin line.
We're doing a good thing.
So, for us, we gotta keep
our heads in the game.
(tense atmospheric music)
Well...
Did you win?
Fliny always says don't
be afraid to use yourself,
if you ain't got the means.
I guess you did just that,
she'll take care of it.
I know you found us some
good out there, boy.
How many miles?
No matter, it's our night now.
City targets is our territory.
That's a hell of a shot, boy.
Pack up.
(suspenseful music)
I have a feeling something drew us here.
Give it more punch.
Try it again.
(engine churns)
- Hey, man.
Need some help?
- We can't figure this engine.
Do you know the F series?
- I've worked on a few, but,
this looks like a 70
and they're kinda rare.
- She's a hand-me-down, from my uncle.
He never mentioned all the problems.
(mechanic chuckles)
- Ain't that how it always goes?
(father chuckles)
The gift that keeps on givin'.
- [Father] Yes.
- Yeah, I guess the real gift is--
(thud)
(tense music)
(dark atmospheric music)
- Is not human.
Built from the ground up like a god.
This one here, hid behind his identity.
Behind his money.
Only traveled by night.
Flew through the darkness
to save an entire city.
It didn't work, though.
It never does.
You are weak.
You didn't even make it
through the first round.
We're gonna play a little game.
You're gonna pretend that
your life isn't already over.
You know we're not out
looking for trouble.
We just know that unless
you can be rebuilt,
you are not a hero.
It's not our call who the heroes are.
It's whoever can last.
And you definitely did not.
(chuckles)
I feel like I'm talkin'
to myself. (chuckles)
(fire crackles)
(crickets chirp)
One day, you'll be in charge here.
Fliny and I will be on the road somewhere.
The markers are getting better.
You're learnin'.
Every time, you're learnin'.
You're looking out for your old man.
There you go.
Kick it, go ahead.
That's right.
Put it out!
There you go, that's my boy. (chuckles)
Yeah, kick it!
Let's go, kick it, put it out, put it out!
There you go, kick it, go ahead!
("Faking It" by Jay Reatard)
♪ You faked it all the way ♪
(feedback screeches)
(lively rock music)
(saw blade buzzes)
♪ Drink, drink ♪
♪ Don't think, drink ♪
♪ Drive, kill ♪
♪ Get drunk on life and
work 40 hours a week ♪
(spray paint hisses)
- Marking your territory
like a stray, huh?
Whoa.
Afraid of strangers, kid?
I don't blame you.
Probably don't wanna get
another one of those.
It's pretty impressive.
Listen, if you're gonna do
this, gotta have a flow to it.
You know, it's like music.
You ever listen to music?
No?
Yeah, it's all right, it
all sounds the same anyway.
Look, you just gotta be
careful out here doin" this.
All right? You've gotta
keep your hands clean.
'Cause you don't want
people catching on, so,
look, you're already destroying the wall.
You might as well not
get your hands dirty.
You gotta be smart about it.
Guessing breakfast was
a couple days ago, huh?
God, slow down, I got more.
Hey.
Did your parents give you a name?
I'm guessing they don't exist, do they?
But you got owners though, right?
Everybody's got someone who owns 'em.
Where your keepers at?
See, the problem is, if you're
a runaway, I'm gonna have to
take you home because those
keepers are gonna want you back.
Hey, what's your name, kid?
- They call me Boy.
Adam.
- Boy Adam.
That's your name?
It's what the owners call you, isn't it?
- I have to go home now.
- What, you got a curfew?
- When it's nighttime.
(dark atmospheric music)
- This place looks pretty empty.
Are you sure those keepers
got a place for you?
Hm?
Out here with the wolves, huh?
Hey, that big farm right there, that you?
All right.
Well, we stay out here much
longer, we're both gonna be
predators" meat, so you best
get yourself back inside now.
- Come on, bring 'em over,
bring 'em over, bring 'em over.
Come on, come on, come on.
Colin, you gotta crack the crust!
There you go!
Oh, damn.
Y'all need to get bigger ones than this!
These are lookin' sad.
(tense atmospheric music)
- This is it.
There ain't now escapin' what's comin'.
We got a new spot.
I'm branchin' out into the waste lines.
We've seen here.
I want you to find me somethin' there.
And maybe we'll find a good house guest.
- Questions just kept coming.
And there I was, in
the shadows, searching.
And this was everyday.
No answers.
Again, and again, and again.
Until one day, (clicks fingers)
I asked myself the right question.
"Is it really about what's to learn?”
I mean, there's hints sometimes, you know?
You ask yourself questions like,
"How is it possible for
them to do this to me?"
Or better yet, "Is the
common denominator me,
"all these times?" (chuckles)
Really, what you should be saying,
is it's not for me to understand,
but it is for me to accept.
(chuckles)
I don't know.
Maybe it's not their fault.
But I'll tell you one thing,
it's sure as hell not mine,
and it's not yours, either.
If you continue to search,
you will continue to fail.
All right, I'm gonna get
off my soap box. (chuckles)
Who's ready?
- My name's Holton.
- What's up, Holton?
- Wasn't alcohol for me.
It was the people that
used it that made me toxic.
I've always found myself
gravitating toward problems.
I think deep down inside,
whether I like it or not,
it's what I'm always chasing.
Chaos.
(dark atmospheric music)
And uh, I know, like you said,
it's not on me to understand,
it's only to accept.
Al-Anon is for those of us who
are dealing with the people
who have the problems and it's
funny, I think sometimes it
makes us think that we don't have 'em.
And I've always been straight-edge.
I've never had a drop of alcohol,
not a cigarette, nothin".
I've never even been curious.
But if all you ever knew was chaos,
would you ever be able to change?
I think, uh...
The way I grew up, and um...
And the things that I saw...
Things that happened to me.
Made me wanna go against that
grain and live a clean life,
but it also left me toxic.
So, um...
That's why I'm here, I wanna be able to
just trust my gut and,
and live my truth, and,
let it guide me.
Everyday.
- Hey, man, that was good
today, you're opening up.
- (chuckles) Yeah, I'm
just trying not to run
from the problem anymore, you know?
Plus, I figured you'd crack me eventually.
- (chuckles) Well, yeah.
It takes some work, but we all
come uncorked at some point.
- I'm with you there.
- It's good to see a new
face in group, by the way.
My name's Karl in, but you can call me Kar.
- Yeah, I'm Holton.
I've been coming here for a couple weeks.
- (chuckles) Sorry.
Being too formal.
(sighs) Well, I guess this
is what the party looks like
when you grow up straight-edge, huh?
- Yeah, this is pretty much
what you would find there.
Coffee and some sugar, shots of cream.
That's better than lettin' the bottle
make your choices for
you though, isn't it?
- That's true.
Al-Anon isn't about separation, though.
It's about guidance
through accepting behavior.
- Well, that's a tough lesson to learn.
But I guess time has wised us up, huh?
- Yeah.
Well, when you've had a breakthrough,
you're gonna wanna keep it consistent.
Come back, don't abandon it.
- Well you're a real straight-shooter
and I appreciate that.
- Hey. (chuckles)
- I'll see you next week.
- Sounds good, man.
(tense atmospheric music)
(moody electronic music)
(Holton chuckles)
(dark atmospheric music)
- It's a veggie patty.
My brother would skin me
alive if he heard me say that.
But it helps clean the
poison out, clears my head.
No meat.
No alcohol.
No friends.
No fun.
Nothin'.
I'm a clean soul now.
- I can't have friends.
That's what I was told.
- Listen.
Whoever owns you,
is creepin' too deep inside.
They're not lettin' the
man in here shine through.
Hey, look, I made somethin' I'm proud of.
You ever do that?
- No.
- Look.
So, uh, this here's a list.
Well, it's a book, but I make lists
and it helps me figure things out.
You see, anything I put
in this book comes true.
All you gotta do is write it down.
That's how I make things I'm proud of.
Know how to do that?
Well, good.
Your owners are doin' a
better job than I thought.
Yeah, this book, it helps me to create,
it helps me to craft,
and it's all kept in here,
it doesn't go anywhere else.
It's for my eyes only.
Any thought, any idea I ever have,
I let it rest in here,
'cause it helps to get it out.
'Cause when you write things
down, it takes what's in here,
and makes it real.
Does that make sense?
(tense atmospheric music)
- The boys have taken to bed,
I suggest you do the same.
(father chuckles)
- The boy's heading back soon.
And we've got another visitor.
(tense atmospheric music)
(bucket rattles)
- Always bringin' trash in here like that.
You've gotta be my
favorite little hoarder.
(father chuckles)
- You know, watching you flirt
is like watching a car wreck.
- Well, it's an early start tomorrow,
and I ain't got much flirtin' left.
- You drew these?
- Yeah.
- This, uh, wasn't exactly what I meant
when I told you to write things down.
This is somethin' else.
What are these drawings of?
- Things I...
Things I see.
(dark atmospheric music)
(knocks)
- Hey, Kar?
- Yeah.
- [Holton] Do you have a second to chat?
- Yeah, sure, shoot.
- I was just think in".
This process that we talk
about, these proceedings,
you think it's possible
to get someone out of it
while they're in it or would they have to,
to grow up with it and then
recognize the patterns?
- Okay, you're either asking for a friend,
or you're sharing outside of group.
- It's, uh...
It's a boy, he's a good kid,
but it seems like there's some
broken support beams at home.
- Is his family not around?
- Well, that's the thing, he
definitely has owners but it
seems like they're sorta leadin'
him sideways a little bit.
- So you think they're users.
- Either that or there's
somethin' happened in the past.
I mean, there's a lack
of social cues in place.
- So, you're his lookout?
- Somethin' like that.
- It's always difficult
when children are involved.
Would there be an opportunity
to talk to the kid, or--
- Would you think that'd be the best move?
- It depends, is it dangerous?
- Oh, I don't know that yet.
- I see.
Well, all I can tell you is
guests are always welcome and
the door is always open.
- All right, thanks your help, Kar.
Appreciate it.
- Anytime, Holton.
Take care.
- It's easy, see?
That's it, so, one every
two spaces over.
You see, germs are a boy's best friend,
but dirt's my biggest enemy.
This way, them feet of yours
won't be trackin' in dirt
and seeds and all kinds of grime.
It'll finally be clean for
once when the season starts.
(dark atmospheric music)
- Come on, boy.
It ain't gonna bite you.
Go on and grab that.
There you go.
Take that mallet.
I'm gonna give you a countdown.
I want you to come down on it hard.
As hard as you can, you hear me, boy?
All right.
Three.
Two.
One.
(thud)
Do it again.
Again!
(thuds)
Come on, boy, hit it!
(thud)
Do it again, go!
(thuds)
Hit it, that's a boy!
Yeah, hit it hard, yeah!
(thuds)
(dark atmospheric music)
Feels good, doesn't it?
Go get another one.
- He showed these to me.
- Oh, Jesus.
- What?
You think it's serious?
- Yeah, this is abuse and neglect.
How long did it take
him to show you these?
- Like a week?
- Where can I find them, the family?
- Eagle Valley, they got a farm out there.
- You gonna help me with
this big fancy dinner?
Y'all earned this one.
This is for gatherin' Durin' the season.
I'm gonna stuff you like kings.
Go round up the boys, go on.
(knocks)
(dark atmospheric music)
- Oh, hello, um, I was
wondering if I could have
a word with you for a minute?
I run a group out in Etna and
I just came by to extend an invitation.
- Speak.
- Okay, (chuckles)
you'll have to excuse me.
My name's Karl in, you can call me Kar.
- That's not a name, that's an automobile.
(Kar chuckles)
- That's true.
I guess my parents had a
strange sense of humor.
- You sellin' somethin'?
- No, no, no, no.
Your son, a friend of mine
received some drawings from him
recently and, uh, they're
pretty explicit, you know?
You know, maybe I should
just show 'em to ya.
Take a look at these.
I'm sorry, I'm not
explaining myself very well.
I'm a counselor and...
Honestly, I really just
came out here to tell you
about the group that I run and reach out.
You know, in situations like these,
not that there's any kind
of situation, I'm not
assuming there's any kind of
situation, but I felt it was
best after seeing these
drawings to reach out and
maybe even meet your son?
- What seems to be the problem?
(tense atmospheric music)
- Oh, uh, no problem at all.
I just happened in to be
in the neighborhood, I'm
spreading the word about a
meet-and-greet that I run that
helps families in need.
- Oh. (chuckles)
Excuse me.
I don't think we've been
properly acquainted.
I'm Arty.
I'd shake your hand, but
I'm covered in cooking oil,
and kid germs.
- Oh, (chuckles) no problem at all.
I appreciate you sparing me.
- I'm sorry about Fliny, she's
a bit touchy around people
she hasn't dealt with before.
- I understand.
- These meetings are
about the neighborhood?
- No, is your son at home?
- Yeah, yeah, the whole family's inside.
- Well, a friend of your son's
brought something to the forum I run.
- A friend of his?
- Yeah.
- Huh.
Yeah.
The boy is more of a
conversationalist than the other kids.
- I see.
Well, these drawings...
I just figured I would
pass them along to you?
- Uh-huh.
He's been reading a lot of comics.
- Oh, I see.
- We're fixin' to get
supper, you know, but these--
- Of course, I didn't mean to impose.
I was just in the neighborhood
and I figured I'd stop by.
- No, no, it's okay, it's
no reason to be sorry.
- No, no, no, thank you so
much for talking to me, I can
come back and I'm really sorry
for the misunderstanding.
- Well, if that's what
works for you, okay.
- Have a good night, please
apologize to your wife for me.
- [Arty] Fliny is a bit jumpy.
(Kar chuckles)
- Enjoy your dinner.
(dark atmospheric music)
- Hey!
Would you like to join us?
We have enough fixings to go around.
And you can come and look in the place.
Might ease your mind?
- Oh, um...
Yeah, no, okay, sure.
That'd be nice.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, sure.
- Fliny likes to cook for a small army.
- Oh, well, I appreciate it.
Appreciate it a lot, it's
not everyday that you--
(tense string music)
- Goddamn it, Artik!
Not in here, we just
laid out the dirt floors!
How're we gonna get this clean?
Come on, come on, get
back, get back, get back!
(dark atmospheric music)
- Hi, Kar.
(Kar splutters and whines)
There you are.
(Kar splutters)
Allow me to introduce
you to my magic workshop.
This is where the research is done.
It's kind of like a melty barn.
- [Kar] Please.
- Please?
- Please!
Please.
- But I'm afraid because
of the situation...
I'm going to have to get my hands dirty.
(Kar groans)
Who's this friend?
The one who knows the boy.
- You may ask yourself, is
my mind back in control now?
I think that's probably the understanding
of where we're all heading.
(fabric tears)
(Kar moans)
(suspenseful music)
- I like to keep my surroundings clean.
- Wait.
Wait!
(fabric tears)
(pants)
Wait!
(flesh squelches)
(screams)
(grunts)
(sobs)
- What's your connection to the boy?
- [Kar] Please.
- No more chances.
(sobs)
- [Artik] You're gonna have to
forgive me for what's coming.
- Wait, wait.
(thud)
(screams)
(whines)
(thud)
(abrasive tones)
(blood splashes)
(coffee splashes)
- Are you the new speaker?
- Hi, Sarah.
- Holton, it's a pleasure.
- Yeah, Kar's out all week.
- He didn't mention being out.
- Actually, we were expecting
him but do you need a meeting?
I mean, any of us are here,
any of us could do it.
- No, no, thank you, I appreciate that.
I just, I needed to talk to him.
- Well, we'll be here
all week, so let me know
if you need anything.
- Thanks.
- Okay.
(suspenseful music)
(fire crackles)
(Artik howls)
(Atrik howls)
(dark atmospheric music)
(distant metal clangs)
(door opens and closes)
(suspenseful music)
(leaves rustle)
(door thuds)
- Shit.
Hey.
It's all right.
Come on.
Come on, let's go.
(thud)
(groans)
(dramatic percussive music)
(bees buzz)
(dark atmospheric music)
(chains rattle)
- Right here.
(Holton grunts)
I take it you are a friend of the boy.
Figures.
I don't know what your
connection is to the boy.
But this land is mine,
and you are marked the
second you take foot on it.
(Holton coughs)
- What're all those kids doing out there?
Why are they all locked up?
- Sometimes,
being locked up,
sets a man free.
- Where is Kar?
(muffled grunts)
- You're gonna tell me what
your connection is to the boy!
(Holton grunts)
Whatever it is you fear most...
It's coming for you.
(dark atmospheric music)
(Holton grunts)
(chains rattle)
I'm writing a story about
finding something that's pure.
The story isn't over.
Purity exists in this world.
The problem is the drivel.
These heroes could not save us.
That's not real life now.
The story I'm writing?
That's real.
- I don't like that we're
havin' more visitors.
- He knows something about the boy.
- Tough shit, we gotta get rid of him.
- Somethin' about the
boy that we don't know.
He can still make mistakes.
- Okay, I'll take care of the boys,
and we'll take care of the harvest,
and you take out that trash
that's been stinkin' up my barn.
(tense atmospheric music)
- I don't know what's comin' to me,
but if it gives Adam a
better life, then, go ahead.
- I have to protect the boy,
which is why I'm going
to give him your gun.
It's something to remember you by.
- Words and threats, it's all I hear.
Real torment comes from within.
That's why these boys listen to you.
See, deep down, you're
the one rel yin' on them.
They don't need you.
- Really?
- I'm tellin' you that you
chase purity and I live it.
And if that's what you're after,
why don't you come and
take mine away from me?
Huh?
Come on!
(muffled grunts)
Let him free!
- Why is he takin' so long?
- We need to try something new.
I need your help.
- (sighs) Damn it.
- [Artik] I need the alcohol.
- [Flin] We were savin' this for leavin'.
Go on, take it.
(dark atmospheric music)
(chains rattle)
- The normal methods aren't going to work.
What does a man without fear,
fear the most?
(Holton groans)
So, the boy says you don't even drink.
That's good because the more
of this poison that goes in ya,
the more you become the little blueprint
you ran away from your whole life.
You're gonna have to open your mouth, boy.
(tense atmospheric music)
(Holton splutters)
- More.
More!
Come on!
(grunts)
I want more!
Come on, I'm ready.
Bring me more.
- Get up, boy.
I got something for you.
(dark atmospheric music)
There, that's more comfortable.
(groans)
There you go.
Not a bad view, right, boy?
Ah, you're thinkin' it again.
The boy has his own free will.
He's coming into his manhood.
Ain't ya, boy?
Oh, I almost forgot.
This isn't for me.
This is for you. (chuckles)
I can't toast myself.
This one's for me.
And this one...
Is for you, boy.
(suspenseful music)
- What the fuck are you doing?
What the fuck are you doing?
- Someone's gotta teach the boy,
how to toast before having a drink.
- Leave him be.
(Artik chuckles)
- I don't see no problem
with sharing a good time with the boy.
No, I definitely don't
see any trouble in that.
Top it off for you.
Now, this is what adults
have on a good day.
- Stop it!
- Go on, you raise it up high.
Yes.
You raise it to him.
And now you take a drink.
Go on.
- Stop.
Adam, don't drink that.
- He has his own free will!
(Adam splutters)
(Adam coughs)
- One more, now you gotta
keep it in this time.
- Adam.
- Now it's gonna have a
little bit of a kick to it,
but I ain't sent you wrong yet.
- Come on, I ain't even
puttin' up a fight.
- It ain't fighting.
This is how your mom and dad
play after a long day at work.
Someday, if you wanna grow up,
you're gonna have to take a sip.
We ain't got all day.
There you go.
Again, drink it up.
(Adam gasps)
Give me that!
- Hey, hey!
Stop it!
God damn it, leave him alone!
- You watch this!
Drink it!
- [Holton] God damn it, leave him alone!
- Go!
(Adam gasps and coughs)
- Hey, hey!
I'm gonna make you feel what he just felt.
(Adam coughs)
- Boy?
Go out and prep the tarp.
Bring the CAT around.
Get a shovel.
Dig a hole.
Go out and dig a hole, boy.
Or I'll make two.
Now!
Shit.
(somber atmospheric music)
(Adam sobs)
I was thinking maybe
that friend of the boy's
really is the one that
I've been searching for.
A true hero.
Pain don't bother him.
He actually moves
like he's living in some
state of constant meditation.
But then...
I had an epiphany.
That when anger comes, so does the truth.
That's when I realized,
when something happens with
the boy that upsets you...
You're not pure inside.
(suspenseful music)
I left your friend out there.
And soon, you'll be able to join him.
(cacophonous clangs)
(groans)
Make it stop!
(suspenseful music)
(boys pant)
(Flin screams)
- Get away from him!
Hey.
It's okay.
It's okay, sweetie.
Come on, give me the gun.
Hm?
Come on.
Come on, sweetie, give me the gun.
(suspenseful music)
(gun cocks)
Give me the gun.
Give me the gun!
(distant gun fires)
(tense atmospheric music)
(suspenseful music)
(footsteps shuffle)
(leaves rustle)
(gun cocks)
(gun fires)
(water splashes)
(screams)
(tense string music)
(suspenseful music)
(thuds)
(groans and grunts)
(screams)
(Holton groans)
(pants)
(tense music)
(grunts)
(pan clangs)
(groans)
(suspenseful music)
(moans)
(Holton groans and coughs)
(pan clangs)
(Holton groans)
(glass smashes)
(suspenseful music)
(gun fires)
(Adam pants)
- (pants) Come on, we
gotta get to the car.
(gun fires)
(gasps)
Here, give me the gun!
(gun fires)
Go, go!
(gun cocks)
(gun fires)
- Come on!
(gun cocks)
(gun fires)
(glass smashes)
(yells)
(gun fires rapidly)
(glass smashes)
(gun cocks)
(gun fires)
(gun fires rapidly)
(gun cocks)
(distant laughter)
(tense orchestral music)
(gun cocks)
(gun fires rapidly)
(grunts)
(gun cocks)
(yells)
(gun fires)
(grunts)
(gun cocks)
Fliny!
(sobs)
(somber atmospheric music)
Fliny!
(pants)
(dark atmospheric music)
- (yelps) God!
(pants)
(coughs)
(groans)
(tense music)
(grunts)
(thuds)
(gasps)
(Adam yells)
(steel clangs)
(coughs)
(flesh squelches)
(somber atmospheric music)
(grunts)
(pants)
(leaves rustle)
(moody electronic music)
("Faking It" by Jay Reatard)
♪ Sitting in the summer sun ♪
♪ Thinking over what's begun ♪
♪ Dreaming of a better place ♪
♪ Frightened look upon your face ♪
♪ 'Cause you know what must be done ♪
♪ Execute the only one ♪
♪ You faked it all the way ♪
♪ You faked it all the way, you ♪
♪ Sitting with no sound ♪
♪ Fucked in terms of what to do ♪
♪ Daydreaming of a better place ♪
♪ Frightened look upon my face ♪
♪ 'Cause I know what must be done ♪
♪ Till I rose the only one ♪
♪ You faked it all the way ♪
♪ You faked it all the way, you ♪
♪ Executes the only one ♪
♪ She executes the only one ♪
♪ You faked it all the way ♪
♪ You faked it all the way, you ♪
("Tonight" by Weeknight)
♪ Under your sun ♪
♪ I miss you less when the sun goes down ♪
♪ I'd do anything ♪
♪ To have this buried in the ground ♪
♪ It's been a little tired ♪
♪ Melodies been turning me tonight ♪
♪ Oh, tonight ♪
♪ It's been a little tired ♪
♪ Melodies been turning me tonight ♪
♪ Oh, tonight ♪
♪ Nothing matters now ♪
♪ Nothing matters now, but we try ♪
♪ Immaterial ♪
♪ And then you'll be set on fire ♪
♪ It's been a little tired ♪
♪ Melodies been turning me tonight ♪
♪ Oh, tonight ♪
♪ It's been a little tired ♪
♪ Melodies been turning me tonight ♪
♪ Oh, tonight ♪
♪ It's been a little tired ♪
♪ Melodies been turning me tonight ♪
♪ Oh, tonight ♪
♪ It's been a little tired ♪
♪ Melodies been turning me tonight ♪
♪ Oh, tonight ♪
(dark atmospheric music)