I'd like to speak of this memory...
But it's so faded now...
as though nothing is left,
because it was so long ago,
in my adolescent years.
Constantine Cavafy
"If you think you were slain by my hand
Then send for me, Mother.
Bury me in the fires of hell.
Are these men my enemies?
There is no water without earth,
no earth without water.
I beg forgiveness, and I repent.
Alerting all units,
it's been reported that another
watchman has gone missing.
Don Colombo, it's been a while
since we've heard from you.
Do you need supplies?
Colombo Quisquiza, Unit 8,
Paramo Alto...
Your son F, has failed to check in.
There are reports of hostile
activity in the area."
To sin is to lack faith in God
and a true love for one's neighbor.
Succumbing to ambition,
greed, and the devil...
Sin hurts the true nature of man
and undermines human solidarity.
War has no purpose; instead,
we must...
...build peace and find
harmony in our family.
A family is a group of individuals
rife with defects
that God brings together
in spite of their differences
so that they may
develop tolerance, respect,
gratitude, patience,
and forgiveness
doing for others what we would
like them to do unto us
without demanding the perfection
that we do not yet have.
We are born where we deserve,
in order to grow and evolve.
Sin is living in hatred
and resentment.
Sin is the loss of Paradise.
How long can we live
with the misery of man,
with our innate wretchedness
and our desire to deplete
devour and dominate
everything around?
The time has come to surrender
God will not lead us astray.
By orders of the Superior Command,
all watchmen and guards must retreat.
You understand we ought to go.
No crops, no cattle, no life.
Nobody wants to stay like this.
Tell your father that he should
sell the land too.
They're paying quickly in US Dollars.
There is no future here.
Rosa...
I will take you to her.
In the name of the Father and the Son
Forever and ever
Our ancestors have been banished.
We are not like them anymore
We no longer use their words
We no longer have a language
We no longer can be fed I am
your servant, the son of your mercy.
Massive dams displace millions of
people and destroy whole eco-systems.
Global warming is altering
the water cycle,
causing more severe and unpredictable
flooding and droughts...
Unregulated corporate privatization
threatens access to water for the poor.
Some governments fail to deliver water
where it is needed most.
These stresses have created
political and military conflicts
that will only get worse.
Ultimately, humanity is poisoning,
squandering and overburdening
water resources.
The result is that billions of people
lack access to clean water.
Millions of children die every year
from preventable water born diseases.
Lack of clean water and basic sanitation
traps people in problem.
People are fighting and dying for it.
Attention: All community members
are advised to not engage in conflict.
And now the moment
you have been waiting for.
It's time to study, it's time to learn,
it's time to have fun.
It's English time.
Right here, right now.
Now, repeat after me:
The morning is sunny.
Very well. Now, repeat after me:
- The afternoon is rainy.
Very well!
Now repeat after me:
- The night is cold.
- I am very happy.
Sumapaz here, over.
Clear and present danger, over.
Can anybody hear me?
Get me out!
Nothing belongs to us, Mother
I rather remain quiet than lie.
A dagger plunged
into my chest is tearing me apart
splitting me
between my shoulders.
I yearn to taste the salt of the sea
My veins are entwined
with the soil of this land.
The end draws ever
near to snatch my soul,
crumbling my bones
and reducing me to dust.
Will I be forgiven?
My father is already with you.
Hello, hello...
Colombo or son, whoever can hear us.
We are being slaughtered!
to my father, in memoriam