ANOTHER WORLD
So...
She owns a first home
with a living area
of 130 square meters
and a lot
of 2,600 square meters,
with an estimated value
of €700,000.
A second home
of 95 square meters,
with one hectare of land,
of an estimated value of €550,000.
Different bank accounts:
a securities deposit
with assets of €35,674;
a deposit account
with assets of €15,300;
a current account
with assets of €12,000;
a life insurance policy
of €201,624;
for an overall value
of €264,598.
The compensation claim takes into account
the loss of career opportunities.
My client and I have estimated
that such compensation
should amount to €375,000.
Unless...
the duration of that
loss of opportunity
does not match the
whole duration of marriage,
since Madam has started
working again since three years.
On the first day of the wedding,
my client's employment foreshadowed
a very promising professional path.
Madam sacrificed her career
to follow Mr. Lemesle's
in all his duties,
in France and abroad.
So she closed
the door to her career.
It was a real sacrifice.
Today, at the time of their divorce,
because that's what we're talking about,
That choice has a price.
Of course, of course,
it has a price.
I do not dispute
the division of property,
but I do not accept
unfair treatment.
€375,000 is a lot of money,
I feel drained...
The amount is calculated
on your current income...
But I've been hearing
from the beginning the word 'sacrifice'.
Like I'm the villain here.
- Nobody said that.
- You insinuated it.
That's the insinuation.
There is no reason
that I must lose more than you.
I'm not saying otherwise.
We are here to
think about the future.
Precisely.
Mr. Lemesle has already
accepted the divorce.
If we talk about the future,
we can not put the whole burden on him.
He should not be penalized twice.
The same thing
goes for my client,
Especially since her life has been hell
for the last seven years.
- Hell?
- Yes, hell.
In this case, excuse me, but...
she should change her request.
Don't ask for €375,000.
If it was hell,
then ask for €8,000,000. Please!
Or even €10,000,000!
She told you
that I made her life hell?
Is this what she told you?
Anne?
Did I make your life hell?
- Mr. Lemesle...
- Please wait...
Did I make your life hell?
Answer me.
- I suggest you avoid...
- No, let me explain.
No, I'm sorry,
I can't allow this...
Let's avoid the emotional road.
I'll do that next, but now...
I won't let you say
that I made your life hell.
No, I worked.
They offered me responsibilities
with an important company group,
I accepted them
and I had to work hard.
It was a lot of work. A lot.
- Yes or no?
- Yes.
Good...
That brought money into the house.
And you benefited from it
as much as I did.
You can't deny it.
I don't deny it.
Before accepting the job,
we talked about it many times,
and you knew exactly
what awaited us.
Sir, I guarantee you
that my client recognizes it,
but that's not the point.
But you must understand
that for seven years,
since you took over
the management of the plant,
you brought your problems home.
- This is the truth.
- But this is not why we are here.
The purpose of this meeting, sir,
to discuss the divorce settlement.
This is not family therapy.
Neither it is the place nor
the objective of this meeting.
I agree,
but I want to say one thing.
I never said....
that accepting this job
would be easy.
I never said that.
We have discussed this many times,
I have never said that.
But my client wasn't supposed to
suffer for your career choice.
That's not fair.
Suffer?
But she also enjoyed the benefits.
- What you are saying is shameful.
- How?
I didn't sign up for you to
bring your problems home.
This was not the deal.
You talked about more work. I said:
"Ok, I'll manage my daily life
despite your absence",
but I didn't expect this chaos.
She's berating me for my absence
and for letting you
manage your daily life?
You were never really there.
- That's not true.
- Ah, yes?
How many weekends we spent
together in recent years?
- I don't keep track of weekends.
- I do. Six.
Six in two years.
Not even a night together.
I'm talking about
the last few years,
but our family fell apart
much earlier.
You were constantly stressed...
Sorry...
What should I have done?
I'm sorry,
but I can't write off both
my private life and
my professional life.
I will not lose on both fronts.
I was very clear,
I have never deceived you.
I've never lied to you.
I said it would be hard until
the Elsonn Group had achieved its goals.
So I depend on the Elsonn Group.
I live with them.
- I'm married to Elsonn!
- I'm not saying that.
I have suffered for years,
listening only about tensions, anxieties
and complaints about your work.
Philippe, I'm almost 50!
I have more years behind me
than in front of me, isn't it so?
I have done my share.
The main question
is not how to succeed,
again cutting 10%
of the workforce, in this context.
Rather, it is how to deal with
a contradiction that is, new cuts.
A new economic plan
in a context where the factory
and the company are profitable,
and also the Group, Philippe.
A contradiction
which will generate conflicts.
You raise a question
that the Group has not asked us
to answer, nor to think about.
But they ask us to do a job.
We have the right to ask about...
the consequences,
we are not mere executors.
The Group asks this,
like it or not, so we have to do it.
And I'll tell you right away:
we will respond.
To put things back in context,
when Elsonn acquired us
we were 603 men,
today we are 508.
We can make everything up, but...
Alexandre,
that's not what this is about.
Spare us the story,
we were all there, we know the numbers.
It's not a history lesson
but the numbers are important.
We have to lay off 58 employees.
That's not a little.
Today I would just like to say:
But no more layoffs in my department.
You can look elsewhere,
like in the communication area,
where they seem a little more relaxed.
- Sorry?
- No, Sayid...
- Can you specify?
- Sayid, please.
Sayid, wait.
I don't want to hear this.
We don't stab each other in the back..
- We're not going to do that.
- I'm just saying...
I just want to remind you that
in the hyper-competitive sector,
the production of parts
for household appliances,
you have to perform to the maximum
and must be very competitive.
If we want to continue
to produce revenues and results,
we shouldn't fire engineers anymore.
I have no elbow room at all
in my department.
- We understood.
- I hope so.
Can I ask Alexandre to be more specific
when he mentioned Communication?
I say what everyone thinks.
If we want to stay on track,
I repeat it one last time:
let's not stab each other in the back.
And we don't tear each other down, clear?
This looks like a repeat
from two and a half years ago.
You are doing
exactly the same thing.
The Group asks for a layoff plan
and you start with the same song:
'If we are going to
downsize departments, it will be chaos.'
We move the administration to Poland,
or another department to Portugal.
There are solutions,
other companies do it...
Easy to say "we relocate".
Stop, please, stop.
We won't go in Julie's direction,
I assure you.
Not in that direction.
I need to have
the maximum of services on site.
No relocation.
But at least someone
made a proposal.
What I want: that you
do proposals and find solutions.
- Is that clear?
- Philippe.
- I just want to say one thing.
- Say it.
What I want to say is
that Alexandre has perhaps
the brightest engineers on earth...
Don't tear it down. Say what you
have to say without attacking others.
We will do our part, we will do...
the task that is required of us,
but let it be clear:
Communication won't do any more
than the rest of my colleagues here.
Great,
because no one asked you that.
- Then it's perfect.
- I need solutions.
If we had six months, I wouldn't worry.
There would be no problems.
But we don't have them.
We have nine weeks,
actually even less.
It's eight weeks because
I have asked about this since last week.
I have a meeting
with the general management,
I need a report to present
and I have nothing for them.
In these eight weeks
the message is simple:
we work, we seek
and we find solutions.
And without leaks,
because
when the unions hear this,
I tell you,
it will be a disaster.
Then it really gets chaotic.
Hi, Lucas, it's dad.
I saw you called me.
Sorry, I was at work.
You have to prepare for your exams,
Call me back when you can.
You know
what I'm going to tell you.
I read it...
We are far from our goals.
Are you aware of it?
My answer is there,
I have nothing else to offer you
than my findings.
So what do we do?
I'm sorry but we will have to
write something else,
because I can't present your conclusions
to the general management.
I cannot.
I cannot give...
a distorted picture.
This is a serious,
coherent report from the figures,
which seems to me
to be consistent.
I did my math...
I can cut a few jobs here and there,
but the number they ask,
is impossible.
This is not the first time they have
asked for staff reductions, right?
You usually have the answers.
Why don't you have them now?
- I can find solutions...
- Good.
...but they would be wrong.
They would jeopardize
the well-being of our employees.
Don't blackmail me
with the employees' well-being.
- It's not blackmail.
- Yes, I don't want to go there.
You know well
that's not how I work.
They ask me to give up 58 people
and you give me 30.
30!
- I can give you 200 if you want...
- I don't want 200, I want 58.
Seriously, Philippe,
next time you go to Paris
to talk to Mrs. Bonnet-Guérin,
you should calmly explain to her
what can and cannot
be done in a company.
If I have to sacrifice 58 people
to save 500, then I sacrifice 58.
Think you'll save 500?
That won't happen,
but you don't get that.
You won't save them,
because they will explode.
I see them in my office every day.
You mean the weakest.
The weakest?
Do you realize what you're saying?
When they came to this company,
they weren't vulnerable at all.
They are weakened
by the constant pressure
which
has been going on for years.
They were
perfectly competent people,
who have
always accepted every challenge.
You work with them from morning
to night. You know it well.
- Olivier, stop.
- You're losing your grip, Philippe.
We have to be competitive,
otherwise we are finished.
But this is not feasible.
Not realistic.
Their demands are not realistic.
You must think
I can't make a decision.
With the lawyers
it's all a question of money.
When they talk,
I get the impression
that it's not about us.
We are left behind
just because of the money.
"I did this,
you did that..."
"Who has done more,
who has done less..."
I'm here, calm down.
This is how these things happen.
You'll think I'm only
interested in money.
Not at all.
Come on
I'm freaking out, you see?
Because I don't know
what will become of me.
I feel useless,
I'm ridiculous.
You are not useless, you're not.
We will find a way.
- I don't give a damn about money.
- I know it.
You will say what you can afford
and that's what it will be.
I am so stupid.
Come on, don't worry.
I shouldn't have called you.
I say one thing and do another.
I'm sorry, I'm useless.
It will pass.
Sorry, I shouldn't have called you.
It is ridiculous,
it doesn't make any sense.
No...
It is so nice
to have a date in a parking lot.
I like it.
We will announce the plan to the markets
in six weeks.
You have had enough time
to refine your conclusions.
I have read interesting angles,
some are near-final proposals,
others are a little less so,
hence we have this meeting.
Didier, do you want to start?
It is a very ambitious plan.
There will certainly be friction
with the trade union once announced.
Saying this,
one of the big union leaders
left the company.
He retired last year.
So we can do it.
Ok. Christophe?
I'm sorry
to spoil the party a little,
but we are asked
to get better results
with 10% less staff...
It doesn't make any sense,
it's impossible.
'Impossible'.
I don't want to hear it.
The British and
the Poles are ready.
They are not alarmed
by this requirement.
The Germans, as usual,
want to prove they are the strongest.
The Dutch will do their job,
I know them.
They manage, without complaining,
staying on time,
no problems, it will be perfect.
And the Americans
are already doing it.
It is out of the question
for France
to emerge as the black sheep
in this operation.
Tell me, Claire,
at the Las Vegas convention
two months ago,
when Mr. Cooper and the Board...
highlighted the positive numbers
of these last three years,
you were there,
you heard that.
Now Cooper himself says that
we can increase profits
by two percent in a year?
You know me,
I'm not really a socialist,
but what he asks of us
clearly serves to increase
shareholder dividends,
at the expense of work quality
at our factories.
That is obvious.
If you can fool the market,
we are all ears.
That is beyond my expertise.
On the other hand,
I would like for once to hear
what the Americans tell us.
As Cooper says:
"Always think bigger than you are."
Mrs. Bonnet-Guérin,
may I have a moment?
I would like to remind Mr. Garousse
that outsourcing of the sector
appliances is very competitive.
- We can't play victims.
- I'm not doing that.
I'm just telling you
that the cuts you ask us
will be synonymous with difficulty
for certain sites...
I would say in all factories.
And not only in France,
even abroad.
For me, in Strasbourg,
for Philippe, for Denis
and for you, Jean-Pierre.
No offense,
but you are speaking for yourself.
We don't all share your opinion.
If we don't take
our responsibilities,
if we don't do our job,
if you don't,
the responsibility will be ours,
because it will be our fault,
our lack of courage and intelligence.
But maybe this is
the scenario you want.
TODAY
is the day when
YOU
are THE KING
HAPPY BIRTHDAY, DAD!
Hi, daddy,
I just woke up here,
while in France you are
already in the middle of the day.
I wanted to tell you that
I think about you a lot
and I wish you all the best
on your birthday.
I guess you'll celebrate
with your friends.
I hope you're doing well.
I send a lot of big kisses
from across the Atlantic
and big hugs for your birthday.
Big kisses!
Who allowed it?
Excuse me, sir,
maybe it was the only way
she could produce such quantities.
I already said that
safety is not a choice.
Now I have to
tell headquarters:
"Hi, good news!
Ms Evrard blocked the device's security
and she lost her arm!"
Do I have to tell them that?
I'm just telling you how things are
for us here everyday.
Everyone knows those lines.
They are programmed to
produce a number of parts,
incorporating safety breaks.
Yes or no?
And, Mrs. Storti,
speaking clearly,
did you see someone disable a security,
and you did nothing?
If there is an anomaly,
I intervene immediately.
Apparently not.
You did not!
I intervene when there is a risk!
But I can't see everything.
What Jacqueline has done
was indeed wrong,
but for many girls,
and above all,
for those of a certain age,
the scheduled breaks
are no longer...
they are no longer enough.
Sorry. I don't want to hear it.
- They're too short.
- I can't listen to this.
I want to say something.
I respect you,
but you are not being honest.
People work hard on those lines.
They love their job and they
do try their best to keep going.
I do my best too.
I also want it to go on.
And as long as possible.
A company is not made up of numbers,
but of workers.
- First of all, people.
- Don't lecture me.
You see it under your nose.
I know my factory.
It is not true, you do not
come to the workshop.
You are no longer seen.
- It is false.
- That's it.
What are you waiting for?
That people get exhausted?
Someone kills himself?
What are you waiting for?
I want to reassure you
about your son.
He is resting.
We'll keep him here with us
for a few days
to understand exactly
what happened.
He insulted his teacher.
But not only that.
He also threatened him
with a compass,
uttering insults.
He spoke incoherently.
Very confused.
That's why we brought him here.
He came to the emergency room
where I examined him
and as we talked,
his anger subsided.
That anger was mainly
directed at that teacher,
but really had nothing
to do with him.
There is mental fatigue,
of course,
there are things that
his brain is unable to process.
I think...
it would be good
if he could be at some clinic
anywhere close to your home.
Keep in mind
that we don't know everything,
we don't have the answers yet.
We are not omnipotent.
So we have to
approach this with humility.
Humility is essential,
so that the answers can emerge.
Did you drive?
What you say is clear to me,
but it doesn't match...
It is a question of numbers.
Or perhaps...
The real problem is that
we get a standard distance,
however it is not correct.
Did the journey seem short to you?
You drove.
You can't be objective.
Did the trip seem short
or very long to you?
It seemed to me...
rather short.
Quite short...
Have you listened to any music?
No.
If you had listened to some music,
for example, two albums,
we would have calculated
how much music
does an album contain,
and we would have
got the travel time.
But we have to leave
from standard elements such as:
a kilometer is a lot,
a minute is a lot,
a meter is a lot and
a second is a lot.
Right now I'm talking about numbers
and they don't match, sorry.
Have you made any stops?
Delays, accidents,
toll booths, stops,
red traffic lights,
traffic jams?
A toll booth.
- A toll booth?
- A toll booth, yes.
- Only one?
- Yes.
- How much did you pay?
- €40.
Are you sure?
Yes, I'm sure.
Do you want to see the receipts?
Yes, if you have them.
Why "receipts"?
A toll booth or more?
No, just a toll booth.
Do you have my wallet?
Shit.
- I do not have it.
- Maybe in your pocket?
I don't have it,
it is in the car.
- Do you think it was €40?
- Yes.
Sure?
Yes, I'm sure.
So you left at 12:15 pm.
No, we left around 11:30 am...
Yes, 11:15 am... 11:20 am.
It is not possible.
The journey takes approximately
4 hours and 20 minutes.
It matches 12:15 pm.
Since it is now 4:35 pm.
I can start from the base I want.
But they give us a standard base,
saying "it is this".
My calculations don't add up.
I can start from my base,
according to what seems right to me...
and what seems right to me,
in numerical terms,
it is 12:15 pm.
Otherwise, one second...
It is not this, it is that...
Or that...
We don't have to tell Juliette.
She shouldn't
worry about her brother.
We have received your report
to the headquarters.
You sure have done
some of the work.
But I think we can
push ourselves a little further.
Have a look.
Her name is...
Genevieve Raynaud.
She's not exactly great...
Maybe not, but Mrs. Raynaud...
She is indispensable, as we have seen
during Mrs. Evrard's accident.
If she's not there,
it won't work.
OK. Let's look at it differently.
Tomorrow someone from the first shift
will be run over by a train.
- Who can't be?
- Seriously?
Nobody.
We need everyone.
But, Mr. Lefèvre,
you have to play along.
I don't make the rules,
I am an employee, like you.
I agree with Olivier,
I think like him.
We did what we could.
What could be done
has been done.
Mr. Lemesle,
I have no alternative.
I have to go back to Paris
with a solution.
It must all be solved,
I have to submit a detailed report
to Mrs. Bonnet-Guérin.
So I ask you...
Tomorrow, someone from the first shift
ends up under a train:
who would be indispensable
to the functioning of the department?
Mrs. Couton, of course...
Mrs. Couton stays.
Ms. Hermine too.
Two people
who should definitely stay.
So all the people we have mentioned
so far, are indispensable?
- They are indispensable.
- Absolutely.
OK, very good.
Therefore...
means we could...
do without
Nicole Lemercier, for instance.
If we give up on Lemercier,
it will be hell after
the first incoming smallest issue.
Mr. Lefèvre, we have too few.
Sorry, but you don't understand.
These people come to work
when they are sick.
Even when they are sick.
We need to understand
at what level we are.
We are on red alert.
But you didn't come right away
with Mrs. Lemercier.
It means she is less efficient.
We wanted to train her for the pumps,
she may be useful there.
You will not train a person
over 50 years old!
Impossible,
you don't do training
for those over 50 years old.
I'll put her on the list.
If you haven't mentioned her,
it means she is less efficient.
So we put her
on the termination list.
I was just in time
for his workshop.
Look, it's unbelievable.
I'm trying to film it, see?
Lucas is so focused.
He is so precise and focused.
You have to keep up
with your partner's pace
and listen to each other.
Position yourself well.
He's so careful.
It's good for him, I think.
I love his expression.
See? He seems to be doing better.
You have to pay attention to this:
To make him walk
he must stand upright.
He's beautiful, our son.
The puppet
is like a musical instrument.
You have to practice,
learn to play it...
He's brave.
I'm sure it helps.
He's fine, look...
Olivier, It's Philippe.
Am I disturbing you?
Listen...
Go to the Financial Director...
and calculate
simulation of total volume...
of premiums and bonuses
of all executives within a year.
I mean, for me,
the other directors
of the French sites,
all Director Assistants
and the top managers
of the headquarters.
That is, Bonnet-Guérin
and her team.
- Hello.
I'm looking for cumin.
Hello.
At the clinic they told you
that was okay for tonight?
Yes, they accepted
6 pm instead of 5 pm.
I'll take this one.
So...
- I'm not sure.
- Try it, use your face.
They all have problems...
- No, look.
- Go on.
Your car looks like a wreck.
It seems that a part is missing.
No, on the contrary.
- Does it have extra parts?
- It is very robust.
Too many parts.
I'll do it again, look.
Does he suffer from road rage?
Is it introverted?
It is nervous?
- Small and nervous?
- No.
A little... edgy?
It is not edgy,
on the contrary.
- Is it severe?
- No.
- Does it only have two doors?
- Yes.
- A Beetle?
- No.
The model of...
- Is it French? - No.
- The model of what?
- Italian?
- No.
- German, then.
I'll do it again.
It's frightening.
- Horrible.
- Look.
Is it English?
Ancient?
- Is it Italian?
- German?
It has a lot...
- It has a lot of personality.
- Mom, are you German?
- Is it an Aston Martin?
- I was going to say it!
I thought about James Bond.
No, it's more...
More like that.
Wait a minute,
you're doing the opposite.
- You just did...
- I don't see what I'm doing.
It's more... an Aston Martin
would be more like that...
Very much so.
This car is more...
I know what it is.
- A very expensive car?
- Very expensive.
- Is it a Rolls-Royce?
- Not at all.
Shit!
Isn't that an Aston Martin?
We are on the wrong track,
if it's not English...
It is elegant and sporty.
- Isn't that a Ferrari?
- No.
The other one you like.
- Not a Porsche?
- But yes!
- But it's German, the Porsche!
- I said it.
- You've been saying it wasn't.
- I was hoping it wasn't German.
If us five plant managers,
our subordinates,
Bonnet-Guérin and her staff in Paris,
give up our premiums
and our bonuses for one year only,
we can avoid employee layoffs
and our factories are not at risk.
What is it
that doesn't convince you?
I don't see it that way.
I can cut the staff.
There will be arms wrestling
with the trade unions, but so be it.
We've seen that before.
What do we care?
Jean-Pierre, that's not the point.
I think if us, five directors,
we go in front of Bonnet-Guérin
with my solution,
which is super solid, well argued,
greatly structured,
then I think
we have a strong case.
- I'm not sure.
- Yes. A strong case.
She will have to listen to us
and report to the Americans and Cooper.
This is how I see it.
If you don't have the balls
to cut the branches,
It's your problem, not mine.
We have the balls,
and we ask you to have the balls
to come with us
to say Bonnet-Guérin
what we must do differently.
For me,
meeting such a difficult
requirement is a way to
get out of my comfort zone
and make progress.
I think we have different goals.
This will weaken our factories.
Inevitably, one will end up giving in,
we don't know which...
and the other four will have to
recover production.
Maybe some of you -
do you really want this?
- Insult us, while you're at it.
- I'm not insulting anyone.
Mine is an engineer reflex,
I try to understand...
the logic of your position.
You insult us and, as an engineer,
can you give us management lessons?
He's not insulting you
and not giving lessons.
- That's all he does.
- No,
he neither insults you,
nor gives you lessons.
But it is our duty,
as plant managers,
to notify the general management
of the dangers of restructuring.
I will be even more direct
than Jean-Pierre.
None of us
steals salary and bonuses,
we deserve them.
Anyway, I will not give to the company
my bonuses and rewards.
Christophe, join us,
I'm running out of arguments.
Help me, explain it to him.
It is true that
I have not said anything so far,
but I'm not sure anymore
that it is necessary to fight against
the management's economic plan.
You, Christophe?
Who put Bonnet-Guérin in her place
and he talked to her...
You remember what you said, right?
Who explained to her that
all this makes no sense...
Are you saying that
you changed your mind today?
- Yes, and I have the right.
- It is not a question of law.
- The situation has not changed.
- Mine does.
The management made it clear that
if I'm too cocky, I lose my job.
How much do I have left?
Four more years until I retire?
I've been
breaking my ass for years.
I will not go without
what they owe me, I deserved it.
You are telling me
you're okay with retirement
leaving behind
a weakened company?
- Is that so?
- Wait...
You all realize that
we are at a dead end?
Philippe and I alone
will never convince the Group.
It's every man for himself.
- Every man for himself?
- It's not that simple...
Yes, it is everyone for himself.
- Philippe, stop fooling yourself.
- I'm not.
Yes, you do
because it is possible that
the Group wants
that we run into a wall.
Then it's easier
to close factories in France
and relocate them
to low-wage countries.
- And Cooper can get even richer.
- It's exactly the other way around.
Cooper wants to cut costs
without endangering its companies.
What I am
desperately trying to tell you.
Okay, but not with my money,
or his, or his!
Can I sit down?
We came for a chat.
Your father came to me
with the list of textbooks
you asked him.
He didn't know if
he should buy them or not,
he asked for advice.
I suggested
to talk to you about it.
What do you think?
No, but it's normal
to ask you for advice.
But I absolutely
need those books...
to catch up and
prepare for the year-end exam.
Do you think you are left behind?
I got a little behind,
but it is normal.
But I have to catch up.
If I could have my books,
it would be useful to me.
Does it seem difficult to you
to catch up for these 15 days?
In any case,
I really can't risk it
to waste more time, not anymore.
I'm already
not very proud of what I did,
I would like to get back to work.
You don't have to be
ashamed, you know?
It happens to a lot of people.
But what exactly
are you ashamed of?
You don't do these things
in front of others,
and I know that...
that my classmates
attack me on social media.
It doesn't matter, I understand...
but I have to catch up on time
that I have spent here.
Do you really
need those books now...
to prepare for your exam?
Well, the sooner I get them, the sooner
I can start to prepare for the exam.
For example, on the list...
You got it?
Your father gave it to me.
I wrote down
the most important ones,
But...
about these they will
question us for sure.
Jean-Marie Peretti,
Human resources, 2017.
Sure, you have to know it by heart.
The evolution of Toyotism since '93.
A lot...
You don't think you should rest
a little longer, catch your breath?
I'm rested and it's quiet here.
I feel much better.
That is amazing.
And then, what
really motivates me...
That...
I was lucky because my time here
coincided with the holiday,
so I didn't miss much.
In that sense, I was very lucky.
What do you think about
what is Lucas is saying?
Well...
I'm glad he's feeling better.
Maybe it's worth a try.
He has worked hard in recent years,
it would be foolish
to penalize him,
and it is also for his future.
That's right,
the job that I have done in recent years
it takes shape now,
in the year-end exam.
- I understand, it's a lot of work.
- Yes, that's a bit of a shame...
But do you see yourself
going back home?
- Resuming the Business School...
- I'm better.
...resuming the courses,
do you feel like it?
- Of course.
- Doesn't that scare you?
No, I'm not afraid.
Here I took a break and
it did me a lot of good.
I am super motivated.
Especially since,
if I pass the exam,
I will have a job at Facebook.
So that's really cool.
It motivates me even more
to commit myself.
Do you already know that you will
be hired by Facebook? - Yes.
- Since when?
- If I pass the exam.
I posted my resume on Facebook,
and Mark Zuckerberg answered me.
He said he's interested.
So great.
I just have to pass the exam.
It will be a formality,
if I have the books.
And then things
will run their course.
Did you talk to him on the phone?
First on Messenger,
then he gave me his number.
So I could
explain things clearly to him.
All right... wow...
When did it happen?
Recently.
While you were here?
Did everything fall into place?
The phone call, the resume?
How did you understand
that he would hire you after the exam?
Because I felt his enthusiasm,
from how he listened to me,
and the ideas I proposed for Facebook.
I felt he was excited,
so I took advantage of it,
and in the end he made an offer to me
if I pass the exam.
An important position.
So I need those books fast
to prepare for the exam.
I have read
your alternative proposal,
and I'll tell you right away,
I am both dissatisfied and disappointed
in the way you handled it.
I have personally
vouched to Mr. Cooper
that you would deliver
your conclusions on time.
I'm late now.
I ask you for the conclusions
and the lists as soon as possible.
The other European sites
did it without any problems.
- Not true.
- We know that's not true.
In Germany and Italy, some
directors are in the same situation.
We know
everything went very well.
The plant managers
talk to each other.
We share information.
Denis, I only see an opportunity
for Americans to say
that the French
do not face challenges.
Claire, why don't you
consider our proposal
as an opportunity for the Group?
Meaning?
Instead of seeing it as an obstacle,
why not interpret it as a signal?
A strong signal for everyone.
And a way to demonstrate
to our collaborators
that all the executives of Elsonn
share the risks.
At the same time,
that the Group defends values
that Mr. Cooper emphasizes so much
in all his speeches.
"Fairness and generosity".
Let's talk about this.
- Is there a business strategy?
- Yes.
- Do you know it by heart?
Let's stick to that.
We stick to it
if the strategy is beneficial.
But at any cost?
A strategy that throws our results and
our collaborators in uncertainty:
do we stick to it anyway?
Is this the policy?
Everything is uncertain.
Life, health, love, work.
So, it will be clear,
I'm not going
to hand this over to Mr. Cooper.
Because,
if you continue on this road,
you will give a deplorable image
to the American board.
He is right,
you are an exceptional manager.
I'm not flattering you,
we all know.
You were extraordinary
two years ago,
and I was the first
to give you praise
for the work done
with the layoff plan.
Now what's gotten into you,
from one day to another?
They will not understand.
We are here to make proposals -
concrete, alternative,
to defend an idea.
It is wonderful
to defend one's ideas,
but do you realize
the consequences?
You can lose your job
that you are putting into play.
It is a steep price for an idea.
Let's talk about
defending our work.
- This is what we're talking about.
- You're doing it very badly.
If you don't, others
will do it in your place.
No questions asked.
You have a special relationship
with the trade unions,
you can make them swallow anything.
Do not risk for other negotiators
to face them.
You are extraordinary,
respected by your teams,
because you respect them.
Take advantage of this
to present conclusions acceptable
to Mr. Cooper and his team,
and less painful
for those that will leave,
and also
for those who will stay.
Focus on this.
That's what the company wants
from you now.
I need you now.
I'm sorry to tell you that...
No.
We will not be able
to fulfill this request.
If you do not satisfy the request,
you take your responsibilities.
We are not here
to obstruct, Claire.
We are here to defend the company
in the long term.
I'm not deaf, Philippe.
And you, do you listen to me?
I will not present this
to Mr. Cooper and his staff.
I personally
vouched to Mr. Cooper
that all French sites
will respond in the same way.
Agree.
It means that if Denis and I
do not fulfill the request,
we risk our jobs.
And Mr. Cooper
will see this refusal
as a consequence
of your failed policies.
Of course.
- You're going too far.
- Why?
You can't get the benefits
without the drawbacks.
Mr. Baumont, please.
No advantages without drawbacks.
You are at the head of the
Elsonn France group, right?
So, if we...
poor little directors
of a regional plant,
we don't do our homework,
because you can't make us do it.
This is what Mr. Cooper will think.
The great director of Elsonn France
declares this meeting closed.
- It's not over.
- We stop here.
Mr. Lemesle,
it's been five minutes since...
- It's not over.
- At this point, we have nothing to lose.
I didn't think I'd come to this.
Claire, I tell you clearly,
Pulcinella's little secret:
that Mr. Cooper wants to appoint you
as the head of European zone, right?
- And what do you want to say?
- Everybody knows.
Everyone knows it, Claire.
So I have a question:
Are you prepared
to disappoint Mr. Cooper?
telling him that two directors
of the establishment,
Denis and I,
will not respond to the request?
Are you ready to take the risk?
He will see it as
a management failure.
Are you aware of it?
I ask if you are ready
to take this risk.
Answer me.
If you can't answer me,
present this proposal
to Mr. Cooper and his staff.
We ask no more.
Good morning.
Take a seat.
We wanted to see you
because we would like to know
if the rumors circulating
in the company are founded.
Elsonn is rumored
to be preparing a layoff plan
that would concern
10% of the workforce.
Who said that?
It doesn't matter who said it.
We want to know
if it's true or not.
Madam...
Mrs. Laurent,
you ask me for a meeting in my office,
so I want to know who
is spreading those rumors.
We are not here for that.
But because of these rumors,
some of us
are worried and also angry.
It's not my job to
make rumors, to confirm or deny.
What does it mean?
That the rumors are well founded?
- Are they partly true?
- I did not say this.
And, if I had an announcement to make,
I wouldn't do it in this office,
you see?
There are legal procedures,
you know the rules.
Okay, there are procedures,
but the workers are worried.
If there's really nothing going on,
you can tell us. Simple.
I cannot.
- Yes you can.
- No.
Legally
there is nothing that forbids it.
I want to know who
is spreading those rumors.
Disrupting a team is easy.
I can do that too.
If no layoffs are planned,
tell us it's not true,
Then we leave. End of story.
Then we can reassure people, okay?
And we end it here.
- If that pleases you, fine.
- It's not to please us.
That's not what
we're here for, okay?
We will not give you names.
You must understand that
people in your factory are worried.
People talk...
Maybe, instead,
it would be better to keep quiet.
Sir, it's simple:
Tell us
there is no layoff plan in place
and we leave.
- I'm telling you.
- Excuse me?
I am telling you.
Do you guarantee us that Elsonn
has no layoffs plan right now?
Is this it?
- Exactly, yes.
- Okay.
So you declare officially
that Elsonn doesn't have
a plan of dismissal right now?
And we can share it
with colleagues, right?
Exactly.
Thank you.
Denis, can you answer?
You know very well that
the factory cannot function
with fewer people.
- Yes it can.
- No.
It will collapse, Mr. Lemesle.
It will collapse and you know it.
It will hold up.
It will collapse, I tell you.
Do you think that I want
to ruin everyone?
- It's not collapsing, I tell you.
- Sir, excuse me.
I have a simple question.
What is the purpose of the Americans
with this layoff plan?
Squeeze ourselves more and more,
more and more?
Squeeze us until
the company collapses?
And after that, what will we do?
Let me finish.
All our skills will go abroad?
Letizia, you're imagining things.
There's no conspiracy behind it.
I don't imagine anything.
We will reorganize and
we will find solutions.
What solutions?
Let me tell you something:
A few years ago
you would've never allowed it.
- Not true.
- It is so.
- A moment...
- Never...
You don't care.
At the end of the year
you fill your pockets.
Don't talk to me like that.
I talk how I want.
For the last seven years
you have been cutting back,
making us overworked.
We are tired,
and you fill your pockets.
Don't go down the road
of offense or insinuation!
Who is insulting who?
No, you're going too far.
Mr. Lemesle didn't insult you.
If there is always quality dialogue
in this company, it's thanks to him.
We are getting nowhere.
I would like to get to one point.
I would like
to come back to one thing.
Your word.
We were in your office,
you looked at us and said:
"No layoff plan".
Is it true or not?
I told you it was not the right place
to make an announcement.
That's not what he said.
If you want me to invent things
to please you...
Mr. Lemesle couldn't
have told you more.
He knows perfectly well
what he said.
- He couldn't have told you more.
- Of course he did!
I ask you again:
Yes or no?
Did you tell us
there wasn't a layoff plan?
Yes or no?
I told you it was not the right place
to announce a layoff plan.
By the way, since you were there,
remember
that I have evoked the law.
- That's not true.
- You are lying, sir.
You mentioned the law and
that it was not the right place,
but in the end
you made us a promise.
That nothing was expected,
you said it.
You may have not
understood correctly.
We did not understand?
Do you think
we have not understood?
And you too?
Did I misunderstand?
And Cedric too?
Did Jean get it wrong?
Are you sure you want
to go down this road?
You can look me in the eye
and tell me that I misunderstood?
Are you sure
you want to play this game?
Then I'll tell you one thing:
that conversation...
we recorded it.
This is outrageous!
You talk to us about trust
since we've been here
and then secretly record?
That's not trust!
- We fight with what we have.
- We protect ourselves.
How can we have confidence?
I propose that
we listen to Cedric's cell phone.
What do you say, Mr. Lemesle?
What do you think?
...Tell us there is
no layoff plan in place
and we leave.
Excuse me?
I'll tell you.
Do you guarantee us
that Elsonn
has no layoff plan right now?
Is this it?
Exactly, yes.
Okay.
So you declare officially
that Elsonn doesn't have
a plan of dismissal right now?
Beautiful space
and yet it feels cozy.
True.
And the heating?
- Floor heating.
- Okay.
There is a heat pump outside,
connected to the boiler,
which heats very well.
Even these large spaces?
No, the heat rises
and no need for other heat sources
for the mezzanine.
- No need.
- Just the boiler is enough...
Yes, absolutely.
- Just in case, there's a fireplace.
- Exactly.
We didn't expect it.
Indeed.
I love this space.
Very cozy.
The house has many nooks.
You can be alone and still be together.
Exactly.
One can work upstairs,
the other rests below.
Ideal for a family.
The living spaces
run into each other.
They are shared.
It's exactly
what we're looking for.
And the bedrooms are isolated...
You can still have privacy.
Absolutely.
It would be nice
to show it to Jeanne.
I'm sure she would like it.
Could we see it again?
Of course.
Our little girl would be thrilled
to give her opinion.
It will not be difficult
to convince her.
- Do you have a daughter?
- Yes.
A four-year-old girl.
What do you think?
I love it.
Exceptional.
Love at first sight.
We made some things nicer.
That can be fun too.
Of course.
And the light?
On the South.
Directly on the South.
In summer it must be...
magical, full of light.
Are you staying in the region?
No, we're moving.
"With your irresponsibility
and lack of leadership,
you have violated the French laws,
deliberately lying
to the union representatives,
stating, in your office,
that the Elsonn Group
did not consider a layoff plan.
Furthermore,
the recorded conversation
was obtained by the media,
while not preventing its implementation,
it has hindered
the peaceful application
of the Group's economic plan,
and has seriously compromised
the image of the company,
its deep ethical commitment
and respect
that is the basis of well-being
of employees and the brand.
Furthermore,
the well-known friendship
with your Director of Operations,
Olivier Lefèvre,
undermined
your managerial authority,
preventing you from realizing
the vision of the Elsonn Group.
This lack of dedication
to the values of Elsonn
prevented you from developing
a constructive dialogue
with staff representatives,
in order to carry out
the restructuring
necessary for
the survival of the company.
Noting the extreme
gravity of the facts,
the Elsonn Group
proceeds to your dismissal
for serious misconduct
to the effect
of immediate departure
and without severance pay."
Do you want to say something?
I would like to say just one thing:
I expected more loyalty
from the Elsonn Group.
I understand.
But perhaps Elsonn
expected more loyalty from you.
But I was loyal.
I've done my job.
I have the feeling that
you didn't get the full support.
What do you mean?
I'm asking you a question.
Don't you think...
Perhaps...
I'm not saying
that you did everything right.
But...
we could say, maybe...
maybe you will agree,
that the one who has hindered
the peaceful execution
of the restructuring plan the most...
Let Lefèvre be your Director
of Operations? Olivier Lefèvre?
Why...
What is the task
of a Director of Operations?
Support and accompany
the plant manager.
- Do you agree?
- Yes.
Not to put a stick in the wheel.
Lefèvre did nothing else.
Do you think I'm not aware?
Do you really think
that no one tells me anything?
It is true that
because of my position,
I spend my time
at the headquarters in Paris.
But I get it all.
I know it all.
I know what happens,
practically in real time,
at each site of the Group.
Mr. Baumont,
tell him what you told me
after you spent the day
on the site of Mr. Lemesle.
Of that visit,
I remember very well
that Lefèvre was extremely negative
about the economic plan
wanted by the Group.
Do you remember that...
we wrote names on the list?
We can say that Mr. Lefèvre
put up a lot of resistance.
He was against everything.
We could even say
that he completely refused
to collaborate on the project.
When we have...
Philippe, look at me.
When we have
a role of responsibility,
like Lefèvre's,
shouldn't we
put the public interest
before our personal scruples?
Yes.
I think that...
your friend Olivier Lefèvre,
took you too far for too long
on the ground of feelings.
That's also what we like about you.
Your value.
Your great humanity.
Everyone recognizes it.
But the fact is that
at the end of the day
you are the only one who pays.
I find it very unfair.
I think Mr. Lefèvre
is totally responsible
for this fiasco.
I'll go a little further.
In my opinion,
Elsonn would have all the interest
to get rid of someone like Lefèvre.
For several reasons.
I'll mention only two.
First, what I believe
is the most important one -
the well-being of employees.
When an element like him,
with his level of responsibility,
prevents a smooth course
of industrial policy,
he just creates a mess.
That happens constantly.
And I think he was very sneaky.
I'm going one step further.
I think that
he had an idea for a while.
Because right now,
the position that is vacant, Philippe,
it's yours.
I don't think it's fair
that it's you who has to
carry the cross for everything.
And here
I come to the second reason.
If you agree to help us
to ensure that Mr. Lefèvre
leaves the company,
I think it would be
a great opportunity for you,
to prove that
you are back in the saddle,
that you take back control.
It would allow everyone to say,
starting with Mr. Cooper:
"Of course,
he is cut out for the task
that we have entrusted to him."
And I also say that...
You know, I have great
respect for you,
so I'm telling you as a friend,
it's also the opportunity to say:
"It was a misstep."
And as to this setback,
makes it a strength
a means for the future,
of your professional career.
Here's what I think.
Does it mean that,
if I accept your proposal,
I start with a clean slate
for Mr. Cooper?
Is that right?
As if nothing had happened?
I'm convinced
that he'd appreciate it.
For sure.
Dear Mrs. Bonnet-Guérin,
A few days ago,
you gave me the chance
to renew the confidence
that the company
had initially placed in me.
Thank you for giving me the
opportunity to prove who I am.
By canceling the contract
of my Director of Operations,
Mr. Olivier Lefèvre,
I'd avoid being fired
for my mistakes.
I'm lucky,
because, it is with your offer,
I could understand
what kind of man I have become
in your eyes and, without a doubt,
in the eyes of many others.
A despicable man,
if you think I could
accept your proposal,
as I am solely responsible
of any inefficiency
at my factory.
Responsible
for obliging the foremen
to turn a blind eye
to dangerous procedures
in assembly lines.
Responsible for lying to my team,
while I was constantly abusing
their loyalty
and devotion.
I was the good soldier
that you wanted me to be.
You call that courage,
but I call it cowardice or stupidity.
The few qualities I do possess,
I didn't even need them
to see our madness.
I've done all of this
for a hefty salary
and I certainly would
even for much less,
because where I thought
to find intelligence
I found nothing but indecency.
My freedom
certainly comes with a cost,
but it's still priceless.
Consequently, I ask firmly
that the totality of faults
that you attribute to me,
fall exclusively on me
and only on me,
as you phrased it.
Those words describe exactly
the man in the position that
the Elsonn Group had entrusted to me.
And most importantly, they describe
a man I don't want to have
as a friend
as a father
or as a husband.
Sincerely,
Philippe Lemesle.