(upbeat music)
Good evening, Mrs. Hicks.
I'm calling about invoice number
137.
There's a balance due
of $365 and 17 cents.
We sent a copy in the
envelope with your order.
Did you receive your order?
I do have your PO number right
here.
It's 137..
I'm sorry to hear that.
But I'm gonna have to
report to my supervisor
and let him know your intentions
in regards to this past due
invoice.
Well you have until the
13th, so enjoy your day.
Wait, Mrs. Hicks?
Can I ask you a question?
How long have you lived in
Denver?
Really?
Wow, that's a long time.
Don't you ever feel like you
just wanna...
leave?
Just let me do it.
Here you go.
I don't think I'll be coming
over anymore.
(soft piano music)
Oh fuck.
Do you think that maybe you can
just turn it back on
for tonight and I can literally
come in tomorrow morning
with a check for you guys or?
Okay. All right.
Well, thank you.
Thank you for your help.
(soft piano music)
Hey Kenny.
Audrey?
Hey, oh sweet.
Well I have to talk
to you about something.
Yeah.
Kenny's been complaining
about the noise and he said,
okay.
He says that you've been-
Fornicating?
That's it.
I don't think it's gonna
be a problem anymore.
Glad to hear it.
(upbeat music)
(dog barking)
Hey mom.
Yeah, things are going really
great.
I just...
I've just been
you know, working and
you know
I'm not seeing anyone right now.
But...
(phone ringing)
Happy Mother's Day.
[Audrey's Mom] Hello,
call me the regular way.
[Narrator] This is Teddy
one of our North American
Porcupines.
(piano music)
(Audrey singing)
You don't do good phone work.
I disagree.
That's what it says here.
It says you better not
dealing directly with people.
But that's not true.
I'm really nice to people.
I'm sure you are.
I just don't have any-
What else does it say?
I'm terribly sorry but
we're gonna have to let you go.
Okay, cool. Got it.
Thank you so much. You
enjoy your day (crosstalk).
You too.
(guitar music)
[Warren] Audrey hey it's Warren
I'm supposed to call it hang on
Jesus I know
If you want someone to do
something
you can just say it
and then you can let them do it.
You don't have to keep yelling
at them.
Sorry, I'm sorry Audrey
You have to get the rent
it's normal to do that
and it's really late.
It's Warren, OK bye.
(girl yodeling)
(cheery music)
(dogs barking)
[Narrator] Okay so, I just
adopted a dog
and I think it's already one
of the best decisions I've ever
made.
We had a sleep over the first
night before I adopted him.
And he's literally the perfect
dog.
[Narrator] Look at that face
how can you resist?
Surprisingly, there's a lot of
older dogs
who are in need of a
new family to love them.
Most older dogs make wonderful-
(car engine revving)
[Narrator] Adoptions create
families.
And the desire for a family
is something we never lose.
No matter how old we are.
Adult adoption is on the rise
and it is creating families
all over the world.
If you're ready to start the
search for your forever family
please visit our website
at adult adoption.
Hi there, I've never had any
kids.
My wife and I are kind of lonely
here.
And I think it'd be helpful
for us to have someone
it's a funny thing, how it came
about.
We were thinking about going
to the humane society and
picking out an animal.
The reason why I would
like to adopt somebody is
because I feel it's very
possible
that many of us have been
in families in other lives.
And that it's possible
that we might meet one
of those family members in this
life.
But I think I could share some
joy
with an adult who maybe has
never had these things either.
If you're an adult who is
looking
for an adoptive mother,
feel free to get in-
Hi, my name's Audrey.
And I'm looking to be adopted.
It was really nice watching your
video
and I hope that we get to meet.
Wishing you the best
over here by the river.
Thanks. Bye.
So um
I used to garden.
But I don't anymore because
of the arthritis now.
No not in five years.
I mean, we have so much in
common.
The music thing for starters
how many people really
like Dixieland Jazz?
I know they say they do but they
don't.
Actually we don't like jazz at
all.
We're just being polite.
Wheat toast and some water
please.
Audrey?
Ted.
Is Nancy coming.
Nancy.
Your wife?
Oh, she's parking the car.
Parking is pretty bad
around here, I guess.
I'm really excited about this
Audrey.
I'm excited too.
So you want a daddy?
[Sunny] Hello, my name is Sunny.
I've never had children,
but over the years
I've watched people who do
I've seen
so much misunderstanding in
families.
I think that if parents
can try to understand
that the things they say can
mean so much to their children
even little things can mean
something big.
If I was ever lucky enough to
be a parent, I'd be the kind
of parent who thinks about
what they say to their child.
And is kind.
(soft music)
(door bell chiming)
Hi Audrey?
I'm Sunny.
Hi.
You didn't have to bring
anything.
Oh we don't have to eat it.
Come in. It smells good.
That's the cumin.
Have a seat.
Would you like some tea?
I had a boss once who told me
I should be on medication.
I think he was trying to help.
But I don't know.
Did you take his advice?
No, no.
I don't want to mess with my
brain.
Oh, do you mind if I charge my
phone?
Here, I'll do it for you.
Thanks.
What kind of job was it?
What?
The one with the boss
and the medication.
Oh God, I don't even remember
I've had so many jobs.
You move around?
I do.
You're a seeker.
Time for dinner?
Otto, this is Audrey.
Nice to meet you.
Hmm.
Words Otto.
Hello.
What is this?
Audrey brought it.
Wasn't that nice?
I made spaghetti.
We will have spaghetti.
Dinner will be ready soon
Otto why don't you tell Mutti.
Hmm.
Mutti is Otto's mother.
He has two children, Gretchen
and John.
Otto calls him Johan, but
everybody else calls him John.
Otto is very traditional.
It's nice.
Do they live nearby?
Yes, but we hardly see them.
They have their own lives.
Otto and I met online.
We both lost our spouses.
So there was nothing bad...
It wasn't that kind of online.
Right
I have to tell you something
Audrey.
Otto doesn't know why you're
here.
I'm sorry.
I was gonna tell him but
I didn't know how.
Hi, Audrey, this is Sunny.
I'd love to meet you.
And if things work out
I would love for you to join our
family.
I'm sorry Otto, I should have
told you.
So your parents are still alive?
What's wrong with them?
Why do you need this strange
thing?
Is she here about the cable?
We don't have cable Mutti.
Television is bad enough
without the cable.
You're missing nothing.
The internet?
Endless sickening pablum.
It could be a good source for
news.
What news?
The world is still a stinking
mess.
God is still dead.
Some sites can be educational.
I don't know if you guys
hadn't gone to the internet
you wouldn't have met, right?
Hmm.
This is really delicious.
Sunny, thank you.
Otto's an engineer.
Seriously?
Yah.
I am retired from NASA.
Oh, cool.
What were you doing there?
Do you have a degree in
aeronautical engineering?
No.
So how would you
expect to understand it?
She's just trying to be polite
Otto.
(phone ringing)
(Otto speaking in German)
Otto and his son have a
difficult relationship.
He does get along a little
better with his daughter though.
Johan lives his life as if
there are no other people.
What kind of man calls at dinner
time.
How old are you?
Mutti die stille!
Don't listen to her she's almost
blind.
Also she's losing her mind.
These symptoms are to be
expected
as an individual nears death.
(Mutti speaks in foreign
language)
Tell Otto where you were before.
I was working in Montana
I was at this little
resort and I was a cook.
How long you were there?
Well, it was a seasonal job.
So it's about three months.
How long have stayed in
Saugerties?
Pretty long like I
think it's a year now.
That's a long time?
For me it is.
What brought you here?
I was visiting a friend.
What happened to the friend?
I don't know.
Audrey was raised in California.
The beaches.
The warm sand.
We lived really kind
of far from the beach
only went there a couple times.
How do you like it here Audrey?
I like it.
I like the river.
It's very deep.
This is what enabled whaling
vessels
to sail up from the ocean.
Whales?
Yah!
In 1766, the British
parliament placed a duty
on whale oil shipped to Britain.
So a group of whalers in
Nantucket
disassembled their houses
and used them to make ships
they then sailed them up the
Hudson River.
Two miles from here they
disassembled their ships
and reassembled their
houses to create a village.
We now know as Hudson.
So they actually dragged
the whales up the river?
No.
First they stripped the blubber.
It's known as flensing.
The remainder of the carcass was
discarded
in the open ocean.
Sunny I've finished eating.
It is time to play.
What are we playing?
Pretty sad looking tree
house you've got there.
It was there when we moved in.
Sunny your hips are not aligned.
That's good now go the other
way.
Oh good shot.
[Sunny] Come on Mutti
You are sane approximately.
A sane as you are.
So
We will call this an experiment.
Sunny and I are taking Mutti to
Bavaria
in the fall to see our old
farm before she expires.
So we're gonna conduct
this experiment until then
and at that time we
will assess the results.
Perhaps it will continue.
Perhaps it will be conclusive,
yah.
Sounds like a plan.
Of course the farm
is now a shopping mall.
We'll take her to another place
and tell her it's the actual
farm.
You don't think she's gonna
notice?
(yodeling music)
(Audrey singing)
[Narrator] Today I'm gonna
walk you guys
through doing acrylic on windows
and that is kinda what's up
with this glow right back here
this is actually blue
and I'll show you guys pictures
of the whole thing afterwards
but just a couple tips
before we get started.
(soft music)
Hey.
What's going on?
Oh just getting off work.
Is that biodegradable?
The paint?
Yeah.
Yeah, absolutely.
Don't let any get on the
tomatoes.
Got it.
You know it's the seventh,
right?
Yeah.
I'm on it.
At the tone, please record your
message.
When you've finished recording
you may hang up or press one for
more.
Hey guys, it's me Audrey.
I was just calling to say hello
and hope everything's going
well.
And, um
And dad I just wanted to
check in and see how you were.
So
Yeah!
Just give me a call whenever you
can.
All right, things are
going really good here.
So
I'll talk to you soon. All
right, bye.
♪ Whoa, whoa, yea, yea ♪
♪ I miss you more than I can say
♪
♪ Why must my life be
filled with sorrow? ♪
♪ Oh, oh, love you more than I
can say ♪
♪ Oh don't you know I need you
so? ♪
♪ Oh tell me please, I gotta
know! ♪
♪ Do you mean to make me cry? ♪
I call this MIYM chicken.
It means melt in your mouth.
I hope you like it.
It looks great.
It's very moist.
What's the matter with her?
I'm fine
I'm fine.
Otto would you go
see if she's all right.
A woman should go.
I think I have like a
stomach flu or something.
You don't have the flu.
Children sometimes unburden
themselves to their parents.
Yeah, so I've heard.
Still I'm objectively
interested in your difficulties.
My dad ran over my pet
chicken when I was eight.
It wasn't his fault.
It just he
was backing out of the garage
and he just ran her over.
I've heard of this
happening to cats and dogs.
No somebody got me an incubator
and two fertilized eggs
and one just sat there.
And the other one hatched.
And I had her for like a year
and a half.
It was responsive to affection.
My own father was a professor.
He knew nothing about farming,
but in Germany after the
war, there was no food.
He was forced to learn
to raise sheep.
We were told
that we were not to
become fond of the lambs
because they were to eat.
So
We will not serve chicken
while you are here.
Thank you.
Emotions.
You have grandkids right?
Two. They are seldom here.
They'd really like a tree house.
Would they?
Yeah, they would.
Hey I'm Bobby I like to make
stuff.
Today we're gonna start
building a tree house.
(upbeat music)
This is gonna be a two part
video.
And in the first part
we're gonna build a big sturdy
platform
and in the second part we'll
make it look really cool.
(upbeat music)
It's hard sometimes
we must take care of our
parents.
I'll see you later Otto.
No.
First we must unload the lumber.
You know I can stay with
her sometimes if you want.
[Narrator] You may have heard
there's a smooth service
called the horizon,
out of which nothing can escape.
You may have also read
there's something called
the singularity of the
center of a black hole
where everything is crushed
into an infinitesimally.
Small infinitely dense point.
Even these two simple
facts are likely wrong
or at least more complicated.
But nobody knows for sure.
If only we had the cable.
[Narrator] Inside there
to be a ball of string.
There could be an incredibly
compact star.
You've done this before?
Shh.
Hey
Hi.
Did you guys have a nice time?
Sunny give me two minutes to
prepare.
(opera music)
A hamburger you can
put it in the microwave.
Thanks.
Good night.
[Audrey's Mom] Audrey its mom.
You call us again and again
and then when I call you
back you can't pick up?
What the fuck is wrong with you.
You gotta be available when we
reach out.
(Humpback whales groaning)
(upbeat music)
Come in.
Here are the tools.
You know how to use them?
Yeah, I know how to use a lot
of things.
I see.
You're trying to induce me to
say
that a woman can't operate power
tools no?
No I just sort of expected
to be said that's all.
I imagine you do, for a
moment I considered that
then I thought she's an honest
person.
She wouldn't tell me she can
use them if she couldn't.
My son one time expressed
interest in
power tools.
And then we went to a hardware
store bought all of this.
You know how to use them?
No.
Sons want fathers to do these
things,
don't they?
I think they just want
fathers to hang out with them.
I'm not a man who hangs out.
Go on, open the next.
Okay.
Now I'm retired.
Now I'm hanging out.
And in this hanging out
I discovered a curious
effect of deceleration.
There are now gaps between my
activities.
These gaps allow me to
experience regret.
For example, activity
I wasn't a father.
Activity
I was not a husband.
Activity, I was a man who worked
too much.
Activity, I was a man who grew
angry.
It's nauseating.
All right, shall we get to work?
You ever built a tree house
before?
Yeah.
(saw humming)
So shall we say we will
complete it
by the 4th of July so the
grandchildren can enjoy it.
We?
(upbeat music)
(phone ringing)
Hi Dad I'm just um
I'm actually building
a tree house right now.
Because he only had two worms.
Hey Kenny.
[Warren] Hey, Audrey, it's
Warren.
Maybe you got my message that I
left.
You have to pay the rent.
It's time to do that now.
And can you just pay it?
I'll just knock again.
I can lower the rent,
like a hundred dollars.
I can ask my mom.
Thanks Warren it's okay.
You know its time to go.
I gotta go.
For your mom?
Okay.
When am I gonna get the
deposit back?
Well we can see what's left
after I refinish the floors.
I'm sure it'll be fine.
Cool.
(gentle music)
Sunny!
Sunny the wind is predicted
to rise to twelve knots
At three forty five.
So, we have to finish the pie by
two.
So, there is time to enjoy
the Fat Daddy.
He's nervous. His kids are
coming.
How can I help?
I can peel those if you want.
Why don't you go help Otto.
Of course.
You need some help?
Some of these balls of
fire can be unpredictable.
You have to be prepared.
Okay. Got it.
Sunny, she seems all right?
Yeah I think so.
Happy Fourth of July, Johan.
John.
He's my son.
The marinate is a little sticky.
So you might wanna grease the
grill.
So is your sister coming?
Gretchen should be here soon.
She has to celebrate with
her ex's family first.
Sounds complicated.
It's a much better situation
now.
Otto loves his fireworks.
I know who calculates the
wind age prior to ignition?
The wind age?
That's the correct term.
Johan do not under cook the
steaks.
Ay you Kraut bastard.
How'd your parents die Audrey?
My parents aren't dead.
Then why are we adopting you?
Guys can we leave her alone?
She has enough problems.
So what's up with the tree
house?
Audrey's rebuilding it.
Oh is that something you know
how to do?
Yeah.
She's highly skilled.
Can I go up there?
It's too dangerous.
It'll be safe after
I finish it. I promise.
Well, better, late than never.
We gave up trying to get Otto to
fix
that tree house a long time ago.
There was never time.
We're driving down to the
Cape in Florida Monday
there will be a launch.
It's gonna be a long drive.
16 hours.
Wow.
Will you stay at a hotel?
No lift off is at dawn.
We leave the morning
before, we watch the launch
then we drive home.
Sunny enjoys
the roar of the first stage
separation.
I really do.
There is blood in the steaks,
Johan.
John.
If there is blood.
There's still bacteria.
Do you know we're
nothing without bacteria.
Otto it's all over our skin
Honey.
Everyone give the steaks to me.
Honey, please.
I'm going to finish
cooking them correctly.
Give it to me
All of them, all of them.
Give to me.
I'm leaving.
Go let him show you
how to make the meat.
Where's the thermometer?
It'll make him happy.
Doubtful.
I have the thermometer.
Okay. If you don't go,
we're all gonna be miserable.
So take one for the team.
Johan you never put it near
the bone.
Bone is much more conductive
than tissue.
It gives a false reading.
There's no bone in these.
Someday there will be bone.
You'll know what to do.
Audrey why don't you
go to the Cape with Otto
the blast is incredible.
Yeah he can teach you all
about aeronautics on the way
down.
You never know.
You might find it interesting.
And if not you could pretend.
The steaks are ready?
I think they're done.
They are not.
They're fucking hockey pucks.
All right, I need to
check on the pudding.
Can I help you?
And watery diarrhea.
Dump the scheisse.
Enjoy.
I want to go inside now.
(soft music)
Danke.
Remote?
(indistinct chatter)
Want to get something to eat?
Something with a lot of
bacteria.
You buying?
Wow.
How do you like my father?
I think Otto's great.
Has he taken you fishing yet?
No. I didn't know he fished.
Well he doesn't, but
when he takes you fishing
he'll set you up at the end of
the pier
and then he'll sit down
and count the number of casts
you make.
And when you've hit 26,
it'll be time for you to go.
Whether or not you caught a
fish.
Why 26?
He did a time and motion study
and determined that if
you don't catch a fish
after 26 casts that you never
will.
Once I figured out the system
then I'd wait longer and
longer in between each cast
because I wanted it to
last.
At least he you took you
fishing.
It's nice.
[Narrator] During the summer
months
when ticks are most active.
But first thing you can do is
wear light colored clothes.
If you're gonna come across a
tick
you're gonna wind up being able
to see
that tick crawling on your pants
or crawling on your shirt.
Even better than that would be
if you're wearing socks
you can tuck those pants into
your socks.
Ooh.
No, you're right.
Cause it'd be like incest.
Stop talking.
We could go to one of
those states where it's legal
or at least they look the other
way.
Just stop saying words.
You're not gonna drive, right?
No.
Good.
Good times.
Yeah.
[Otto] Johan.
Oh shit.
Johan where did you take her?
He just took me to get some
food.
[Otto] You have been
drinking (indistinct).
Why is it that immigrants
have more respect
for the national holiday?
What are you talking about Otto?
You are having a
celebration and you left.
I actually really like the 4th
of July.
I just thought you and
Sunny needed a little space.
(crowd cheering)
We are not going to the Cape.
Otto
his name is John.
He prefers John. He's a nice
guy.
What's that mean?
Is that what a man wants
on his grave marker
he was a nice guy?
Better to say he was adequate.
It's not safe to drive with him.
John?
No in general. You must be
vigilant.
Also it's a holiday.
People drink.
They fire guns in the sky.
Otto I've been taking care
of myself for pretty long now.
Listen to me, the world is
dangerous.
I'm talking to you as if you are
my child.
I've forgotten.
How disagreeable that is.
(yodeling music)
[Voicemail] Hi it's Warren's
phone.
Please call me back.
I mean, I will call you back
when you leave a message here.
Thank you. Okay, bye.
Hey Warren, it's Audrey.
I really need my security
deposit back.
And if I could get it in cash,
that would be preferable.
Just call me when you can
or you can text me and we can
meet up.
I hope you're well.
[Narrator] If you have ever
thought
about moving to Vermont
Governor Phil Scott
just signed a law that may make
it
a little more enticing
workers who move to Vermont
and make it their home will be
eligible
for up to $10,000 in moving
expenses and other costs.
State officials hope that the
money
and Vermont's high
quality of life will lure
out of state workers to
trade their office work.
(power drill humming)
You coming up?
Yeah.
Looks like there's much more
work to do.
No, I'm actually almost
finished.
No this section, for example
requires more support here.
It will stabilize it.
Otto I don't have any more
lumber.
You can get more.
If I did that all the way
around.
That's another like day, two
days of work.
Oh three, I think.
And you have pride in your
labor.
All right.
(upbeat music)
Lithium is present only under
the salt plains of Bolivia
some day it will run out.
Which is why another
battery material is needed.
Manufacturers are not
willing to knowledge this.
What the fuck?
(opera music)
(wind howling)
(crickets chirping)
Hey Audrey.
Hi
So I brought the money.
My deposit, thank you.
Yeah, it's in cash like you
asked.
I needed this.
Where do you live now?
Just
you know, around.
I'm fine.
I'm on my way out of town
actually going to be leaving soon.
I'm just ready.
You ever feel like that?
Where you're just ready
to see something else.
I mean
volcanoes
But I live here.
It's my home.
But you could live anywhere.
Your home could be anywhere.
Not really.
It's where you live,
where your family lives.
Me and my mom live here.
Yeah I get it.
I would rather that you didn't
leave.
Thank you, Warren.
What do you have there?
I brought you some tomatoes,
from my tomato garden.
Thanks.
Here you go.
(soft music)
I did this whole thing for Otto.
I figured that.
I'm sorry I misled you.
Okay.
You'll be leaving soon?
I hate rockets.
Really?
You can tell.
Oh yeah.
Audrey.
You found me.
Yeah.
Sunny, she told me you are
leaving.
Do I smell cumin?
You want some?
Yeah.
Good
Sit down.
I see that you have prior
experiences.
The wheels come off every now
and again.
And I do this for a bit
and then I get things back on
track.
So you will finish the
tree house before you go?
This is for you.
Mutti give it to me. It
was to help me sleep.
Shouldn't you give that
to like Gretchen or John?
They say this is music for
Nazis.
My parents were not Nazis.
(music box playing)
This helped you sleep?
Of course not.
Listen to it.
[Narrator] One of the awesome
things
about living here in Vermont
has been just the number
of friendships I've
been able to establish.
So today's gonna be a big day
for doing some work on the barn.
The term meteor in fact
refers to the streak of light
caused by a meteoroid as it
collides
with the upper regions
of the earth atmosphere.
Most of meteoroids are only the
size
of a grain of sand.
Is that right?
Space dust.
Measure twice cut once.
(saw humming)
We're here.
Hey.
We're finishing up the tree
house for my grandchildren.
I told you they can't go up
there.
Audrey is making it safe.
It's more than sufficient
to meet the demands
of the County Building Code.
Tree houses don't have
building codes.
If there was, it would
pass there's no doubt.
(power drill humming)
Sorry can you stop that.
When you were a child, you
often asked me to fix it.
Yes, I did.
Look at it now you can use it.
Fuck.
I cannot understand
when she was a child.
She was the stable one, a fixed
particle.
Maybe you should go talk to her.
Is that appropriate.
Yeah, it's appropriate.
What do I say?
Just go in there and listen to
her
and try not to teach her
anything.
Hey Audrey?
Fuuuuck! Fuck! Fuck!
Are you okay?
Goddammit you little fucker.
Hey what did you just call him?
What the fuck?
What is the matter with you?
Oh my God.
Oh shit.
My finger I don't know where it
is.
Right there get in
the house in the house?
Oh God.
(Audrey groaning in pain)
I'll get the first aid kit.
We need the big one.
(Audrey groaning in pain)
I think it's time for me to go.
Yeah
Scheisse
Where are you going now?
I have some friends in Vermont
who are
her barn is needing some repair.
How will you do that?
You're missing a finger.
Do you have insurance?
I will pay.
This is an emergency room Otto.
They fix you whether you can pay
or not.
That's how it works.
What do we got here?
We got a finger.
You sure do.
Let's see what we can do with
it.
Good.
It's gonna be a really long
time Otto.
I think you should probably go
home.
I will wait.
It's okay if you come in.
You're her dad, right?
Just go home.
(soft music)
(Audrey sobbing)
(music box playing)
(soft music)
Hey mom.
Hi Audrey.
Come in.
[Narrator] Who has a shot at a
million
the rest can still win the
overall
but they would get on the grid,
the riders in the game, 22
but there's only one with a
shot at a million dollars.
And that's Eli Tommack
he has to win this race
right here to continue
that quest to a million.
Can he do it again he did it
last year.
How about the Toyota
Whole shot it's the rider
whose been out for 16 months.
(indistinct) and then just
like the 64(indistinct).
How are the kids?
I don't have kids.
Hey Dad
Why did you and mom get married?
She had air conditioning.
Makes sense.
Can I tell you something
about me dad?
I move around a lot.
In the past two years, I've
lived in four different places.
I've had like six, seven
different jobs.
I get someplace and it's great.
Things are working out and then
they just
stop working out.
I think once people get to
know everything about me
I just got to keep moving.
Why do I do that?
I don't know.
(upbeat music)
I was driving to the library
to return "A Theories on Dark
Matter."
And I saw your minivan.
It's a distinctive car.
Yes it is.
May I see it.
Yeah.
Is there nerve damage?
I mean I can't feel a thing.
Careful around hot objects.
It will burn before you're aware
of it.
I know Otto.
You didn't go to Vermont.
No.
No, I was already to go and
packed up.
I came in here to get some
propane and I saw they're hiring.
So I thought I'd give the old
staying put, a try.
See what that was like.
And what is it like?
So far so good.
I like it here.
Do you have friends?
I'm working on it
To have friends is crucial
to regulating blood pressure.
So?
Yeah.
(opera music)
(soft music)
(soft ambient music)