- This is the story
of America's past
that never made it
into textbooks.
- When most people
were in school,
you began American history
at Jamestown and Plymouth Rock.
- Jamestown narrative is viewed
very much in isolation,
that this was
the first encounter
between Europeans and Indians.
- If you really wanted to look
at the Founding Fathers,
you'd look a lot earlier,
and you'd look south.
- It starts nearly a half century
before the Pilgrims landed.
- The children who stepped ashore
probably had their own
grandchildren by the time
Jamestown was founded.
- Pedro Menéndez and the people
who went with him,
they are really the fathers
of the United States,
the true fathers
of the United States.
They are.
They arrived before,
before Mayflower, Jamestown.
- It's a story that has
taken archaeologists,
marine scientists and historians
several centuries to uncover.
- I've always thought
it was like having
a 2,000-piece jigsaw puzzle,
but you don't know
what the picture
is supposed to look like.
- This stuff has not seen
the light of day
for 250...
to 275 years.
- And I could feel the lip to it
and put my hands inside,
and then I realized what it was.
- This is one of the, maybe,
one of the most
important documents
in the United States
history, no?
If you read it, you go,
"It's a film.
You could make
a film out of it."
- What these discoveries reveal
is a very different America.
- It's multicultural
from day one.
- You had Africans.
You had a few Italians,
Germans, Irish priests.
- It really was America's
first melting pot.
- How did this history
become lost,
and how does it change
our thinking about race
and immigration in this country
to know what really happened?
- If you don't know your past,
you can't understand who you are
and where are you going.
- This is the rest of the story
of America's birth.
- It is just as much a part
of American history
as Washington crossing the
Delaware or Paul Revere's ride.
- If we took that as a beginning,
I think we would have
a very different picture
of the United States.
- What makes you American.
- This is American history,
revised.
♪♪
They have been walking,
night and day,
struggling against
fierce winds and rain
that had already proven deadly.
- It's a massive storm.
No matter how hard they tried
to claw their way out,
they kept on being pushed back.
- 500 of them, making their
way through swamps
and unfamiliar terrain,
passing creatures
they've never seen before.
- They're marching through, in
some cases up to their waists,
in some cases higher,
up to their chest,
through flooded swamp land.
- During the course of the march,
about 100 of his troops
dropped out.
They didn't make it.
- And, waiting for them
at the end of it all,
a battle they might not survive.
- And the stage is set for this
really very rapid
and very bloody end game.
- This wasn't the journey
they had signed on for.
It had started as a dream
to settle a new territory,
more than 4,000 miles
across the ocean,
a venture that first began
in this modern-day
seaport town of Avilés
in Northern Spain.
450 years ago,
Avilés was an important
maritime center,
and ship-building
was its main industry.
Hundreds of young men
grew up learning
how to navigate
along these shores.
One of them was Pedro Menéndez,
who became, over time,
one of the king's
most trusted men.
- The royal family trusted him
for their most
important missions.
He spoke English,
which was not very common
for a Spaniard at the time.
He was a Renaissance man.
He was a great seaman.
- He understood the winds,
the waves and the weather
better than almost
anyone at the time.
- Little was known about
Menéndez or his influence
on American history
until Dr. Eugene Lyon
began combing through Spanish
archives in the 1960s.
- El dicho,
Pedro Menéndez de Avilés.
- Lyon spent 6 years in Spain,
microfilming more than
a million pages of material,
and another decade translating
and piecing these
accounts together.
- Any new document
is like finding a treasure.
It's the only real
treasure there is.
- What emerged is a story
that radically changes
our understanding
of this country's roots.
The year was 1565,
and the entire East Coast
of what is now the United States
was Spanish territory
known as La Florida.
It stretched north
to Nova Scotia,
and all the way west
to the Mississippi,
and along the gulf coast
of Mexico to Texas.
This had been Spanish territory
ever since Juan Ponce de León
had claimed it in 1513.
King Phillip Il
wanted to establish
a strategic foothold here
to prevent other countries from
encroaching on Spanish land,
and he wanted to deter attacks
on his Spanish treasure fleets.
- One main reason was to protect
the homebound Spanish fleets
bearing the riches
of the mines of Mexico
and the great silver
mountain in Peru.
- Pedro Menéndez had once
been a Captain General
of those treasure ships.
- These were dangerous waters
and ships often struck sandbars,
and the survivors
were taken captive.
Some died in captivity,
some were made slaves.
- For several years, Menéndez
has been seeking permission
to go to La Florida
to search for survivors
of one of those lost ships.
- His son had been a sea captain
who had sailed one or two years
earlier from Havana
into a hurricane,
and he was lost
on the Florida coast.
- The Crown had repeatedly
refused those requests,
but Menéndez was not
easily discouraged.
- He was good at making decisions
and taking quick action.
- Menéndez
was also an entrepreneur,
and he saw the potential
of developing the New World.
Raising his own capital,
he proposed an
ambitious undertaking,
one that was different
from the conquistadors
who had gone before.
Menéndez proposed to
transplant thousands of people,
along with the infrastructure
of an entire town,
to La Florida.
He would create a colony
that would be self-sustaining
and produce its own
goods for export,
a venture that stood
to add considerable wealth
to Spain's coffers.
But there was another reason
the king wanted
to start settling
this new territory,
and it went back more
than half a century
to Columbus' first voyage.
- For the Spaniards at this time,
religion is the driving force.
Christ can't come back until
the whole world is evangelized.
- History books have focused
on other motivations,
the drive to explore
the New World,
the desire to
plunder its riches,
but Columbus was also
a fervent Christian
who believed his explorations
could play a role
in fulfilling
Biblical prophecies.
- So, those prophecies are saying
that, "Christ is coming back.
We have to evangelize the world,
and the monarchs of Spain
will in fact be
at the forefront
of the Apocalypse
when they re-take Jerusalem."
- Columbus was convinced
that this would be the ultimate
legacy of the Spanish Crown.
For the next 73 years,
Spanish conquistadors
would continue to explore
the East Coast of North America
on behalf of
the Spanish monarchy.
Not all of them shared
this spiritual quest,
but Pedro Menéndez did.
- When he spoke to the king
at court, he said,
"Such grief seizes me
when I behold
those large communities
of native peoples in Florida,
who are sunk in the thickest
shades of infidelity
that I would give
anything to be able
to take Christianity to them
and redeem their
lives and souls."
- That resonated profoundly
with King Phillip,
who was such a devout Catholic
that he'd commissioned
a basilica
to be built inside
his own palace.
It was specially designed
so that his bedroom
overlooked the altar,
allowing the king
to hear mass recited daily,
even years later,
as he lay on his deathbed.
- He was certainly devout,
almost a frenetic supporter
of the Catholic Church
everywhere.
- But there was little chance
that religious missions
would succeed in La Florida.
So far, no one in Europe
had been able to survive
long-term in this
inhospitable land.
♪♪
- Florida was a challenge.
There had already been 10 to 12
Crown-sanctioned
expeditions into Florida
to establish permanence,
from Ponce de León forward,
and no one had been
able to do this.
- The rest had failed.
They finally ran out
of supplies and died,
or were killed by the Indians,
or they had to leave.
- When the last failed leader
sailed home to Spain,
Tristán de Luna y Arellano,
he said to Menéndez,
"Florida is not
worth another try.
There is nothing there.
The land is not arable.
The harbors are too
barred with sandbars.
It's a waste of men
and resources
to go back to that place.
It was just too difficult
living there,
scratching out a living."
- The king offered
several inducements.
Menéndez could claim
53,000 acres as his own.
He would be made Governor,
and Adelantado.
- Which literally means,
"he who goes before others,"
and was a title of nobility,
and that was granted
to him in perpetuity,
that he could pass on, then,
to his heirs, forever.
- And the Crown offered
other incentives
for anyone else
willing to go along.
- Menéndez and all those
associated
with the Florida venture
were exempt from taxes
and a series of taxes for years,
ten years in some instances.
- They held out the promise that
they would have their own land,
and that was hard
for an ordinary person,
sometimes, to acquire in Spain,
so this possibility would
have lured a lot of people.
- The expedition would
require eight ships,
carrying more than 1,500 people,
and enough provisions
to sustain the colonists
until they could produce
their own food and supplies.
- You have tailors,
hat makers, shoe makers,
surgeons and barbers.
One of the last
individuals on the list
is a master beer brewer.
- There would be soldiers on
board to protect the settlement,
26 families, 7 priests,
and a virtual melting
pot of immigrants.
- There were Spaniards,
Portuguese, English, French,
we see Flemish,
Germans and Africans.
- There are some Black
translators
that have been rescued
as shipwreck victims
from among the Indian villages,
and so it's multicultural
from day one.
- Once he'd gotten this
new settlement started,
Menéndez hoped to finally be
able to search for his son.
- He must have loved
his son, Juan,
very much to have undertaken
this great effort
as a means of finding Juan.
- But just before the journey
began, there was troubling news.
- The French had
established a fort
smack in the middle
of Spanish-claimed Florida.
This was an insult to the king,
and he became quite angry
at this trespass
because he had in place a treaty
which recognized Spain's right
to the whole Atlantic coast.
- Suddenly, overnight,
the venture turned
into a combat mission.
- "You are to drive them out by
whatever means you see fit."
- Fortified with hundreds
more soldiers,
Menéndez was now in a race
to beat the French Captain,
Jean Ribault, to Florida.
Ribault was headed there
with supply ships
to fortify Fort Caroline,
the small settlement
that France had just set up
near the mouth of the river
known today as the St. Johns.
It's a matter of debate
among historians
how accurate the depictions
of that time are,
but what isn't in question
are the accounts
of how evenly matched
these two rivals were.
Jean Ribault was
a formidable adversary.
- Sounds a lot like Menéndez,
great danger to the Spaniards.
- French settlers were running
out of food
and adequate supplies.
Fort Caroline was
barely holding on.
If Ribault did not reach there
with reinforcements,
the fort could be easily taken.
- But, of course, this venture
does not unfold the way
that Menéndez
expects it to unfold.
- His enterprise of Florida
really went wrong
from the get-go, in many ways.
- Hurricanes struck
as soon as the Spanish ships
got out to sea.
- At about a quarter of the way
across the Atlantic,
all but five of those ships
were either sunk at sea
or driven back to port.
Only five ships
would reach Florida.
- One of his main supply ships,
La Victoria,
is wrecked on Guadalupe
and all the supplies are lost,
and the whole crew
is lost to drowning.
- Only about half of the
original 1,500 passengers
made it to La Florida.
The ships headed directly
to Fort Caroline,
but they were too late.
Jean Ribault had already
beaten them there.
- So, as Ribault is unloading
his three smallest ships
on the River of May,
the St. John's River,
the Spanish show up.
They identify themselves.
They fire shots.
The four French ships
that are offshore
cut their anchor
lines to escape.
- Menéndez could not follow
because his ships were laden
with supplies and men.
- Menéndez retreated to an inlet,
about 40 miles south
of Fort Caroline,
hoping it would
provide safe harbor,
but Menéndez couldn't
get his main supply ships
past the shoal.
They unloaded as much as
they could into smaller boats
and went ashore.
- And the first thing
he did ashore was,
essentially,
went about the business
of legally establishing the
settlement of St. Augustine.
- Much of our knowledge
of what happened next comes
from a document
that is housed here,
in the Archives of the Indies,
in Sevilla, Spain.
♪♪
- The fact that it
survives is amazing.
You know, the fact
that it's even here.
- It is the original diary
of one of the priests
who accompanied Pedro Menéndez
on the voyage.
For several centuries,
American historians
knew nothing of its contents,
which is one of several reasons
why the story has gone untold.
It's only been in the past
few decades
that a small number
of scholars have learned
how to read this archaic script.
Dr. Michael Francis, from
The University of South Florida
at St. Petersburg,
is one of them.
- I, Francisco López de Mendoza
Grajales, chaplain,
give my word
that everything said
in this account is true.
Fantastic.
- In vivid detail, Father López
described the great pageantry
that marked the landing.
- There were trumpet salutes,
and the firing of cannon
and flags waving everywhere.
Father López was there
to greet each one.
- Menéndez christened the new
settlement San Augustine,
or St. Augustine.
It was September 8, 1565.
- Traditionally, the Spanish
representative of the king
would go to the flag,
plant the flag in the ground,
and proclaim the land
in the name of the king.
He, however, went over
to Father López
and knelt down
and kissed the cross.
So he proclaimed the land
in nombre de Deus,
in the name of God,
before the name of his king.
A little bit risky, maybe.
- As Menéndez and those
after him came up,
those arrivals knelt
and kissed the cross,
and López observed
the Natives imitated
all they saw done.
Now there is a picture for you.
- Father López then conducted
a mass of thanksgiving...
and Menéndez ordered that
a meal be prepared for everyone,
including the Natives.
- They were fed with what was
on board Menéndez's ship,
so the Indians would have
had European food...
Garbanzos, garlic,
olive oil, vinegar,
maybe some sort of salted meat
that they would have
brought with them.
- This was 55 years
before the Pilgrims
even arrived in Plymouth.
Dr. Michael Gannon,
one of the country's leading
scholars of Florida history,
drew fire a few years ago,
when he called this meal,
"the true first Thanksgiving."
- There was a guy who called me
from WBZ, in Boston,
he said, "While I'm talking,
do you realize
that there's
an emergency meeting
of select men at Plymouth
to contend with
this new information
that there were
Spaniards in Florida
before there were Englishmen
in Massachusetts?"
And then he said,
"Well, you know
how you've become known
up here, in New England?"
And I said, "No."
He said, "The Grinch
who stole Thanksgiving."
- But while the Spanish
were celebrating
their new settlement,
Jean Ribault was
planning his next move.
- He says, "We need to stage
a preemptive strike.
We need to hit the Spanish
now, as hard as we can,
before they entrench
themselves."
- Ribault left a small number
of men to guard Fort Caroline,
then set out with
the others on four ships,
looking for the Spanish camp.
- They had it in mind to kill
everybody at St. Augustine.
"Cursed Spaniards,
we will hang them
from the halyards
of their own ships.
The French show up off
the bar at St. Augustine
and, all of a sudden, this huge
storm bears down on them.
- Ribault's ships couldn't
make it over the sandbar
at St. Augustine,
and his surprise attack failed.
He decided, instead, to chase
after those large supply ships
which Menéndez had just
sent south to safety.
But the Spanish vessels
managed to elude the French.
Ribault's ships were
ravaged by the storm.
- And, of course,
they were shipwrecked.
All of those Frenchmen,
from Daytona Beach to a point
just north of Cape Canaveral.
- They probably lost
most of their weapons,
most of their food.
They don't really know what to
do expect to try to march back
and try to get back
to Fort Caroline.
Now, unbeknownst to them,
Menéndez also makes a bold move.
- Menéndez figured that,
"The weather is nasty.
I bet you that Ribault
basically stripped the garrison
at Fort Caroline
to come down here,
so that fort is probably
under-manned right now.
This is my chance. I need to go.
I need to take this fort now."
- Some historians say
it was a hurricane,
others believe
it was a nor'easter.
Either one could
have proven lethal.
- Most of the accounts allege
that few of the Spaniards
wanted to go.
Obviously, there was a terrible
storm, the rain is pelting down
and they don't think
they can make it,
and they don't quite know
how far it is,
and they think
that they'll perish.
And Menéndez says,
"We're going."
- This was his best
time to attack,
and that was typical Menéndez.
- It was September 18th.
They had only been in this
new land for 10 days.
- So he marched, and he had
squads of axemen
who were in the vanguard,
and they would cut where it
was necessary to get through
because it wasn't
very easy going.
- It must have been horrible,
in full armor,
carrying your weapons, to march
through Florida wilderness
during a hurricane took
a lot of determination.
- So when he came up on the fort,
he had about 400 men.
They were cold,
no doubt, hungry, ornery.
- It took them about
two days to get there,
walking throughout the night.
Father López wrote,
"They arrived within a quarter
of a league of the enemy's fort,
where they remained all night,
up to their waists in water."
- At the break of dawn,
they essentially charged
the gates and broke in,
and the French
were mostly asleep.
- The sound of the rain
somehow allowed the Spanish
to get right up to the fort.
It masked the sound
of approaching soldiers.
- They really caught the fort
completely by surprise.
The French never dreamed
that they would face
an enemy during this storm.
They figured everyone
would be battered down
just like they were.
- The French were all asleep,
some in their night clothes,
some of them were
completely naked,
and the slaughter began.
- Only a few escaped
into the woods.
Menéndez and his men
collected the spoils of war...
Food, weapons,
and a chest with the French
king's orders for the fort,
which violated Spain's
claim to La Florida.
They also found Lutheran texts,
which the Spanish Catholics
considered heresy.
- The French Huguenots were
a real threat to Catholicism.
The Huguenots,
or the Protestant group,
was obtaining a lot of power.
- It makes, in that worldview,
total sense to eliminate someone
who is not only a political
and economic challenge,
but also a religious challenge
to your very reason of being,
as a Catholic.
- "The greatest triumph,"
Father López wrote,
"will be the Holy Gospel being
introduced into this country,
a thing necessary to prevent
the loss of many souls."
- We're dealing with people
from a different era.
This is what people thought.
This is what they believed.
This is what they hoped for,
that all things would be
made new in Christ,
and suffering would
come to an end,
and there would be
finally the peace
that had been prophesied
in the Scriptures.
- Menéndez provided a ship
so the women and children
that he spared
could leave safely.
He renamed the fort San Mateo,
or St. Matthew.
He left some of his soldiers
there to guard the fort,
and took the rest back
to St. Augustine.
A little more than a week later,
about half of the Frenchmen,
who had survived the shipwrecks
off the coast of Cape Canaveral,
were trying to make their way
back to Fort Caroline on foot.
Jean Ribault was
not one of them.
- But when they got
to Matanzas Inlet
they were unable to cross it,
and Native people in that region
saw that these Frenchmen
were stranded there,
and ran up to St. Augustine
to advise the Spaniards,
and Menéndez went
down with 50 men.
- Menéndez told the French that
their fort had been destroyed.
- The French, at this point,
would just be happy
to surrender unconditionally
and be given a ship
and sail back to France.
- Menéndez said,
"Tell your commander
that you can come over,
10 at a time, in my boat,
and I will deal with you
as good captain should."
And that's the only
promise he made to them.
- "Your fate will be what God
tells me in my good conscience."
- Menéndez had his men
bring the French
across the Matanzas River
by boat, 10 at a time.
When the Frenchmen disembarked
on the other side of the water,
the Spanish tied their
hands behind their backs,
and marched them to a point
where Menéndez had drawn
a line in the sand.
- Menéndez had situated
his men behind the sand dunes
with daggers and spears,
and when each group
of 10 was brought over,
Menéndez's men set
upon them and killed them.
And soon it was 20, 30, 40,
50, 60, the bodies piled up.
- Menéndez spared a few
of the French, mostly craftsmen,
who's skills could be put to use
building the new settlement.
- He says that the total
number of Lutherans
killed were 111 men,
and that there were 14 or 15
that were taken captive.
- Father López's account
ends at this point...
but another document
continues the story
even further.
- We kept these documents,
and here they are.
- Don Alvaro Armada
is the Count of Guemes
and a descendant
of Pedro Menéndez.
His family archive houses
over a million pages
of handwritten documents.
One of them is a full account
of the expedition,
written by
Gonzalo Solis de Merás,
who was Menéndez's
brother-in-law.
- This is one of the, maybe one
of the most important documents
in the United States
history, no?
- It describes the fateful day,
two weeks after the slaughter
of the first group
of French shipwreck survivors,
and Jean Ribault and about 200
of his remaining soldiers
met face-to-face
with Pedro Menéndez.
They met at the sand dunes
about 14 miles
south of Saint Augustine.
It was October 11, 1565.
- Menéndez then informs
Ribault, of course,
that he's already captured
Fort Caroline.
There's nowhere
for Ribault to go.
The fort has fallen and Ribault
tries to negotiate safe passage
back to France,
and then offers a...
- An amount of money, no?
- Yeah. He offers...
- An amount of money.
- Yeah. A lot.
- And Menéndez said "No."
- No.
- Jean Ribault then
recited a psalm.
- He begins to say a prayer,
and after he finishes...
So he's saying to them
that we are all of this earth
and to this earth
we shall return.
- He's saying goodbye.
- So that within 20 years
all of this will be a tale,
a story, a legend.
- If you read it, you go,
"It's a film."
You can make a film
out of it, no?
It's amazing.
- And then he looks at Menéndez,
and he says...
So he's telling the
adelantado, Menéndez,
"Do with us as you will."
Menéndez is quite open
about what happens.
Menéndez simply says, "I could
not risk keeping Ribault
and the principle
officers alive."
- When a war is a war
you kill everybody,
but he didn't kill
women or children.
So some of the residents
in Saint Augustine
felt that what he had done
was excessively cruel.
So, others saying that
what he had done
was the act of a great captain.
- It was a very calculated
choice.
He did not have the food that
would be required to feed them.
He did not have arms
sufficient to guard them.
These hoards of Frenchmen
could overwhelm his forces
at almost any time,
so he made
a calculated decision,
and this was it...
Either kill these people
or be killed by them.
- So as many as 350 men
were massacred,
and that's how we get the name
Matanzas Inlet, Matanzas River.
That's "massacre"
or "slaughter" in Spanish.
- Jean Ribault's last words,
that someday this
would all be legend,
proved to be ironic.
For centuries the true story
of America's beginnings
went untold.
American history textbooks
do not even give it a mention.
- Pedro Menéndez and the people
that went with him,
they are really the fathers
of the United States,
the true fathers
of the United States.
They are.
They are, because very simple.
They arrived before Mayflower,
Jamestown and all that.
The story shouldn't be invented.
It can't be invented
because here are the documents.
Here are the documents.
- The search for the missing
pieces of this story
continues today.
A team of divers from
the Lighthouse
Archaeological Maritime Program
are off the coast of Cape
Canaveral National Seashore.
They are looking for
those fateful shipwrecks
that not only cost Jean Ribault
and his men the conquest
of the new world,
but ultimately their lives.
- We have, for example,
a letter from Pedro Menéndez
to the king of Spain
reporting that he has
taken Fort Caroline
and that the French ships
have wrecked,
and he gives a very
rough estimate
of how many leagues away
from Saint Augustine they are,
so that kind of
puts us in the general area.
- They have honed in
on an area near shore
where small artifacts
believed to have belonged
to Ribault's men were found.
- The shipwreck survivors
who made it ashore
had some kind of campsite there
and there's a lot of artifacts.
There are coins dating 1550s,
and there's actually one
coin that is dated 1565.
That's the magic number.
- Ribault's ships were carrying
large quantities of iron,
cannons and ammunition.
The team uses a high-powered
metal detector
that penetrates deep water.
- There we go.
So now the line... There we go.
- There it is.
- You can't miss that.
There was definitely
something there.
- But it's not what
they're looking for.
- At night the coast,
all the coastline
south of us is just dark,
and it really feels just like it
must have felt 450 years ago.
You can imagine there were
bodies washing ashore.
There was flotsam and debris
from the shipwrecks all ashore.
There was probably
a horrible stench.
I mean, you can really start
to picture it in your mind.
All of the hopes of these people
who are really the first to come
over to seek the American dream,
and it all came down
to this storm,
this fateful storm that just
dashed their hopes to pieces.
- More than a year later,
a breakthrough
just south of the area
the team had been searching.
- Treasure hunters have
apparently found
the nearly 500-year-old
remains of La Trinite.
- News programs reported that a
private treasure hunting company
had unearthed
three bronze cannons
belonged to belong
to Ribault's fleet.
- There really is no doubt
to any of the archaeologists
who have really looked
at what has been found
that this is the Trinite
or certainly one
of Ribault's ships,
so it's a very exciting find.
So this is the cannon
in question,
and here's the H with the crown
above it for King Henry Il.
The biggest smoking gun that has
been found was a stone pillar.
- It's a stone column
like the one
depicted in this
16th century etching.
The columns were used
to mark territory
when the French arrived
in the new world.
- We know a pillar very much
like this one was established
in the area of the River of May,
where Fort Caroline is,
so present day Jacksonville,
and we know that Ribault
loaded six more
of these stone pillars
on to his fleet.
And it's amazing.
It's striking image of the one
that's in the de Bry engraving.
- France has laid claim
to the shipwreck
and is in talks
with archaeologists,
including Chuck Meide's team,
to assist with the excavation.
- Until someone invents
a time machine,
the best way to immerse
ourselves in that life,
that time period,
that experience
on a particular vessel
is through maritime archeology.
- Ironically, these ships
have been sitting
at the bottom
of the ocean buried
under rocket ship debris
just a few miles from the place
where modern day explorers
are launched in to space.
- They were the space shuttles
of their time period.
I mean, these were the ships
that were launched
to explore the great unknown.
- Meide expects it to take
several years
to excavate the ships
and several more years
to have some answers.
What kind of preparations
did Ribault make for his attack?
Could he have out-gunned
the Spanish
if it hadn't been for the storm?
♪♪
Back on land in Saint Augustine,
Dr. Kathleen Deagan
and a team of archaeologists
from the University of Florida
have unearthed a major new find
about what happened
to those first settlers
who came over
with Pedro Menéndez.
- I've always thought
it was like
having a 2,000-piece
jigsaw puzzle,
but you don't know
that the picture
is supposed to look like.
- Deagan has already uncovered
some of the most pivotal
archaeological sites
in this country's early history.
- It's really only
through archeology
that we know
what regular people did.
I've always thought
of archeology
as the most democratic
form of history
because it isn't
just what the people
who knew how to write say,
and it isn't just what
a more elite class
of people left behind.
- After working at the site
for several years,
Deagan and her team found a well
that was typical of European
rather than Native American
construction.
Its contents led them to believe
that this was the site
of the first settlement
when Menéndez first came ashore.
- At first
we couldn't believe it.
We said, "No. This couldn't have
been here all this time,"
and here we've been
working for over 30 years
on and off at this site.
- They found the site while
digging at the Fountain of Youth
Archaeological Park
just north of downtown.
- It was enough mass to convince
us even after 30 years
that it really was
the Menéndez settlement.
- They found hundreds
of artifacts,
including Spanish beads,
musket balls, belt loops,
fragments of medicine
vials and uniform buttons.
- It really wasn't until
some of the kind
of smoking-gun artifacts
and archaeological
deposits showed up
that you would really
let yourself say,
"This is it."
Its real significance
is that it's the first place
in the United States
that Europeans came and stayed.
- And there's evidence of the
children who first came here,
as well.
- We found a little figa amulet,
which is a little clenched fist
with the thumb
between the fingers,
and Spanish women
had many of these
hanging around babies necks
to protect them
against evil eye,
and we just couldn't
help imagining
that this was associated
with the first European child
born in what's now
the United States,
Martinico de Arguelles.
- And we have references
to children being born
in Saint Augustine obviously
soon after people arrive.
- Dr. Susan Parker scours
parish records
now housed in Saint Augustine
to reconstruct the lives
of ordinary people.
- It's just whatever you can find
to try to piece them together
and give a voice
and a face to many people
that wouldn't have a voice
and a face otherwise.
- Women and children are often
missing from official accounts,
but Parker has managed
to breathe life in
to these first families
through their letters
back to Spain and vital records.
- I think we need to remember
that it's 42 years
between when Saint Augustine
was founded
and when Jamestown is founded.
If we look at that
in a different way,
that's almost two generations.
In other words, the children
who stepped to shore,
however many children there
were, with Pedro Menéndez
probably had their own
grandchildren by the time
Jamestown was founded.
- Another discovery, the
important role native women
played in providing food
for the new colony.
- We have found
the remains of foods
that they must have
learned about the foods
and how to fix them from
the native people in the area,
and this, I think,
is a real indication
that Native American women,
even though they were invisible
in much of the document record,
really shaped the actual
life experiences
of everyone in these colonies.
- At first, the relationship
between the natives
and Spanish settlers
was a good one.
It's said the Timucuan
Indian chief named Soloy
gave Pedro Menéndez
his own council house,
big enough to hold
hundreds of people.
- In this GIS map
just happens to show
where all the post molds
and big pits are.
- It's believed that an
archaeologist may have
discovered
this round house in the 1950s,
but his findings
were never published.
All of those records recently
turned up in a garage
in California
nearly 70 years later.
Deagan and her team plan
to search for that round house,
but in the meantime,
they've made another discovery.
Deagan believes they may
have found the walls
of this settlement's first fort.
- In 1565, the ground surface
would have been somewhere
in this area,
and this is where, for example,
if somebody was standing
and dug this hole for a wall,
their feet would have been.
- Menéndez ordered a fort
to be built just before he left
to start up other
fortified settlements
along the east coast.
He was gone
more than four months,
but by winter, rations and
supplies were becoming scarce.
- They complained of starvation
and Indian attacks,
and most of the people
who came here with Menéndez
came because they assumed
they would have a better life.
They would have livestock.
They might find gold and riches.
They would have
their own piece of land,
but none of that ever happened.
- A group of discontented
soldiers
began plotting a mutiny.
- So within six months
of arriving,
most of the soldiers decided
that they had enough,
and said "We're just going
to capture a boat.
We're going to get the supplies.
We're going to get out of here."
- At midnight, rebels marched
with torches and guns,
looting Saint Augustine's
store room
and loading weapons on board
a ship headed for Spain.
- They tied up the quartermaster
and took off with the weaponry
and some of the supplies
on a ship,
but the quartermaster was able
to get himself free
with the help of a few
other loyal soldiers,
and he shot at the mutineers.
He did quell the mutiny.
- The leader of the uprising was
immediately hanged for treason.
Pedro Menéndez returned
two weeks later with food
and additional troops.
He pardoned those willing
to swear allegiance to him.
Those who didn't could take
their chances on their own
without a ship or provisions.
- He gave them a choice.
They chose, for the most part,
to go back to Menéndez.
- But it wasn't just the soldiers
who were unhappy.
Evidence of burnt structures
confirms another dark truth...
That the goodwill with the
natives lasted less than a year.
- The Timucua, after nine months,
attacked and burnt part
of the settlement,
and that's when
it was abandoned.
- The settlers had overstayed
their welcome.
♪♪
The settlers moved across
the river to a small piece
of land now known
as Anastasia Island.
The structure that used
to be Fort Caroline
remained to the north
on the mainland
with just a small number
of soldiers guarding it.
Three years later,
a Frenchman by the name
of Dominique de Gourgue
brought his own band of men back
to Florida to exact revenge.
- He claims, "I arrived in
Fort Caroline, what is our fort,
that the Spanish had renamed
Fort San Mateo,
and I surprised them,
and I killed all 200 soldiers,
hanged them at the fort,
and burned the fort
to the ground
and stole all of their
artillery,
and vengeance is ours."
- De Gourgue claimed to have
used a searing iron
to burn a message for the
Spanish in to one of the tables.
- He said, "I do not do this
as unto Spaniards,
but as unto traitors
and robbers and murderers."
But, of course, there is
no burned table at the fort.
In fact, there are not
200 soldiers at the fort.
There were 100 soldiers
stationed at the fort
when he arrived,
and when they heard
the cannon fire
from the mouth of
the Saint John's river,
every single one of those
soldiers packed their supplies
and they left,
and they all made it
to Saint Augustine.
- The fort was never rebuilt.
Very little is known about life
in Saint Augustine
during the years the settlers
lived on Anastasia Island.
No one has ever found
remains of the settlement
which may be buried
underwater now.
Around 1572, they returned
to the other side of the river
and took up residence where
the city of Saint Augustine's
historical district
is located today.
As for Pedro Menéndez, he had
been traveling up and down
the East Coast
during most of this time
establishing a second colony
in South Carolina
and 13 more forts,
but by 1574,
only the two settlements,
Santa Elena
and Saint Augustine remained.
In all that time,
Menéndez never found his son.
He returned to Spain and was
preparing to command
another fleet for the king,
but exactly
nine years to the day
after he marched his troops
through a deadly storm
and captured Fort Caroline,
Pedro Menéndez died at home
in Spain of typhus.
He was 55.
- At the end, he's a romantic.
He's not a person who's looking
for the jewels or the...
He doesn't care about that.
When he died he was ruined.
No money.
He spent all his money
on his adventures.
He's not a materialist.
He's an...
He's an idealist.
He catches my heart.
- Over the next decade,
Saint Augustine
began to transform
in to the city
that Menéndez had envisioned.
Residents built a town
square patterned
after the plazas in Spain.
- The Plaza, I call it the heart
and soul of Saint Augustine.
Just about everything important
would take place there.
The religious festivals
would take place in the plaza.
Any military parades
or gatherings
would take place in the plaza.
- The plaza also housed
the marketplace.
- And because the market
was there,
we have the first known
regulation of weights
and measures,
so I kind of think of it
as the first consumer
protection laws in the nation.
- We found street deposits
that date back to the late 1500s
or early 1600s.
- Carl Halbirt has overseen Saint
Augustine's archeology program
for more than 25 years.
It's one of the few cities
in the country
that requires an archaeological
dig be conducted
before any new
construction can begin.
- Aviles Street is the
oldest documented
European street
in the United States,
and Philadelphia said,
"Oh, we have the oldest street."
I said, "Philly can
eat my dust."
Clearly we beat them
by 100 years.
- Across from the plaza
on Aviles Street
stood the centerpiece
of it all...
The first parish church
in the United States.
- It was the first building
that one saw
as one entered the inlet
in to the harbor.
- Picture yourself.
You're on a ship.
It takes a month, two months,
to come across the ocean,
terrible, deplorable conditions,
food, sanitation,
fright from storms, pirates,
and you come to Saint Augustine,
and what do they see?
- They would see the church
and the cross
and know that their Christian
home was just ahead of them.
Religion really was an integral
part of their very being,
and you can't exaggerate the
place it took in their lives.
- The church also played a role
in the blending of cultures.
Spanish soldiers began
to marry native women.
- The main thing that had
to happen first
was that you be a Catholic.
Either you convert or you
already were a Catholic,
and so these men, you know,
married women who converted,
who became Catholics.
- 20 to 25 percent
of the marriages
recorded were between a Spaniard
and a Native American.
- There was a lot of
intermarriage because they felt
that these people
were human beings
just like them.
There was such a huge difference
in the acceptance of that
in the Spanish colonies
rather than in
the British colonies.
- In fact, the artifacts
discovered throughout the city
reveal some startling truths
about this country's roots...
That the population
in America's first colony
was a mix of races and cultures
more closely reassembling
the diversity of
America's population today,
not the Anglo version that's
been depicted in textbooks.
- Why did Spanish America emerge
with such a different
kind of society
than English America?
I believe that it has
a great deal to do
with the integration of other
people in to Spanish society
and the exclusion
of other people
from Anglo-American society.
If you really looked at the way
people lived
in colonial English America,
you would only see
English things,
English traditions and
English objects and food.
Most of us look to that
as our history, our origins.
In the Spanish world,
it looked very different.
It was very multicultural
and very integrated.
- You had people
from the Canary Islands.
You had Africans.
You had some converted Jews.
You had a few Italians,
Germans, Irish priests.
- And it really was America's
first melting pot.
- So it's very strange, really,
that that whole part
of the history was eliminated.
- I think that the
United States is richer.
Its history is richer
because of the existence
of Saint Augustine,
of the establishment of it.
It demonstrated that African
and European people
could live together,
could benefit from
each other's skills.
That as a beginning
for the United States,
if we took that as a beginning,
I think we would have
a very different picture
of the United States.
- Two decades after
Saint Augustine was founded,
it had become a thriving
16th century town
complete with shops,
inns and taverns,
but all of this was
about to be destroyed.
Suddenly, one day in June 1586,
a foreboding sight
appeared on the horizon.
- People looked out
over the inlet
and saw 23 heavily
armed warships.
19 auxiliary vessels
which contained 2,000 armed men.
- This was the fleet of the
notorious English pirate,
Sir Francis Drake, known
the Spanish as a vicious foe.
- He had come to attack,
seize, destroy,
pillage the Spanish city
of Saint Augustine.
- To the Spanish,
Drake was known as a monster.
- You Spanish bastards!
- As a merciless man,
as a power-hungry man,
as an avaricious man,
as an inhuman individual,
really.
- The word Drake was... to the
Spanish, he was a terrorist.
He was an international
terrorist.
- The citizens of Saint Augustine
were out-manned and out-gunned.
- You're the enemy.
- How could they
possibly survive?
- You're either with us
or against us.
If you're against us,
you're going to die.
♪♪