♪♪
- Among the 1,500 men,
women, and children
seeking refuge inside the fort
were friars and priests,
several Natives, free blacks,
slaves,
and two infants
less than a week old.
♪♪
- It had to be terrible in there.
1,500 people
crammed inside the Castillo?
♪♪
I don't imagine
there are washing facilities.
There is a well for water.
And I'm not sure they think
they're gonna make it.
You didn't know how this
was going to turn out,
and you didn't even know
if you were going to come out
as a captive.
♪♪
- Governor José de Zúñiga
knew that his soldiers
were no match
for the English troops
in South Carolina.
Spain hadn't sent provisions
in months.
The men were getting just
two servings of bread a day.
Pulling everyone
into the Castillo
was the only way
to protect the townspeople
and keep his soldiers fed.
♪♪
- They actually rounded up the
animals as much as they could
and brought them close
to the fort...
Cattle and other things
like that.
The sharpshooters
up on the gun deck
would be able to protect
anybody from getting them.
♪♪
- In the meantime,
about 1,000 English troops
were descending on St. Augustine
by both land and sea.
♪♪
They were joined by roughly
as many Native allies,
Yamasees, Creeks,
and other smaller tribes
that had resisted the efforts
of the Spanish friars
to convert them.
Leading the onslaught
was Carolina Colony Governor
James Moore,
a man known to be
a ruthless slave dealer.
He had been eyeing St. Augustine
for a long time.
The Spanish stronghold
in La Florida
stood in the way
of English expansion.
- That's when the British
really began to make
an effective challenge
to Spanish rule.
You know, everybody wanted
to knock down the guy in charge
and take over those colonies
for themselves.
♪♪
- A century earlier, Spain had
made a serious strategical error
when it decided not to challenge
the establishment
of the English settlements
of Jamestown and Plymouth
in Spanish territory.
King Philip Ill lacked
the fervor that his father had
for maintaining an empire
in North America.
It was too costly.
- It's difficult to maintain
a series of forts
up and down the coast.
The priority
for the Spanish king
were these colonies
that really produced the wealth,
so Mexico, you know,
the Philippines, and Asia.
- What's more,
those early British colonies
seemed too small
and insignificant
to pose a threat
to Spain's sizable territory,
which stretched along the entire
East Coast of North America.
♪♪
Over the next century, however,
British colonies
had virtually dismembered
the northern portion
of Spanish-held La Florida,
and they were working their way
southward.
- And so, with the settlement
of Charleston,
that now made
an English settlement
that was close enough
to launch an attack
on St. Augustine from land.
♪♪
- The British saw
their opportunity in 1702.
Spain was in upheaval over
the death of King Charles Il,
who had no male heirs.
♪♪
As the War of the Spanish
Succession raged on in Europe,
English colonists
in South Carolina,
led by Governor Moore,
decided it was time to strike.
♪♪
Half of Moore's troops
set off by sea.
The rest marched south
through the backcountry,
preying first on
Spanish missions along the way.
- All of a sudden,
here comes a rampaging army
of Englishmen and Indian allies
to kill them and crush them,
and by the most violent means
possible.
- The storming of the missions
destroyed most buffers
St. Augustine had
along the coast,
but they had proven
to be easy prey.
The Natives living on these
missions had been unarmed.
- The friars had an issue
giving firearms to the Natives.
They're keeping firearms away
from the Natives
as a way of keeping them pure,
keeping them
from harming one another,
keeping them from
committing murder, essentially.
- The British, on the other hand,
issued guns
to any Natives
who would fight on their side.
- When you introduce the element
of guns, fire stick,
now you've given our people
the ability
to be able to hunt and provide
for their families easier.
- Of course they woo
a lot of the Indians away
to the English side.
They have more goods
to give them,
and the Indians can also see
that they're probably
the stronger side.
- They helped us.
These are our friends.
We can help them.
- As Moore's troops
triumphantly moved southward,
they continue
to solicit recruits.
♪♪
But a baptized Choctaw woman
overheard their plans.
She managed to get word
to St. Augustine's governor,
which is why the entire town
was now setting up camp
in the Castillo.
It was November 9, 1702.
By the time James Moore
and his men arrived,
the town looked deserted.
- Everybody's in the fort,
and the town's really free
for them to walk into.
- As the English got within range
of the fort,
the Spanish fired on them,
and the exchange began.
The Spanish artillery
was so out of practice
that they failed
to hit anything.
♪♪
- Spain's economy had collapsed
in the 1600s.
The Spanish soldiers are still
armed with matchlocks
that de Soto's soldiers
had used in the 1530s and '40s.
So, the Spanish, because
of their economic situation,
they're behind the times.
- In fact, the first casualties
in the Castillo
weren't caused by their enemy,
but, instead,
by overzealous Spanish soldiers
who loaded too much ammunition
into an old, cracked cannon.
It misfired...
♪♪
Killing the gunner
and two other men.
Five more were wounded.
♪♪
To keep the British from
taking cover close to the fort,
Zúñiga made a radical decision.
- The governor realizes
very quickly
that the houses
that are closest to the fort
will provide a place
for the English to shoot
at people up on the gun decks
or people that are trying
to leave the fort.
And so, he orders
about 30 houses burned
that are closest to the fort.
And the people who were
sequestered in that...
In the fort at that time
could see their houses burn.
It must have been a heartbreak.
♪♪
- The siege continued
for the next 52 days.
- And, of course, life goes on
inside the Castillo.
- We know that there are
two or three children born
during the siege.
- The first child
that's born there
is actually born
to a Native American woman
and a black slave,
a few days
after the siege starts.
- Now, we have found evidence
for the Siege of St. Augustine.
♪♪
- Archaeologist Carl Halbirt
made a surprising discovery
among the artifacts found
from the attack on the Castillo.
♪♪
It appears that, before
they abandoned their homes,
the citizens of St. Augustine
had made a cunning move.
They filled their wells
with sand.
- Normally, when you find wells,
you find trash deposits in them,
but here, in this well,
I mean, there was nothing...
No artifacts at all
in this clean sand.
So it led us to the conclusion
that this well may have been
intentionally filled
by the Spanish
so the English
could not have access
to a reliable water source
so close to the fort.
♪♪
- Moore's army proved weak,
and morale was low.
The Castillo
seemed to be impenetrable.
What made the fort so resistant
to artillery fire?
♪♪
This is what is expected
to happen
when a cannonball strikes
the wall of a stone fort.
- Brittle rock,
such as sandstone,
when you start to compress,
it shatters violently,
the fragments will fly off,
whereas coquina doesn't shatter
and fragments do not fly off.
- Dr. Ghatu Subhash has conducted
compression experiments
on the unique stone
used to build the Castillo,
known as "coquina."
His team at
the University of Florida's
Department
of Mechanical Engineering
want to understand
why the fort was able
to withstand artillery fire
while other structures
could not.
- The principle behind
why it withstood so elegantly
and majestically
is simply coquina was able
to absorb energy locally,
not sending the energy
to a global region,
which is fracture.
- The coquina walls are composed
of compressed-shell fragments,
bonded together
over thousands of years.
- It's all a tunneling effect,
so the ball comes...
Material ahead of it
is being crushed,
crushed, crushed, crushed.
That's all.
- The tiny shells crumble,
absorbing impact,
so bullets and cannonballs
sank into the Castillo,
rather than shattering
the walls.
Coquina is a material unique to
just a few regions of the world.
St. Augustine is one of them.
- They just got lucky.
They just got lucky.
- As the days wore on,
the English began to blame
General Moore
for their failure
to take the fort.
- The British start arguing
among themselves,
because the British invaders
had put a lot of their own money
into it,
but they've got their own money
riding on this venture.
- But conditions
inside the Castillo
were becoming dire, as well.
Food was running scarce.
- That's one of the things
you do with a siege is,
ultimately,
you can starve them out.
If you can't bombard them out,
you know,
you can just wait them out
on the outside,
because you have access to food
and they don't.
♪♪
- The governor sent out
messengers,
hoping one of them
would reach Cuba.
- He's hoping that he can send
someone in a small canoe
down the tidal creeks,
down past Fort Matanzas,
down beyond what is today
Palm Coast, Daytona,
that whole area.
Can you imagine taking a canoe
out into the Atlantic Ocean?
- Meanwhile, the Carolina troops
had also sent word to Jamaica,
asking for bombs that
they might lob over the walls.
In preparation,
they began digging trenches
close to the Castillo.
Suddenly, four Spanish warships
from Havana
appeared on the horizon.
♪♪
- So, the Spanish ships
literally appear,
probably just at the right time.
- Four galleons
are on the horizon!
- They've got troops with them.
They've got, obviously,
supplies and ammunition.
♪♪
- After 52 days of fighting,
the siege was finally over.
♪♪
But before Moore's army
retreated,
they set fire to the remaining
buildings in town.
For at least the third time
since the first settlement
had been established,
fire had ravaged the city.
It was going to take decades
to fully recover.
- No food, no homes.
It's late December
and almost January,
so, you know, it's not even
a good time, really,
to grow food.
♪♪
We do know, by looking through
the parish records,
that, over the next two
or three years after the siege,
the birth rate in St. Augustine
dropped drastically.
The birth rate in 1703 and 1704
is 1/3 of what it was in 1702.
Whether the mothers
weren't healthy enough to,
you know, bring babies to term,
we can conjecture,
but obviously, it is an issue
of food supplies
and health and shelter.
And, I mean, that's a drastic
drop in the birth rate.
♪♪
- The untold emotional
and physical toll
that rebuilding took
is probably most apparent
in the Spanish skeletal remains
from that era.
- Culture was under stress, their
life was a life of hardship,
and this is reflected
in the broken bones.
- Virtually everybody
over a few years old
had terrible dental caries
and abscesses in the jaws
and had lost teeth,
and pretty much everybody
over 20 had severe arthritis.
It must have been painful to do
daily chores like drawing water
and chopping fuel wood
and grinding corn.
♪♪
- But while the people
of St. Augustine
were slowing piecing
their lives back together...
James Moore
was back in South Carolina,
plotting revenge.
- He suffered
the loss of his pride.
He was treated
as a contemptible person
for having failed in his mission
to capture
the castle at St. Augustine.
- And so, Colonel Moore is
in trouble back in Charleston,
because they lost
a lot of money,
the backers of this expedition.
- He was brought
before the courts,
and that was
a great embarrassment to him
that he had failed to capture
St. Augustine and to loot it.
- So, he decided to make up
for it somehow.
♪♪
- Piracy.
How did you make a living
back then?
You stole from other people.
- Moore hatched a new plan
to get revenge on the Spanish.
This time, he promised
that South Carolina
would not have to pay
for the expedition.
He was going to recover his
costs in a highly lucrative way.
- It was stealing people...
That the Native Americans
could be rounded up.
They could be walked back
to Charles Town
and sold into slave markets.
- A promotional pamphlet
is distributed around England
that advises people
to enslave Indians
because they're cheaper
and they're easier to acquire.
- And that was where
the money was.
It was in the slavery business.
- Indians increasingly have to
choose whether to become victims
or to participate in the
slave trade as slave raiders.
And so, the Yamasees and the
Lower Creeks, in particular,
they have become
very active slave raiders.
- We did not understand
the concept
of what they
identified slavery as.
I think that
if our people had known
that this would have turned out
the way it did,
they wouldn't have assisted.
- Over the next two years,
Moore and his raiders storm
the Spanish missions
throughout the interior
of La Florida.
- There, he burned
and maimed and killed.
It's a disaster.
- Most of the survivors of these
mission raids were captured
and taken back
to South Carolina.
According to his own report,
James Moore
took over 4,000 Natives,
mostly women and children,
to sell into slavery.
- The historian of this period,
John Hann,
said that this was
the largest slave raid
in the history of the country.
- In South Carolina,
about 25% of the
slave population is Indian,
so a full quarter
is American Indians.
- And that's how
he redeemed himself,
with all these slaves,
all this income.
- There's a term,
and it is an insult
for a Native person to say
they act
as if they have no family,
because kinship is humanness,
because, obviously,
they would never treat
another human like that
if they knew what it was to love
and to hold something sacred.
So, in our eyes,
they were less than human.
- It is nearly impossible
to find much writing
in the documentary record
about Mission Indians,
because the English wiped out
so much of their past.
- Yes!
- But Dr. Susan Parker
has managed to trace
several decades of the life
of one Indian and his family
as they endured numerous attacks
by English invaders.
Their story shows
the enormous price that was paid
by those who remain loyal
to Spain.
- Francisco Jospo
was a Mission Indian,
born about 10 years before the
English established Carolina.
- Jospo grew up on a mission
in what is now
St. Catherines Island
in Georgia.
When he was a young man,
his mission was attacked
several times,
first by early Carolina settlers
who predated Moore,
and then by English pirates.
Jospo moved south
and started his own militia.
♪♪
- In 1715, he talks about
how he is living in a village
south of St. Augustine.
The English Indians
attacked the village.
♪♪
- Jospo had been one of the first
to take up arms
to defend the settlement.
- They attack his village
while he is out with his men,
and they take his wife
and children,
he says, at knifepoint.
- Three times, the English offer
to return Jospo's family
in exchange for his alliance
with them
and abandonment of Catholicism.
Three times, he refused.
- No.
No. No. No.
♪♪
- In a letter
to the King of Spain,
Jospo said he believed
his family had been separated
and sold as slaves,
probably to work on
sugar plantations
in Jamaica or the Barbados.
- And he says that he fears
that they have been taken
and perished in foreign lands.
And it was a story that just...
That grabbed me
and certainly touched my heart,
I think, when he said
that he feared that his family
had perished in foreign lands.
- The British had no interest in
spreading their Christian faith
among the Native peoples of,
say, New England or the Midwest.
The English
had very little interest
in the welfare
of the Native societies.
It was commonly said in, what
I call the powdered-wig states,
"The only good Indian
is a dead Indian."
- Moore and his allies
viciously killed
over 1,000 people
during his raids.
- Well, it was terribly brutal.
People were burned alive.
People were disemboweled,
flayed, crucified.
Christianized Indians,
the friars might be nailed
to the cross.
- It was genocide.
It was ethnic cleansing.
History is written
by the victors,
so whoever tells the story
is obviously going to tell it
from their perspective,
and there's an indigenous voice
that really hasn't been told.
- In one document,
there's a whole list of chiefs
that were killed.
- Flagler College Distinguished
Professor of Religion
Dr. Timothy Johnson
has been studying
eyewitness accounts
of the genocide that occurred
at these missions.
- People are given the chance
to deny their faith.
Some of them decide to flee,
but many of them decide,
"We're gonna die as Christians."
They would stand up,
even watching and seeing
and hearing what was happening
and knowing full well
what was coming their way.
And so, not only are these
incredible historical documents,
they're really
quite inspirational...
The stories of what people
would do in the face of death.
- These accounts are part
of the sworn testimony
taken by the Catholic Church
in 1704,
when Pope Clement XI
set up a commission
to look into these reputed acts
of faith.
But it wasn't until
a few years ago
when Catholic historians began
transcribing these records
that bishops felt
there was enough there
to propose consideration
for sainthood.
- There's a very sad story of a
young boy by the name of Manuel.
Manuel is an altar server,
and he is referred to
in the sources
as a young boy,
maybe 13 years old,
but who had
a great, great devotion to God.
And when the Creeks came in,
they set fire to the chapel,
and they said,
"Well, if you're a Christian,
then pray that God
will send rain to put this out."
So, he raised his hands,
and they cut them off,
and they threw them to the dogs.
And then what they do...
It's horrible.
You slice someone's neck
and then pull their skin
completely over their head.
That's how he died.
♪♪
- The Vatican has begun
the process of canonization
for some 82 Native Americans
and missionaries
killed for their belief
during these raids.
♪♪
Among them were Apalachee,
Chickasaw, Yamasee,
Tocobaga, and Timucuans.
- And the Vatican said,
"We believe that there are
justifiable grounds."
He'll declare these people
as servants of God,
which is the first step
on the road to canonization.
♪♪
- Only one Florida mission
has ever been reconstructed
based on the ruins
archaeologists have found...
Mission San Luis in Tallahassee.
- The estimate that's been given
for San Luis, at its heighth,
was between 1,500 and 2,000
in this area.
And that was Apalachee,
and at its heighth,
there were probably
100 Spanish residents
that lived here permanently,
plus the soldiers who were
cycled in with the garrison.
- But ever since Moore's
first attacks in 1702,
several attempts
to fend off these raids
killed off
most of the Apalachee.
The number of Spanish soldiers
sent to defend the mission
kept dwindling.
When they heard Moore's troops
were advancing,
the residents
of Mission San Luis
burned down their buildings
and fled.
♪♪
By 1706, the Spanish missions
in La Florida
had been almost
completely obliterated.
It dealt a demoralizing blow
to Spanish Catholics,
but it was also a crippling
setback for St. Augustine.
The missions
had been its breadbasket.
- The outlying missions supplied
much of the surplus corn
for St. Augustine,
and that chain of missions
going north
became a really important source
of food
for the Spanish settlement.
♪♪
- Now those fields were barren,
and even a decade later,
food continued to be scarce.
♪♪
But as the town slowly rebuilt,
the British began
to turn their gaze again
on the Spanish presence
to their south.
La Florida was a threat
to the British way of life,
particularly on
the issue of slavery.
As far back as the days
of the conquistadors,
Africans had been an accepted
and integral part
of everyday life
in Spanish America.
- Probably the first
African-American
to this part of the world
was on missions here,
scouting with Ponce de León.
The person was not a slave...
He was a free man.
- There were
free black people here
from the beginning
of the colony onward.
- These were people who helped
build the early garrisons.
They built residences.
They did work that was critical
for the survival
of the community.
They weren't working out, for
example, on sugar plantations.
That was not something
that the Spanish started.
- Race was not the basis for
slavery in the Spanish world.
If somebody
was Christian and Catholic,
there really was no impediment
to them being free.
- The Spanish did have slaves,
but slavery under the British
was not the same.
- Their method of enslavement
and control of Africans
were very different than
the Spaniard, absolutely.
♪♪
- Under English law, a slave
was property, or chattel,
without any legal
or civil rights.
No!
No! No! No!
- Slaves could be bought, sold,
and punished, or even killed.
♪♪
Spanish law, on the other hand,
recognized slaves as
human beings with legal rights.
- Slaves had inherent rights.
Slaves could, for example,
purchase their own freedom.
Slave families
could not be separated by law.
- They marry, and their marriages
appear in the church record,
so these were considered
official marriages
and recognized
as legal marriages,
just as anyone else's were,
which is a right, as we call it,
that we don't often see
in the British colonies.
- So, we have to be careful
not to say that
somehow Spanish slavery
was good slavery,
better than English slavery.
It's still slavery.
At the same time,
Spanish laws that govern slavery
were fundamentally
different from, say,
English laws
that govern slavery.
- Spanish slaves
could own property,
sue their owners in court,
and both men and women
could even petition the King.
- One of the largest differences
was the belief
that Africans were human beings
who had souls,
whereas the British
did not believe that at all.
They were just savages, and,
you know, beyond redemption.
- It’s very hard for
audiences in the United States
to get that
because we're so much more
familiar with chattel slavery,
which was the English system,
where a person enslaved
was considered
no more than
a piece of property,
like a horse or a cow,
which is why people
ran from that system
to seek some sort of sanctuary
among Spanish people, usually.
♪♪
- Ever since the late 1600s,
Spanish Florida
was becoming a sanctuary
for African slaves who fled
from British plantations.
- Long before there was
an Underground Railroad
that ran north,
there was
an Underground Railroad
that ran south.
♪♪
- La Florida started
granting asylum to slaves
after a small group
escaped by canoe
from the Carolinas in 1687.
- Please, Governor.
Please let us stay.
- They asked
Governor Diego de Quiroga
for asylum,
saying they wanted to become
members of the true faith,
Catholicism.
The Spanish who had founded
La Florida,
in part to convert the New World
to Christianity,
could hardly refuse.
- And the Spanish governor's not
quite sure what to do with them.
"What status
do these people have?
Do we risk some...
A potential conflict
with the English over this?"
- And he keeps writing to Spain,
"What do I do about this?"
- After five years of this,
King Charles Il
finally responded that
as a, quote, "prize for having
adopted the Catholic doctrine,
they should all be set free
and given anything they needed."
- And he says,
"By my example and liberality,
others will do the same."
And he's hoping to drain off
the plantation slaves
from South Carolina,
weaken the English usurpers.
The King's edict declared
that runaway slaves
who became Catholic
or willing
to help defend the town
would be granted freedom.
- And, of course,
that then initiates waves
of runaway slaves from
the Carolinas, from Virginia.
You see in the records
some slaves from as far as...
Far north as New York,
who are escaping plantations
to reach St. Augustine.
- The English
were angry about it,
and they sent people
to try to recover these slaves,
and they never
would return them.
- The British
were very much afraid
of Spain's sovereignty
in Florida,
accepting people and allowing
them to gain their freedom.
- In fact, Spain's open-door
policy was not just a vehicle
to save more souls
for the Catholic Church.
It was also a way to destabilize
the plantation economy
of the British colonies.
- The planters were
particularly concerned that,
if waves of runaway slaves
make it to St. Augustine,
all that's going to do is
encourage more runaway slaves,
and that will, in the end,
dismantle the entire system,
and it will encourage rebellion
in these plantations.
♪♪
- Around this time,
a young Mandingo child
was captured in West Africa
and taken to the Carolinas
to work the plantations.
Eventually, he was given
the European name
"Francisco Menendez."
- The ship arrived
in the Carolinas
with less than 3/4
of its cargo...
Of its human cargo.
So, aboard that ship,
most of the slaves
that were captured
from Mandingo in West Africa
were dead.
To imagine surviving that,
cramped in a space
smaller than this chair,
not a lot of sun,
not a lot of food,
not a lot of cleanliness,
you know, it takes
an extraordinary will to live
when you're seeing others dying
around you.
And how you do that at 8 or 9,
I don't know.
- As he grew into manhood,
Francisco Menendez
became indispensable
to his British owners.
He could not only do
the work of several men,
but he also learned
to speak several languages.
♪♪
When he first escaped
to Spanish La Florida
in the early 1700s,
Menendez sought refuge
with various Indian tribes
living in the backwoods
to the north.
- But what he learns in the three
years living in the wilderness
is how to move through
the forest
without harm, hurt, or danger,
sound or footprint,
how to track and hunt.
But he also learns,
during that time,
how to master British firearms.
- In 1715, Menendez proved
himself a fierce warrior,
fighting the British
alongside Natives
in a conflict known
as the Yamasee War.
The Yamasees had once been
allies with the Carolina colony,
but the British slave raiders
had begun to turn on them.
- In the 1710s,
the Indian slave trade
had sort of reached its height.
It's frenzied.
So many Native groups
are now vulnerable,
and they're watching their
own family members or friends
become slaves.
And they're seeing that they are
on a slippery slope downwards,
that they will end up as slaves.
- You have constant encroachments
on our land,
along with the taking
and kidnapping of our children.
It forced us to a situation
where all the head warriors
came together,
and we're talking about war.
- Francisco Menendez
knew the enemy well
and proved to be a valuable
fighter for the Yamasees.
When the war was over
two years later,
Menendez headed to St. Augustine
to petition the Spanish governor
for his freedom.
But on his way there,
he was betrayed.
- An infidel Yamasee named
Perro Bravo, which is Wild Dog,
somehow acquired him
in the trail down here,
and Perro Bravo threatened
to kill him
and other slaves
that he held in his possession
if the Spaniards
didn't pay for them.
- Menendez
was sold back into slavery
for a bottle of rum
and a small harvest of corn.
He was later sold at auction
to Florida Governor
Antonio de Benavides,
who blatantly ignored
the Spanish edict
to free escaped slaves,
and even bought and sold them
himself.
- In, you know, the 18th century,
in Spanish Florida,
not many people
could read and write,
and here's
an African man who can.
That gave him tremendous status,
and he was linked
to the very important people
in the community.
♪♪
- Benavides put
Francisco Menendez
in charge
of the black slave militia
to help the Spanish regiments
defend St. Augustine.
- He hates the English.
He'd been their slave.
He knows the terrain.
He's fought them for years.
♪♪
- Eventually, Spain outlawed
the sale of runaway slaves
in Florida to private citizens.
A new governor,
Manuel de Montiano, took office.
He offered members of the
black militia their freedom,
provided they would serve
four more years first.
♪♪
In 1738, Francisco Menendez
was finally granted
unconditional freedom.
- He becomes the leader
of a new free community here.
- Escaped slaves had been
living in St. Augustine
for nearly a half century now,
and they had become an integral
part of the community.
♪♪
In 1738,
Governor Manuel de Montiano
gave them their own land
and chose Francisco Menendez,
now a free man, as its leader.
The community was located
about a mile and a half
outside the city.
It was called "Gracia Real
de Santa Teresa de Mose,"
or as it's known today,
"Fort Mose."
It was the first
legally sanctioned
free black community
in what is now
the United States.
This was 125 years before
the Emancipation Proclamation.
- That experience is not
like anything we learn
in our African-American
history textbooks,
so they usually miss
a whole century
and a lot
of different experiences,
if you think of it only as an
enslaved-plantation experience.
- It's very difficult
to understand U.S. history
without understanding Florida.
I think it's...
When you start to integrate
the narratives
about the experiences,
for example, of Africans
in the United States,
and you fail to look
at the Africans in Florida,
you get a very distorted
picture of what's unfolding.
- The new, fortified settlement
had its own church
and was comprised
of skilled blacksmiths,
carpenters, cattlemen,
boatmen, and farmers.
- This was a rough frontier.
It wasn't easy for anybody.
So, I don't mean to glamorize it
by saying people
were made free here.
Sometimes, the food supplies
would be disrupted.
Sometimes,
there were epidemic diseases
that wipe out
black and white alike
and Indians worse.
It's not easy, but it's
at least the possibility
of everybody living freely
in an urban setting,
having property,
not worrying that their children
are gonna be sold away
from them.
Those sorts of things
are quite different.
- In the 1970s, Dr. Jane Landers
was just a graduate student
when she discovered documents
in the archives of Spain
describing the settlement.
- One day, I almost jumped
because I came across a census
of the town of Gracia Real
de Santa Teresa de Mose,
and it was household
by household,
exactly who lived
in the households,
you know, whether
they were already converted
or on their way
to full Catholicism.
And I was able, finally,
to get the full picture
of the community.
- She found a treasure trove.
Most historians have thought
that African-American life
was totally almost undocumented.
They were really
the people without history.
She was able to find census data
and information
about where the people came from
and what they did
and their names and ages,
and that was tremendously
exciting for us.
- When I brought all this back
and made some reports on it,
then the archaeologists
could start digging.
- Yeah, but unless it's...
- Dr. Kathleen Deagan
led the dig.
- We were then able to work
with some of her information
and do large-scale surveys
and low-level
aerial satellite imagery
and verify that this place
we thought probably
was Fort Mose really was.
- Deagan's and Landers' findings
gave a glimpse
of what life was like
in the first
free black settlement
in what is now
the United States.
- They had fields
outside of a fort.
They grew crops.
They had animals.
They fished.
They gathered cattle...
Wild cattle roaming
in the hinterlands.
They rode horseback through
the woods all the time.
They were pilots, and they were,
you know, corsairs.
- I think that the United States
is richer.
Its history is richer
because it demonstrated
that African and European people
could live together,
could benefit
from each other's skills,
and that, as a beginning,
I think we would have
a very different picture
of the United States.
- What I think
is really important
is it's a story
of empowerment and of freedom.
I think it's such
a different narrative
than saying everybody got off
a slave ship, bedraggled,
and sweated
in a cotton field somewhere.
This is centuries of other kinds
of experience, and it...
I think it is important
to show that, too.
- The location of Fort Mose
at the edge of town
was an important defensive move.
There was no better soldier
to defend St. Augustine
than a man who did not want
to become enslaved again.
- They have every motive
and impetus
to fight hard
against any British attacks.
- Well, we know that
they're going to fight
and they're gonna fight
to the death
against their former oppressors.
- The militia at Fort Mose
would soon be tested.
A year after the town
was established,
the largest slave uprising
in the British mainland colonies
erupted in South Carolina.
- On the ground, it's personal.
You know, people who thought
they had slaves...
They're running away to Florida.
They're angry.
They want to come get them.
- Finally, King George Il
ordered Georgia's troops
to take St. Augustine
and end the practice
of harboring runaway slaves.
- They were adamant
that this place had to fall,
so they had to be wiped out.
- General James Oglethorpe
had founded Georgia
and had been its first governor.
Although he was actually
against slavery,
he'd been anxious
to take La Florida
away from the Spanish for years.
- He’s very close
to St. Augustine
and even moves down
to put some forts
near the mouth
of the St. Johns River,
so he actually comes into
what is today Florida.
- King George
commanded Oglethorpe to, quote,
"spare no personal danger
in exacting revenge
on those slaves
who had fled their owners."
Francisco Menendez
had successfully led
several attacks on the British
before this,
but when Governor Montiano heard
that the English were coming
to avenge the slave owners,
he feared for the safety
of the people at Fort Mose.
- So, he orders them
to abandon Mose
and to come into St. Augustine
for their protection,
because he figures
they'll either be all killed
and/or captured.
And so, they come into
St. Augustine,
and the British just walk right
into Fort Mose and take over.
- But 16 days later, the Spanish,
the black militia,
and the Native allies returned.
They caught the British
by surprise at daybreak
and easily retook the fort.
The British called it
the Battle of Bloody Mose.
- There's a quote
by Shakespeare...
"Some are born great,
some achieve greatness,
and some have greatness
thrust upon them."
Francisco Menendez...
Greatness was thrust upon him.
- Here were Africans
who were demonstrating
that they had the skills
to defend not only themselves,
but the Spaniards.
They were very brave people.
And so, that is a form of pride
for African-Americans.
- As many as 75 British soldiers
were killed.
- One of the people that was
killed at the Battle of Mose,
Colonel Palmer, had attacked
St. Augustine several times.
He had, you know,
had been reported
for brutalities
against Spaniards and blacks.
And so, it was a great feat
to capture him and kill him
at the Battle of Mose.
- Oglethorpe and his men
retreated.
- Some of the stories
that came out after Mose,
and some of the things
that the English claimed
the black militia did
to the people
that they killed and captured
had created this view
among the English that,
you know, they committed
all kinds of atrocities,
and they used this
as powerful propaganda, as well.
"This is what happens,
see, with these...
If these slaves escape,
and this is what they do
to people."
♪♪
- Though
they had won back their land,
the village of Mose
had been completely destroyed
in the battle.
- The free blacks from Mose
move into St. Augustine,
and they live in St. Augustine,
and they're property owners
in St. Augustine,
and they become a critical part
of the city's fabric.
- They stayed in St. Augustine
for the next 12 years.
Francisco Menendez went to
St. Augustine with the others,
but when the King of Spain
didn't compensate him
for his service,
Menendez signed on
to a Spanish ship
that was attacking
English settlements.
- He's eventually recaptured
by the English
and fully admits who he is.
- Menendez acknowledged that
he had been the leader
of the Battle of Bloody Mose,
and his English captors
became incensed.
♪♪
The tales of vicious savagery on
the part of these former slaves
had become legend
in the British colonies.
- And they torture him brutally
because they believed
the whole Spanish-Negro
conspiracy,
and they also say,
"There were people
who were tortured at Mose,
in that battle,
and you're responsible."
- And they gave him
a beating with a whip,
and in between,
they brined him in a salt,
pickled it.
- So, he was placed in a solution
that is...
Effectively,
eats away at his skin...
A high concentration
of salt and vinegar,
and it would've been
beyond enormously painful
to experience that.
- They just decided to sell him
as part of the loot
that they took on the ship,
and they take him
to the Bahamas,
and he's sold back into slavery.
♪♪
- It is not known whether
Spanish governors
negotiated his freedom
or he ran away,
but once again,
Francisco Menendez
miraculously escapes slavery.
- And returns to St. Augustine,
where, again, he becomes captain
of the new Fort Mose.
- Menendez led his community
of free slaves
back to the site
of the old Fort Mose
and reestablished the town.
By 1763, St. Augustine had been
the Spanish stronghold
in what is now the United States
for nearly 200 years.
♪♪
During that time,
the town had fended off
every attempt by the British
to conquer it.
But, ironically, it took just
a single stroke of the pen
for all of that to change.
It happened at the end
of the Seven Years' War,
when Spain was faced
with the possibility
of losing its valuable port
in Havana.
It chose, instead,
to give up La Florida
to the British.
♪♪
For the people of St. Augustine,
this was an unimaginable
twist of fate.
It meant certain death
or enslavement
for La Florida's
free blacks and Natives.
There was only one choice.
- If the British
are coming in here in 1763,
bringing their alternative view
of everybody
and of law and property,
the Spanish are leaving,
and they take everybody
that wants to go with them.
- And so, by February of 1764,
3,019 people had left
St. Augustine for Havana.
Every single Spaniard, with
the exception of three families,
all of the Spaniards,
all of the free blacks,
all of the slaves
that those Spaniards owned...
The entire city was depopulated.
Everybody had left.
- Uno, dos, tres...
- They set sail for other lands.
Among them, the free men
and women of Fort Mose
who headed to Cuba in hopes
of keeping their freedom.
- Francisco Menendez leads
the exodus in 1763 to Cuba,
and he leads that community
into exile.
- They had made a mark
in history
that demonstrated
how blacks could contribute,
how they could be free,
how they were not in need
of control,
like animals to be chained.
- Well, they would have to start
all over again in Cuba,
but they were free.
- As the Spanish ship
sailed away from St. Augustine,
the first legally sanctioned
free black community
in the United States
disappeared with them...
into the horizon.
♪♪