♪♪
- It was the dawn
of a new era
for the British Empire.
For the first time since
Spanish conquistadors
claimed La Florida
250 years earlier,
all of the Atlantic Coast
of North America
was finally under the control
of Great Britain.
- We all know about
the 13 British colonies.
But at the time
of the Revolution,
there weren't 13 British
colonies... there were 15.
Nobody knows that, hardly.
- Spain had given up
La Florida in 1763
in exchange for recovering
Cuba from the British.
England created East and West
Florida as royal colonies,
making them the 14th
and 15th British colonies
in North America,
that would later
become part of the U.S.
East Florida stretched
from the Atlantic
to the Apalachicola River.
St. Augustine,
now 300 buildings strong,
was the capital.
West Florida, with the smaller
settlement of Pensacola
as the capital,
reached to the Mississippi.
- East Florida and West Florida
have been completely
written out of the narrative.
Search "13 British colonies"
and you will not find
numbers 14 and 15.
- It was a radical
changing of the guard.
The scrappy melting pot
of European, Native,
and black communities
that had eked out a rough
frontier life under Spanish rule
had evacuated
to Mexico and Cuba.
And stepping in to govern
the colony of East Florida
was a British aristocrat,
Colonel James Grant,
heir apparent of
Ballindalloch Castle
in the Scottish Highlands.
Grant was literally
of the manor born,
growing up on this 10,000-acre
estate in Speyside,
which has been kept
in the family for centuries.
Many of the rooms
remain as they were
when the castle
was built in 1545.
- I always think it's such
a shame the walls can't talk.
'Cause think of
the wonderful stories
that must be in every room.
- Grant left is comfortable life
here to fight for his country
when he was 24.
- He was a very big military man.
He was obviously very bright.
He had a great estate.
He had lots of servants
to look after him.
And he needn't have done that.
He could've stayed here
on the estate and done nothing.
- Grant left the lush,
rolling hills of Scotland
for the relentless heat
and sandy soil of East Florida,
hoping to transform
this unmanageable territory
into a viable British
trade colony.
The governor of West Florida
was another aristocrat
who had been a commander
in the Royal Navy.
Commodore George Johnstone
had a reputation
for being hot-tempered,
scheming, and duplicitous.
But he was vigorous
about encouraging trade
in the new colony.
- Here was a subtropical region
that suddenly they had
that might
potentially allow them
to grow some sort of fruits
or vegetables
they would have
to go elsewhere for.
- They saw East Florida
and West Florida
as an extension
of the Caribbean.
So they saw
agricultural profits.
- Many of the missing pieces
of the story of British Florida
were hidden in the attic turret
at Ballindalloch Castle,
buried among thousands
of other papers
that had been stored there
and forgotten for centuries.
In the 1970s,
Grant's descendants
asked the Scottish
National Archives
to inventory what was there.
A decade later, Dr. Dan Schafer
was allowed access to the papers
and began methodically
reconstructing the history
of British Florida.
- That's where the records were.
The whole James Grant
letter collection
were in the castle
in a far attic,
in the cold, in a room where
they were stored very well,
but nobody knew they were there.
This country, I am convinced
is totally unknown.
- Grant's letters describe
East Florida
as completely undeveloped,
still in a state of nature
when he arrived.
And since only three families
remained after
the Spanish left St. Augustine,
Grant had no one to help harness
the wilderness beyond town.
- How are you going to
develop a province
when there's nobody here?
- Grant began by offering
free land
to successful plantation
owners in other colonies.
- He would say,
"We have better climate.
We have better everything
than you have there.
Come here."
- The British-sanctioned
land grants were anywhere
from 100 acres
to 20,000-acre parcels.
- Well, if they come in
to St. Augustine
and find a dismal place
and have a terrible time,
they're not gonna come,
so he lit up their night life.
- He was a bachelor.
And he had one of the largest
collections of wine
in this area.
And by "this area,"
I'm talking about North America.
He had three slaves who were
trained in French culinary arts.
And he threw a party
probably four,
five nights out of the week.
- Yeah, he was quite a party guy.
Every month,
he would do inventory
of the Governor's cellars.
And if you were to see that,
how much alcohol
passed through his cellars...
♪♪
- Those inventories,
along with Grant's letters,
are now housed in the National
Registry of Scotland
in Edinburgh.
- During his first year
in office,
beverages drunk from
the Governor's cellars
tallied 86 gallons
of Madeira wine,
76 gallons Tenerife wine,
1,200 bottles of claret,
519 bottles of port,
and ample amounts of Champagne,
sweet wine, porter, beer,
ale, cider, arrack,
and old Hock.
He kept a daily inventory of how
he entertained all the soldiers
and how long
and how late they stayed.
"Eight bottles of Madeira drunk.
Captain Rainsford went
home speechless.
Unusual for that captain.
Debram, the Surveyor General,
once again got drunk.
Mr. Row's daughter, poor girl,
got half-drunk.
Mrs. Sharpe sung,
as did Mrs. Box.
Neither of them well."
- ♪ They do as they will ♪
- "Captain Sutherland
was hobbling,
but he got home sober."
- West Florida was desperately
in need of settlers, too.
But its governor was not
as charismatic as Grant.
And the presence of
some 28,000 Natives
living near the Mississippi made
Europeans wary of moving there.
Grant however managed
to court dozens of investors
to East Florida,
developing plantations
along the Atlantic Coast,
from the St. Marys River
in Georgia to a region
just north of today's Orlando.
- I think you'll probably
find few examples
of more successful governors
than he was.
- But along with that plantation
economy came the British form
of chattel slavery,
which they introduced
into colonial Florida
for the first time.
- "Keep in mind that settlements
in this warm climate
must be formed by Negroes.
Success in Florida, my lord,
will not be achieved
until this country
is brought to that rich
and plentiful state
by the labor of slaves."
- Everything changed when
the British came in in 1763.
There was no longer
slave sanctuary
for British slaves to run away
to from Carolina and Georgia.
- And that's why East Florida
was overwhelmingly
a slave-plantation colony.
- In the meantime in Cuba,
the Spanish free blacks
who had left before
the British arrived
were not faring well.
- If it's not a tragedy enough
that most of them left,
within six years
of their departure,
20% of that group
had died in Havana.
- The Spanish Crown is not able
to support them with the money
or food
like they said they would.
There's a tremendous
loss of life.
- These are the books
of the burials
of the people of color
at Santa Mosé.
- For several years,
Dr. Jane Landers
of Vanderbilt University
has been tracking the fate
of the residents of Fort Mose
after they arrived in Cuba.
- You can track epidemic disease
through these burial records
and see that so many people
are buried on the same day,
and sometimes they even
tell you what disease.
- Landers is working with a team
of graduate students
to digitize the records.
- We're trying to get as many
of the oldest books
preserved as possible.
As you can see, especially
from that other book
we're working on there,
they're very fragile.
They're old.
They're disappearing as we're
talking and filming here today.
Some of them look like lace.
Climate is a problem.
It's hot and humid.
Bugs are a problem.
So, you'll see worm paths
through the paper.
Fires occasionally.
Sometimes people don't know
what was in those records
and they got tossed.
At one point, there was
no roof on this church,
and everything was
exposed to the air.
They moved the books
to the safest place they could
and they've since
put back a roof.
But all of that damages records,
and some of them
have not survived.
- Landers' team has found that
disease wasn't the only reason
why so many of the refugees
from Florida died here.
- They'd already undergone
so many disruptions.
They'd been moved,
they'd been under attack.
- And some of it may just be
emotional distress, as well.
Especially for the older people.
- And those indigenous tribes
that had gone to Cuba
to avoid being enslaved by the
British were also in jeopardy.
- There were 89 Timucua
and Guale Indians
who left with the Spanish.
And within six years,
more than half of them had died.
- So Guanabacoa has an important
history also for Florida
as the last resting place
of many of the Florida Indians.
- And as for Francisco Menendez,
about a year after he
and his family arrived in Cuba,
the trail goes cold.
- And I'm trying
to track Menendez.
You can see when they give up
their homestead
because you can see them making
payments, and at some point,
they sort of disappear
off of that account book.
- So far, Landers has been unable
to find his grave
in any of the church
cemeteries in Cuba.
We may never know
what happened to him.
Back in East Florida,
illness forced Governor Grant
to return to England
for medical care.
Two years later, he was
elected to Parliament
and resigned as governor.
A new leader was appointed,
Colonel Patrick Tonyn,
who ran into opposition
almost immediately.
- He was the nastiest person
I've ever read a letter from.
He hated everybody.
He had a chip on his shoulder
the size of Ireland.
- Such a vindictive nature that
he had, and so self-serving.
I find it really hard
to like the man.
- Tonyn drew resistance
from several of Grant's friends,
including one who publicly
insulted Tonyn's wife.
- He announced, "I will not
allow my wife and daughters
to interact with Mrs. Tonyn.
I knew her in Scotland,
and she was a whore."
So the gauntlet was thrown
immediately.
And Tonyn never forgot.
He never forgave.
- Several clashed with Tonyn
over the issue of governance.
The colonists believed
they had the same rights
as they had had in Britain,
such as electing representatives
to a colonial house of assembly.
Tonyn viewed such demands
as disloyalty to the Crown.
Former governor Grant
wrote letters back to Florida
assuring his friends
that his successor would
soon win them over...
but he didn't.
- "You predicted that
Governor Tonyn
would bring all into good humor
and drowned animosity
in a bottle of claret.
You're quite mistaken
in your man.
I went to one of
his first parties
and he served bad food
on a dirty tablecloth,"
and then continues with, "in all
the comfort of a dirty whore."
- Tonyn lost even more ground
when he began to mistreat
the three domestic slaves he had
promised to purchase from Grant.
- Do you understand me?!
- Alexander, who Governor Grant
had trained to be a prized baker
for all these great affairs,
dinners, that he was having,
was punished by putting
an iron mask around his head
that padlocked in the back.
"Alexander stopped me
in the street.
He complains of the iron caps.
He wishes very much
to be your baker again.
He complains that madame
is the devil.
But since I saw him,
he has had the cap put on
and been flogged."
- Alexander and the two
other slaves
eventually ran away
to the woods.
When Grant heard about this,
he insisted that they be given
sanctuary at his own plantation.
- "You are publicly to make it
known that Governor Tonyn
has nothing to do with them,
that they have nothing to fear."
Which is a most
remarkable thing.
To rebuke the other
governor publicly
was a remarkable thing to do.
- But ironically,
just a few years later,
Tonyn would cast himself
as a great liberator,
and in doing so,
he would turn people against
one of his more vocal critics.
That man was
Dr. Andrew Turnbull,
who ran the largest plantation
in all of North America.
- Turnbull is dreaming big,
big dreams, amazing dreams,
and he had no idea the troubles
that lay ahead of him.
- Educated at the University
of Edinburgh,
Turnbull studied medicine
there when he was only 13.
When the British started
offering land grants in Florida,
Turnbull and his two
wealthy partners
were granted over 100,000 acres.
- There's nothing like that
in colonial American history.
This is just massive
in its scale.
- Turnbull personally recruited
indentured workers from Menorca,
as well as Turkey,
Greece, and Italy.
More than 1,400 people.
- "And I'm going away
as fast as possible,
as the Governor has
taken umbrage at my taking
so many people from his place.
I beg Sir William that you will
not say any of this
until you hear from me
after I've gotten
safely away from here."
If the Turks had apprehended
and jailed him,
he wouldn't have gotten
out of that jail,
or they would've killed him.
- Many of those who signed
on were fleeing famine
and drought in
their own homelands.
- Everything would be
paid for them.
He would provide transportation,
food, provisions.
And once they arrived
in Florida,
then they would begin to work
under contract for him.
They would be
indentured laborers.
- For a while, Turnbull
turned the colony
into a successful
indigo plantation.
- Accomplished on a huge scale
development of plantation-based
economy with export products
that are baffling in size.
- Turnbull was influential
back in England.
When he criticized
East Florida's governance,
Tonyn was reprimanded.
- So there was a real clash
between these two men.
And if you were Tonyn, you would
have some hard feelings
if Turnbull tried to get
you fired, which he did.
- But nine years after it began,
the Turnbull venture
was finished.
- It was a terrible failure,
actually, because about
half of his labor force died
within four years
of leaving Europe.
They faced devastating drought,
hurricane, money shortages,
inability to buy things.
- Turnbull's accounts,
as well as his record
of the number of lives lost,
are housed in the Dundee
City Archives in Scotland.
- And it's one of the saddest
of all the documents
that you'll find
in this entire archive
at the Dundee collection.
"Males... 406 left alive.
Females... 296 left alive."
- Within two years after Turnbull
had brought
more than 1,400 people
over from the Mediterranean,
half had died.
The desperation of
his workers grew worse
when Turnbull returned
to England on business
and left his overseers
in charge.
- Increasingly, the behavior
of the overseers and guards
toward the indentured servants
was unfair,
approaching on criminal.
The workforce
was just completely
depressed psychologically.
One of the Menorcan group
gather together a couple
of other Menorcans and sneaked
out of the encampment one night,
walked up the beach
to Anastasia Island,
swam across the river
to St. Augustine,
and approached
the English governor,
begging him to do something
to redress their grievances.
- Governor Tonyn seized
the opportunity to get revenge
on this man who had so openly
defied his authority.
- Governor Tonyn hated Turnbull
so badly, and the first thing
Tonyn did was he had a notary
taking the sworn affidavits.
- Turnbull was portrayed
as a monster.
- And of course,
he becomes a most hated figure
in British-colonial history.
- The complaints launched against
the overseers included rape,
beatings, and floggings.
- They accuse him of whipping,
that he whipped people.
They accuse him
of starving his laborers.
- The stories were very similar
in the affidavits.
I mean, there were people who...
you know, pregnant women beaten.
There were who had brothers
who were beaten to death.
- And many of these people
were imprisoned.
Some were executed.
- Turnbull later defended himself
against these accusations.
- His defense is interesting.
His defense is, "Look, if I was
so brutal to them,
how can it be then that
my children and my wife
were not vindictively killed
while I was away
for three years?"
- The infraction Tonyn
was able to get him on
was enslaving white people.
You could indenture them,
but they had a contract.
Contracts have ending dates,
and they swore
in their affidavits
he had illegally kept them
beyond their dates,
and that's where Tonyn said,
"I've got him."
- Turnbull maintained he would
have honored his contract
once the debts were paid.
The court agreed with him.
Nevertheless, Turnbull's alleged
brutality became legendary,
and his plantation was
eventually closed down.
- Governor Tonyn,
a very vindictive man,
and at the end he had
Turnbull thrown in jail.
He came out on bail and left
the province as a result.
But surely, each person is
guilty of arrogance and haughty,
vindictive behavior
it seems to me.
- Despite how Tonyn had treated
his own African slaves,
he now set himself up
as a great liberator
by freeing Turnbull's
indentured servants.
Several were too sick to leave,
but with Tonyn's blessing,
about 500 of them
came to St. Augustine
and made their homes there.
Most of them were Menorcan.
- And there they
have been ever since.
From their ranks
have come mayors,
two bishops,
two great literary figures,
Stephen Vincent Benét
and his brother
William Rose Benét.
They've had a very distinguished
and long career in the city.
- But by this time, Tonyn and the
rest of the British colonies
had bigger problems
to contend with.
The American Revolutionary War
had begun.
The Boston Tea Party had
taken place in December 1773,
just a few months before
Tonyn arrived in Florida.
For the next year,
as unrest boiled to the North,
Tonyn kept a watchful eye
on his citizenry.
- He was here to keep this colony
safe for king and country.
- He was caught in the war almost
within months of his arrival.
But he had such
an aggravating personality
that people of importance
became the enemy,
and as he saw them,
they were part of the American
revolutionary mentality.
- Both East and West Florida were
the newest of the royal colonies
and had been tightly
controlled by the King
and by Parliament ever since.
- Had it been an older colony,
the kinds of grievances
rebels are talking about
in Georgia and South Carolina,
might well have been
in East Florida as well.
But the population that comes in
is settled in so late,
most of the people who were
there had very strong,
deep ties to England,
and they had not developed
those sort of self-governing
institutional ties.
- Meanwhile, the colony
of West Florida
was dealing with other problems,
as the War of Independence
loomed.
It had gone through numerous
governors since it began.
Once of them, John Elliot,
hung himself just a month
after he arrived there.
West Florida was hardly
ready for independence.
- I think that East
and West Florida
have been written out of
the historical narrative
because they remained loyal
to the British Crown
during the Revolution.
And so they just
don't quite fit in
to that story
of the American patriots.
- And so it was sort of
like phantom pain
from an amputated limb...
Nobody paid attention to it,
and nobody claimed it
for a long time,
and yet it's a politically
important place.
- Much has been written
about the conflicts
fought in the 13 colonies
and the help the rebels
got from the French.
But little is known
about the pivotal role
that battles along the
Mississippi and Gulf Coast
played in turning the tide
of the Revolutionary War,
or the vital part Spain had in
supporting the American cause.
- It's just as much a part
of American history
as Washington
crossing the Delaware
or Paul Revere's ride.
- As iconic as the steeple
of the Old North Church,
this unfinished tower on
the Cathedral in Málaga, Spain,
stands in silent tribute
to the part it played
in the American
fight for freedom.
- Because the money
the Málaga town council
was to use to finish
this tower was sent
instead to help fund the
American War of Independence.
- During the Revolution,
Spain secretly funneled money
to the Americans
through this man,
Bernardo de Gálvez,
a native of Málaga,
who was the Governor
of Spanish-held Louisiana.
Donations came from
all over Spain.
The Cathedral's tower remains
unfinished to this day,
as a lasting tribute
to that effort.
- It's a great story.
Even on the level of the
common man and the common woman,
you're seeing support
for what's going on.
- By 1777, Gálvez had sent
an estimated $70,000
worth of medicine, weapons,
and ammunition
to the American rebels.
But in 1779, when Spain
declared war on Great Britain,
Gálvez was free to openly
defend the American cause.
He gathered recruits
from Mexico,
free blacks from Cuba,
Native Americans,
Spanish soldiers, Germans,
and Acadian French.
- Gálvez had a huge army.
Huge.
And it was one that was
multicultural in its makeup,
multi-ethnic.
- And this fleet full of
black sailors and militiamen
who helped win the independence
of the United States of America,
not memorialized, usually.
Except we find them
in the Spanish records.
- By 1780, the British
had taken Charleston
and blockaded the port cities
along the East Coast.
- The British war effort
in the War of Independence
is entirely based on the sea,
and eventually they
capture key port cities
basically to control the
economic life of the colonies.
'Cause there's no way
of getting all those goods
that you're producing out
into the world trade system.
So what the British are saying,
"We hold Charleston.
If you want to trade,
trade through us."
- Gálvez knew the Mississippi
was a vital route
that circumvented
the British blockade.
He led attacks on the British
forts along the Gulf,
taking Baton Rouge,
Natchez, and Mobile,
but Pensacola
was the most formidable
British bastion on the coast.
- Washington makes a statement
that much depends
on what happens in Pensacola,
that he is placing great value
on what is happening
Gálvez's efforts as he moves
towards Pensacola.
- On his way there, Gálvez lost
more than half of his troops
to a hurricane.
Then several of his officers
refused to cross
a shallow channel
to get to shore.
- He stood up in the prow
of his ship and stated,
"I alone will take Pensacola."
The rest of the ships followed
after this display of courage,
and the siege
of Pensacola began.
- The Battle of Pensacola
lasted two months,
one of the longest conflicts
in the American Revolution.
- And in taking Pensacola,
this was the big prize.
He effectively
shut down anything
that could have happened
from the British front
along the Gulf Coast
of the Mississippi.
He was brilliant.
- The siege of Pensacola
was a decisive battle,
as it made it impossible
for the British
to attack from the rear
any of the 13 colonies.
- I think had there not been
the protection from the rear,
that Washington would've had
a much harder uphill climb
in what he was doing
on the Atlantic seaboard.
So yes, I think that this was
a pivotal event
in the American fight
for independence.
- The importance of that battle
has not been fully acknowledged
in textbooks.
The siege not only kept
the British occupied
on a second front,
but also affected
the number of troops and ships
the British sent
just two months
later to Yorktown,
the final battle
in the War of Independence.
- And after the loss of Yorktown,
the British recognize
there's no way back from this.
"We have enough power
to defend the West Indies,
the sugar islands,
the Caribbean trade,
or to carry the war on
in America."
And it's a no-brainer.
- Back at that time,
sugar was the oil of the day.
Sugar afforded empire.
So the British West Indies
were the most crucial lands
in the British Empire
at this time,
so the number-one priority
of the British Empire
during the American Revolution
was not to allow the Revolution
to distract them to the point
that they could lose an island
down in the Caribbean
to the French or the Spanish.
- So they started to move
those people
into positions
outside West Florida,
outside the 13 colonies so they
can hold what they still have.
- East Florida became the haven
for thousands of loyalists
leaving the colonies.
- East Florida is designated
as a haven for refugees
from Charleston,
from anywhere
in the American South,
and 13,000 to 14,000 refugees
pour in.
- They migrated all over
the province,
setting onto estates
that had not yet been developed.
History books
have largely ignored
those thousands of
loyalist families forced
to leave their homes
at the end of the war.
But the recent discovery
of a shipwreck
off the coast of St. Augustine
paints a very human picture
of what those men, women,
and children experienced.
- You see these artifacts
and you can't help
but think about the people
who use these artifacts
and what a turbulent period
in their life this was.
- Chuck Meide is director of
the Lighthouse Archeological
Maritime Program,
also known as LAMP.
Meide and his team
believe this wreck
was transporting loyalists
from the fallen 13 colonies.
- Remember, these people
were living
through just perilous times.
War was raging around them.
They were about to
lose their country.
They had fought for king and
country, and now all of a sudden
they have to gather
their families up.
- What happened to these
people on their way
to the one last colony
that was still loyal to England?
- The story is also just
unfolding right beneath us
on the sea floor as we pick
it apart piece by piece.
♪♪
- It's a story that would take
these marine biologists
all the way to the British
National Archives in Kew.
- I came back from the archives
with more than 1,000 pages...
Correspondence, a list of ships.
So it just paints
a great picture for us
of what was going on.
- It's actually very interesting
because all of these logbooks
make note of the weather.
- Dr. Sam Turner is LAMP's
director of archaeology.
- And what that weather
data tells us
is that there was
a nor'easter brewing.
- It was New Year's Eve, 1782.
A fleet of 16 British ships
filled with refugees
from Charleston
was sitting off the coast
of St. Augustine
hoping to cross the bar.
They needed to get
into the harbor
before American
privateers attacked.
- Pirates were out there
trying to pick off ships.
And we know the very fleet
that our ship
was a member of was
being chased by privateers.
- Among the hundreds of documents
the pair combed through
was a diary of a German soldier
in the British Army.
- He describes his journey
down from Charleston.
He describes themselves
as being flung about pitilessly.
The shipmaster was very nervous
about crossing the bar.
- St. Augustine had a reputation
for being
the most dangerous inlet
of all the other British
colonies in North America.
And as they sailed in,
you could see
the wooden remains of shipwrecks
jutting out on either
side of the channel
where ships had been
lost before.
- "The chances of getting across
are terribly slim
and we're all
probably gonna die."
And there's wreckage everywhere.
It's all flung up on the beach,
half buried in the sand.
It's out on the bar.
- To add to the problem,
the British ships were far
too laden for a shallow inlet.
- When we look at some of these
tonnages, they're extreme.
335.
384.
365.
They are not gonna be able to
get across the bar
at St. Augustine.
- They knew like,
"This isn't the time to
try to get into St. Augustine.
We're gonna wait until
we have a better tide."
- And there's a nor'easter
blowing.
It's a recipe for disaster,
really.
- They are waiting offshore
and the captain
finally dares
to cross the sandbar...
bam!
The ship is run aground.
The surf is pounding
on the ship.
It's coming to pieces.
All of their possessions
are spilling out into the sea.
I mean, just within less than
a mile of safe refuge,
their hopes and dreams
are being dashed to pieces,
just like the ship that they
thought was their salvation.
- LAMP's divers have pulled up
a wide array of artifacts
from the storm wreck,
including a flintlock pistol,
two loaded Brown Bess
muskets, six canons,
and the intact ship's bell.
But the most remarkable
artifact was one that
instantly transported Meide
back to the final moments
of the ship's demise.
- The visibility was zero,
as it usually is
offshore St. Augustine,
so we're really in the dark
just feeling this object.
And it was round,
and I could feel a lip to it
and put my hands inside,
and then I realized what it was.
- It was a cooking pot,
which led the archeologists
to a chilling revelation.
- In one of these cooking pots,
one of these iron cauldrons,
we had the remains
of the last meal
that was prepared in that pot.
This is something that has
not seen daylight in,
as it turns out, 228 years.
So that's a pretty
special thing.
I mean, you're the first
person to touch it.
The last person to touch it
did so under very different
circumstances,
probably in those
chaotic moments
in the middle of this tragedy,
when the ship was wrecking and
was going to be lost forever.
- A year after the last
of these loyalists
arrived in St. Augustine,
the Revolutionary War was over.
The British period in Florida
had lasted merely 20 years.
- "What shall become of
the thousands of poor loyalist
settlers who are now here
and were just made
comfortable and happy,
astonished by the crops
in the ground?"
- In the short time
the English had been there,
the loyalists had
turned a barren land
into a viable trade area.
But they were about
to lose it all.
As a reward for Spain's
contributions
to the American cause,
East and West Florida became
Spanish territory once again.
Among those chosen to draft
the Second Treaty of Paris,
ending the Revolutionary War,
was Bernardo de Gálvez,
the Spanish hero
who had defeated
British troops
along the Gulf Coast.
And now that the territory
was back in Spanish possession,
many of those survivors
who had fled to Cuba
to escape British rule returned.
Most of them were just children
when they'd left.
- They're sending back certified
copies of deeds to prove
that they owned property in
St. Augustine in the 1760s.
- But even though
the British were gone,
slavery in the new
United States remained.
Runaway slaves began heading
to Spanish Florida again,
hoping for asylum.
- And Thomas Jefferson
is our Secretary of State,
and he writes to the Spanish
government and says,
"If you still want
to be friends with us,
you will shut down this
sanctuary and this policy."
Spain agrees.
Spain is under a lot
of duress at this point.
Rebellions all over
its wide empire.
- So in 1790, Spain reversed
its century-old edict
offering sanctuary
for runaway slaves.
- They have to post announcements
everywhere that
"no longer will we receive
and free runaway slaves."
The royal policy was now
officially closed
thanks to Thomas Jefferson.
- But that didn't stop
the animosity
between Spanish-owned Florida
and its American neighbors
to the north.
Slaves still ran south,
but this time they sought refuge
with Seminole Indians in the
backwoods of Spanish Florida.
- The reason that the people
became known as Black Seminoles
was because they were allies.
- South Georgia
plantation owners later
claimed over $5 million
worth of slave property
was lost during this time.
They sent bounty hunters
to get them back.
- And most of the time,
their autonomous communities
were formed in very
inhospitable areas,
in swamps, where it was
difficult for the slave catcher
to come and get them again.
- Adding to the tensions
with the United States,
the Spanish began
offering inducements
to move to its colonies.
- You know, no taxes,
fair amount of land.
Originally they wanted people
to convert to Catholicism.
That was a stopping point
for many people
that were Protestant by faith.
But they dropped that provision.
They said, "No, all you have
to do is you have to take
an oath of loyalty to the King,
the Spanish King."
- For those who doubted
the United States would succeed,
it was an attractive offer,
particularly for
British loyalists
who had lost their land
during the war.
- Their business was commerce,
their business was planting,
and they wanted land again.
- The increased revenue that
Florida was enjoying from trade
with Europe
also stirred resentment.
- Florida was trading like
wildfire with Great Britain.
And that angered a lot
of the Georgians.
They were like,
"If you look at the Spanish side
of the St. Marys River,
it's all full of British ships.
And if you look at
our side of the St. Marys River,
there's nobody."
- Moreover, Americans worried
that their southern-most border
was not well protected.
- The St. Marys River
that divides Georgia and Florida
today,
that was an international
border at the time.
You were in one country
on one side,
a different country
on the other side.
In the late 1700s and 1800s,
you couldn't stop people
from coming in
and out of Florida or Georgia.
And sometimes they were coming
to seek revenge on someone
they had a long-standing
grudge against.
So that whole area was almost
like a no man's land.
Georgians raided
and Floridians raided back.
- It was a time
of complete lawlessness.
- I think Florida was always
the Wild, Wild West.
I think we could've
taught the West
how to be the Wild, Wild West.
- And the beginning of the 19th
century brought more trouble.
In 1800, Spain lost Louisiana,
which bordered the Florida
colonies to the West.
It remained a French colony
until Louisiana was purchased
by the United States
three years later.
On the world stage,
the Battle of Trafalgar
destroyed much of Spain's navy.
The Napoleonic Wars
took a devastating toll,
throwing the country
into an era of turbulence.
Spain could not send
much aid to its colonies.
The volatile tensions
between the U.S.
and Spanish Florida
came to a head
just before the War of 1812.
As America was preparing
to declare war
over trade restrictions,
they feared that the British,
now allies with Spain,
would stage troops
in St. Augustine.
- So we need to seize
these Spanish port towns
now before we have the British
navy sailing into them.
- Many Americans felt it was time
to seize the territory
for the United States.
Former Georgia governor
George Mathews
created a private army
and headed to Florida.
He called his troops
the Patriots.
In March 1812, this force
of more than 200 men
seized the East Florida port
of Fernandina on Amelia Island.
- This insurgent group moves
in and the very next day,
they raise the American flag
and they ask the American Army
and the American Marines
to come take control
of the town,
which they do.
- It was known as
the Patriot War,
and it's one of the most
overlooked events
in early 19th century history.
With Fernandina secured,
the Patriots headed south
to capture St. Augustine.
- So by April, there's actually
an American force
just north of town,
up where Fort Mose used to be.
And when they get there,
the Madison government retracts,
quickly, any support
for what they're doing.
- News of the Patriots' move
against Spanish Florida
took the Madison administration
by surprise.
Military preparations for war
had been focused
on the northern border
with Canada,
not the southern one.
President Madison did not
want to provoke Spain.
He refused to publicly
support the seizure.
- But the U.S. government
does not make a move
to pull the troops out.
- The American troops were told
to hold their position,
avoid a confrontation,
and defend if attacked.
Inside the Castillo,
Governor Sebastián Kindelán
gave similar orders.
- "Don't attack the Americans.
Because if you inflict
an injury on those troops,
there will be 10,000 more troops
coming down for vengeance."
- It was a standoff.
Unable to capture St. Augustine,
the Americans tried
to starve out its population.
- American officers were
given the instructions
to kill the cattle.
Because that way, Spanish forces
can't drive them into town
and use them for food.
And people said that
for miles around St. Augustine,
there was just a stench
of dead, rotting animals,
and that everywhere you went,
you saw dead cattle lying on
the banks of the various rivers.
- Meanwhile, the Patriots looted
and burned the homes
of anyone sympathetic
to Spanish rule.
- And so the destruction
all around this area
was just unbelievable.
- Incensed by the destruction
throughout the area,
the Seminoles and Black
Seminoles took up arms.
They stormed the plantations
occupied by the Georgia Patriots
and destroyed them,
liberating hundreds
of plantation slaves
who then joined their ranks.
But the people of St. Augustine
were barely holding on.
- The Governor is actually
counting down the days
to when he will
have no more food
and no real chance of survival.
And ironically, what breaks that
is a very small contingent
of men from St. Augustine,
all free blacks.
- It was a militia of
about 60 free blacks,
led by a 6' carpenter
and former slave known
as "Big Prince" Whitten.
- Prince Whitten was a slave and
who became kind of a war hero.
- He was the leader
of the free black militia
in the later period.
- He and his family had escaped
from St. Marys, Georgia,
four times before they
successfully made it to Florida.
They had been granted freedom
just two years before
the Spanish stopped giving
sanctuary to runaway slaves.
- But this family takes
on a very important role,
including beating the U.S.
Marines in a covert operation.
- It's the black militia that
goes out on a raiding party,
realizes that
the American troops
are almost in the same shape.
They're hungry, too.
'Cause they're not getting a lot
of supplies down from Georgia.
- The black militia, along
with a band of Seminoles,
lay in wait at a place
called Twelve Mile Swamp.
When American troops send out
a convoy to get supplies,
Whitten and his men ambush them.
- And pin them down,
seize the wagons,
and force them
basically to turn back
or to flee for safety
to the St. Johns River.
And the American commander,
when he finds out
that that has happened,
retreats.
- It was another victory
for the people of Florida,
but it would be the final
victory for Spanish Florida.
The attack at Twelve Mile Swamp
only fueled America's anger.
Newspapers and politicians
in the Southern states
called for these Native and
black militias to be punished.
- They could not have
blacks with guns
and giving hope to
people on plantations
that they too could join them
and get their freedom.
- After Seminoles ambushed
another American supply convoy
a few years later,
General Andrew Jackson
led a retaliatory attack
known as the First Seminole War.
It was 1818.
Meanwhile, the entire Spanish
Empire had been collapsing.
Major colonies were
declaring independence
and breaking away from Spain.
- So, you have, during
the Second Spanish Period,
the complete and utter collapse
of the Spanish New World Empire.
Argentina has gone its way.
Peru has gone its own way.
Mexico gains its independence.
- No longer a dominant
European power,
Spain could not
keep its territory
from constant conflict.
Secretary of State
John Quincy Adams
demanded that Spain either
control its Florida colonies
and their defiance
on the issue of slavery
or cede the territory
to the United States.
- All the trouble that came
from the War of 1812
destabilized the area so much,
I think it made
the acquisition of Florida...
The transfer of Florida
to the United States,
I think it made it inevitable.
- In February 1821,
the Adams-Onís Treaty
made Florida
a territory
of the United States.
- When the Spanish gave
up Florida in 1821,
almost immediately the Americans
begin to turn
to the problem of Indians
and how to get them out.
The 1820s is a period
of extreme racism
against American Indians
in the South.
- The Native population that
had thrived in the region
for 12,000 years
before the Europeans arrived
was now nearly extinct.
A small remaining group
of Apalachees
migrated to Louisiana.
The Yamasees, who had long been
believed to be extinct,
had scattered throughout Florida
and South Carolina to survive.
- To be Indian in Florida
was dangerous,
so they would hide themselves.
- We went back to
our traditional ways
of hiding our women and children
because we saw that they valued
the women and children.
- So that's where the swamp
became our friends.
But it kept us alive,
and it kept us here today.
- And we'll see moments
in the 19th century
as white Americans are trying
to make all Indians extinct,
that they begin to say,
you know, we see here
the last of the Yamasees.
So it leads to this notion
that they are gone,
that they have become
conquered, right?
But they didn't.
- So we became known
as the hidden people
because that's what we did.
We hid mostly
amongst other tribes.
A lot of us have been
identified as Cherokee.
Some of us identified
as Seminoles.
- Andrew Jackson was appointed
Governor of the territory.
The U.S. began efforts to
relocate the Seminole Indians,
eventually to
present-day Oklahoma
where other Southeastern
tribes had already gone.
- They are removed through
deception, through force,
into Oklahoma,
and then several hundred,
probably 250 or 300 Seminoles,
will not go and they will
hide out in the Everglades
and they will stay there
until the early 20th century,
sort of withdrawn
from American society
because they distrust
them so much,
and they will create their own
communities in the Everglades.
- And as for the hundreds
of escaped slaves
known as the Black Seminoles,
most of them fled
to the Bahamas.
- Prince Whitten leads
the next exodus in 1821,
when the United States
is gonna take Florida.
And he leads his
community into exile.
- Because the United States
brought their form of slavery
and ideas about black people
right down into Florida.
- For the second time,
the once-thriving free black
and Native communities
of Spanish Florida
disappeared from the landscape,
and from American history.
♪♪
- Just because they moved away
doesn't mean
they were never here at all.
- M y nation continues as long as
I keep telling these stories
and keep telling our
histories to our people.
The purpose of my life
is to continue these stories
and continue to tell the history
of the Yamasee people,
that we're still here.
- They did not kill us.
They did not kill us.
♪♪
- It will take until the year
2055 before the American flag
will have flown over
the first permanent settlement
in the United States
as long as the Spanish flag
flew over it.
- We as Americans
kind of inherited
the English version
of this story,
and so we didn't really
get the full story.
- I think it's the time
that we put in the minds
and in the hearts
of the American people
and the Spanish people
that we went along
for a huge period of time.
That makes us brothers
in terms of history, no?
- St. Augustine really is a
microcosm of U.S. history,
when you think about it.
I mean, you have the Native
Americans, you have the Spanish,
you have the British,
you have the Americans...
This whole cornucopia
of differences
that occur in this
one small area
that measures probably no more
than 10 square miles in area.
- This is how America started.
- I think that if
we could project St. Augustine
as an example of what
the United States started as,
then I think that would create
a whole different atmosphere
in this country.
- We're looking at questions
of race, religion, diversity.
I think it’s very important
to recognize that
at a certain period of time
in American history,
there was a place where
different groups came together
and were able to live
with each other despite,
or because of, their
incredible diversity.
- It wasn't always
easy and peaceful,
but multiculturalism
has been part of the U.S.
for a long time.
- Will school kids
in Boston and Virginia
learn about the Spanish
who were here before the other
Founding Fathers we know of?
I don't know.
That remains to be seen.
- I would like the rest
of the United States
to accept it as part
of the history,
as a part of the credible,
believable history,
that it belongs in the history.
It's not an anomaly like,
"Oh, that's Spanish."
- As the very base of it,
it's a pretty good story.
It has all these great
implications for, wow,
this is a history that we've
forgotten or under-appreciated,
but, man, at the foundation
of it, it's just a great story.
- It's good to have a narrative
of persistence, you know?
We will survive.
We will be strong.
We will have problems.
We may even have our towns
burned down from time to time,
but we will rebuild
and we will carry on.
That's a powerful story
for any country to have.
It's a powerful narrative.
♪♪