Long ago, two friends took part
in an incredible race.
They tied and together won first prize,
a red dune buggy with a yellow soft top.
Since they didn't want to share it,
they had
a beer and sausage eating contest for it.
But then, a bad guy
who was terrorizing the neighborhood
destroyed the bar where they were eating
and set the dune buggy on fire.
Huh!
So the two friends got mad,
and after smacks and slaps,
punches and blows,
eventually, the bad guy bought them
two brand-new dune buggies.
One for each of them.
Both red with a yellow soft top.
But then, one of the dune buggies
caught fire, leaving only one left.
And since sharing it
was completely out of the question,
our two heroes kept fighting
over the last remaining dune buggy.
You're always so stubborn.
It's all your fault.
You know as well as I do
that's not true.
You crashed into me.
I crashed into you...
I was only distracted for one second.
- Staring at that girl.
- What girl?
Nobody's leaving here
until this is settled.
Fine.
Let's settle it with a game of cards.
You'll cheat.
Let's arm-wrestle instead.
Now you're offending me.
What,
am I too strong for you?
Yeah, right! You wish.
How about we do the usual?
Beer and sausages?
No, not this time.
Let's have a race.
A race?
You must really want to lose.
If a car
hadn't crashed into me, I would've won.
Dad, how much longer?
Not right now!
And don't you dare touch the car!
- You're always coming up with excuses.
- You are.
- No, you are.
- No.
Hey! Hey, come here!
This is a dune buggy.
74 cubic inch engine, 41 horsepower.
It goes over 85 miles per hour.
Does it?
What are you doing? Scram!
- Or what, bro?
- Or else Dad will get mad.
He's already mad.
And besides, this buggy
doesn't even belong to us.
"This buggy doesn't even belong to us."
Don't mock me like that!
- "Don't mock me like that."
- Stop! I mean it.
"Stop! I mean it."
Whoa!
You can drive the buggy first.
Hey, where are you going?
Come back!
I told you not to touch it!
I'm gonna kill them.
I wouldn't stop.
- What if it were me?
- Do I have to answer?
Thanks, guys.
We ran out of gas.
Hey, nice car.
Aren't you a little too young
to be driving?
And aren't you ashamed that
you're driving around in that clunker?
Hey, my bike's name is Bolt.
And no one can bad-mouth Bolt.
Can I take it for a ride?
- No.
- Yeah.
How does this sound?
If you win, uh, Bolt's yours.
What are we supposed to do
with a two-speed?
- Shh. Let him finish.
- Get off me.
And if I win,
you let me go for a spin. Deal?
- No.
- It's a deal!
Here's the rules. The Virgin Mary wins,
St. Anthony, St. Januarius lose.
Example.
- Are you even watching?
- Shh!
This loses.
This wins.
Saint Anthony loses.
This loses or wins? Forgot.
This wins.
Now pick out Mary.
I'm afraid that you lose.
Yeah! Nice...
Dealer always wins.
You weren't even watching!
He'll be back.
Any second.
MANY YEARS LATER
STROKE
Aw, good doggy.
Hi. Ooh, doggy.
Hey, karasho.
Be happy you have a friend, huh? Cutie.
Come, Geremia.
My goodness, so grumpy.
What a bear!
- How much?
- It'll be fifty.
Fifty?
Mm-hmm.
You thief.
I'm the thief?
Here, just take it.
Fifty.
The Cobras.
Yo, it's the Cobras! Hey!
Hey, they're back!
- The Cobras!
- Run!
No, no, no.
Whoa!
WOLAND CIRCUS
Watch out!
CRAZY 4 RALLY
FIRST PRIZE: DUNE BUGGY
Where are you going?
Let go!
Mm-hmm.
- I appreciate a woman with fire.
- That so?
Mm-hmm.
Did you tell your boyfriend?
I'll give you two days to sign
and get out of here.
Torsillo has run out of patience!
Two days!
Two!
Hey.
You hear what I said?
Yo, fatso. Am I getting through, huh?
Bust him up, Scaglione!
Let me go.
Huh?
Now he'll clobber him.
Crush him!
Where are you going?
I'll get my money next time.
Ahh! Get off me!
Hey! Where are you going, coward?
Get your hands off me!
Hey, thanks.
You can, uh, drop me off right here!
- Ow!
- Thought you could cheat us?
Ow!
You're dead next time!
SMILEY
Hmm.
Ta-da!
Huh?
I'm doing swell. Yourself?
Not even a hug?
Get over here!
Okay, fine. I get it.
You don't want to talk to me.
You've seen this. Huh?
Together, we can get it back. Me and you!
Yeah?
What do you say? Hmm?
Ow!
What the hell?
That's how it's gonna be?
Fine, I'll win it on my own!
When I win, you're getting nothing.
It's gonna be all mine!
You'll see, I'm gonna keep it!
Good morning, Vietnam!
And welcome to the Crazy 4 Rally!
A cutthroat race.
A blaze of insanity,
gas, and testosterone.
How pumped up are you folks?
And let's not forget what brings us here.
Ladies and gentlemen,
a man who needs no introduction.
A man who has been blessed
with the divine gift of charisma.
A man so handsome
that when he looks in the mirror,
he kisses his own mouth!
What the hell is this?
So let's hear the heartiest applause
for Flavio Torsillo!
That's enough of that.
- Hey. Looking strong.
- Hey.
- Good luck to you. Best man wins.
My Lord!
Hey. Break a leg!
Huh?
- Yo! Yo! All right?
- Hey.
And if you thought this race
couldn't get any better, it just did,
thanks to this amazing prize,
a sensational 1974 dune buggy!
Who will win?
Who will be the most reckless driver?
So are we ready to get this thing started?
In five...
...and four...
...and three,
two,
one!
Go!
Come on, come on, come on!
Come on.
♪ You're always leavin' me alone
She don't care ♪
♪ I'm through with messin' around
She's not there ♪
♪ If you've got a lady friend... ♪
Eat my dust!
Whoo!
♪ So come on ♪
♪ Yeah! Come on ♪
♪ Come on ♪
♪ You're gonna get what you need ♪
♪ Gonna get what you need ♪
♪ Gonna get what you... ♪
Who's going crazy?
♪ ...get what you need
Gonna get what you need... ♪
Perfect! That's what I'm talking about!
♪ Now I'm in a rockin' band
She's not there ♪
♪ No one has to hold my hand ♪
♪ You're gonna get what you need ♪
♪ Gonna get what you need ♪
♪ Gonna get what you need... ♪
It's stuck! It's stuck!
He's done for.
Scaglione, let's go.
- Hey, what about your son?
- Forget him.
Put your hat on. Open the door.
Hey! Come on! Quit it!
Holy cow!
I don't believe it! What a twist, folks!
Looks like the car's rolled over,
and I can't see the drivers.
Damn it.
There they are!
They're gonna finish the race by running!
It's the first race without cars!
And without any people watching!
I'm the only one left.
Unfair shouldering!
Only a few meters to go!
There they are, folks, on the homestretch!
And they've done it, folks!
Mine!
Champions! Champions!
Champions! Oh my!
So tell me, just how does it feel
to win a 1974 dune buggy?
That's it! Yes, it is!
That's the true spirit!
So I don't want to be the one
to ruin your excitement.
But I'm gonna go get the champagne.
Champions! Champions!
Whoa!
Well-done. Keep it going.
Everything was set.
The cars were all identical.
Mine was souped-up.
I have no idea how I lost.
What's that?
- That the cars were all the same.
- No, after that.
I just said, uh, mine was souped.
After.
After, um...
Uh, what was it, Dad?
Now, listen. It might have looked
like you lost the race.
But it's just an impression.
No. Look, Dad, I really lost out there.
You were there too.
In a race,
it's not about fairness.
Only winning matters.
A Torsillo never accepts defeat.
But that's why we always win.
Come. Follow me. Come.
Who cares if they have the car?
Just go there and take it.
Right.
But they're not just gonna give it to me.
You can't just go there and be like,
"Excuse me, please give me the car." Huh?
Mention the name Torsillo,
and they'll shit their pants.
After all, it's more fun to get something
when you don't deserve it!
"Torsillo."
See, Raniero, your father here
was in a similar position.
He wants that land. They won't let it go.
And believe me, I know.
It is theirs, after all.
And so what should dad say?
My feet, I can't feel them.
No, really, Alfredo. Of course,
you've been there for freaking two hours.
You should accept already,
before your brain freezes too, eh?
It's not for sale.
That's my home.
I said I want a clean job,
and so I want a clean job.
- Yes, sir.
I'll have to throw away the meat
if he contaminates it with his bacteria.
- You know?
- Yes, sir.
Hey.
Sorry.
- The cold air.
- Why do I get this always?
Tell me. Close it.
No. No, no, no, no. No!
Ow!
Why would you do that?
I just wanna drive, you know?
Why?
Because until we settle the matter, yeah,
the buggy is staying right here.
- Oh yeah?
- Oh yeah.
Hey, you know if I want,
I can take it without the keys, right?
- I see.
- Mm-hmm.
All right, then.
Hold up. Hold up.
You find the joker, the buggy's yours.
I'm not falling for that.
- Piss off there, buddy.
- I could be offended by that.
Or what if we settled it
like we did in the past?
- Like in the past?
- Mm-hmm.
I'm on a diet.
Uh... One second.
Okay, I... I get it.
- But what kind of diet?
- Dissociated.
- Ah, now I see.
- Mmm.
When did you last clean here?
This place could use the touch of a woman.
You got a girl now?
- Geremia, it's ready!
- No, I mean, besides Geremia.
- Okay. I'm in.
- Hmm.
- Like in the past, yeah?
- Mm-hmm.
As long as you keep quiet and be still.
Okay. But I'll drive us.
Ugh, they came back again.
Those damn Cobras.
Ah.
You really changed up the place.
What'll it be?
Ah, let's see now...
20 pints and 20 sausages, yeah?
Uh, 40 sausages.
- Mmm.
- And a vanilla ice cream. Thank you.
Cleanses the palate.
Miriam.
Karasho!
Of course, they trashed everything.
They trashed the circus,
and you're here munching on hot dogs?
Would you look at me? Yo!
You're worse than the Cobras.
I don't wanna see you.
What are you looking at?
You must be a robber.
- How dare you!
- Mm-hmm.
'Cause my heart has been stolen.
I don't believe it. Okay?
- Talking romance?
- Mm-hmm.
- I'd sooner die.
- Okay.
- That's the mother of my children.
- Mm-hmm.
I need a break.
The heart wants what the heart wants.
Plus, you've got something on your... Hey!
Well, if you quit, then I win. Okay?
I'll be a minute. Gotta get my heart back.
I don't believe it.
I had nothing to do with this.
Hey, can't you hit another spot?
- Where is it?
- No clue.
I can imagine they stole her.
MIRIAM - SORAYA THE TIGER
WOLAND CIRCUS
Good girl.
In position.
Soraya.
Here.
Good. Good.
Now roll.
She's amazing.
And now up.
Good girl!
- I don't know. I smell a rat.
- Hmm?
The other side.
- good.
- I think it's the camel.
Don't worry.
I'm pretty sure we can barter
with these folks.
I have a plan. Here.
I'll sort it out for you.
Good girl.
Uh, Stroke.
Soraya doesn't bite her meat
unless I cut it beforehand, huh?
That must be a nice cat. That's great.
- Can I feed you?
- No, no.
Cut it already.
Don't. But I still need it.
No, no, no, no.
- Cats love the flesh.
- That buggy you stole back there is mine.
- No. Ours.
- Repeat that.
- Yeah.
- We're not stealing from you.
No, no, no. No one's trying to say
you're thieves. No. No.
- Then get out of here.
- All right.
We have enough problems already.
Who can we talk to about it?
Armandino might know about it.
But I must warn you that...
...you'll need a translator.
Okay.
- This is Armandino, my cousin. Hmm?
- Mmm.
Not so little, huh?
For 50 bucks, I'll translate for you.
- Fifty?
- Sure, fifty.
Okay.
Mmm.
Armandi, come talk to these guys.
So, hey, Mr. Armandino. Um...
In no way do we have something
against your business as a thief.
Thanks.
But since you seem to be
a distinguished and reasonable person,
you'll understand why we want it back.
Mmm.
He's saying I'm really nice.
He's asking to bang me.
Tell him
if he wants to die, I'll sort that out.
- Tell him! Tell him!
- I'll tell him.
Look, my cousin is mortified
by what's happened.
He very much
more than more apologizes for it.
I know he's stolen your buggy,
but he's not giving it back.
- No give it back.
- No back.
- Won't give it to us.
- No?
- No.
- But please smile!
You don't want him thinking
you're disrespectful. Yeah?
- That's great.
- Mm-hmm. Come here.
Why's he smiling?
He says I'm cheap but worth it.
I think
we're getting played today.
Mm-hmm.
You're disrespecting me.
You're disrespecting my cousin!
Nobody talks about my cousin like that!
Nobody talks about my family like that!
He's saying,
"It belongs to me."
- "Me and only me."
- Me. Only me.
- Won't give it back!
- Mine!
- I just need to talk for a second.
- Sure.
He says, "Give me
the girl, or I'll tear you apart."
This is going nowhere.
Joseph, Mary, pizza, rabbit!
Fatty fatty, phone home.
Kara-karasho! Kara-karasho!
Fatty fatty?
Sorry, that's you.
There is no pain.
And now it's the tradition.
This is how we settle things.
Man enough? Come. Come, come.
Place your bets!
The first to fall, 25 bucks!
25 bucks, first to fall!
Place your bets. 25 bucks, first to fall.
No, no, no. No, no, no.
It's okay. It's okay.
It's... It's a warm-up.
Come on, get pumped. Go.
Like in
the American movie Over the Top!
Let's go!
No.
Such a cool space station.
Armandino?
Up, my love. Get up.
- Great, huh?
- I can't believe it.
- You're telling me you bet on...
- No.
- No?
No?
Ah!
Freeze, yeah?
I need to talk business with you.
If you don't let go,
I swear on your old skank
of a mother I'll smash your face in.
My mother's not old.
- It sure is nice here.
- Mmm.
You know,
I could get used to circus life.
No.
Why don't we make a pact?
You let me help you find your buggy,
you return the favor.
- Mmm.
- Hmm?
- Is the spitting thing really necessary?
- Necessary.
If it's necessary...
It was Raniero.
Torsillo's son.
I saw him with it at the bar.
His father's a very powerful man.
He has everything
but still wants more, yeah?
He wants to take your buggy.
And he wants to take our land now.
He paid the Cobras to threaten us.
Why don't you just leave then, you know?
Circus folk travel, don't they?
- No!
- Oh. No. Oh...
This is like home to us!
Five generations, we've lived here!
Man, you're sitting here
crying over a buggy
while this land belongs to me. Huh?
Hold on. Look at me.
It's not any old hunk of junk.
It belonged to my father.
Ah.
Looks like we're after the same thing.
I see. We want the same thing?
Thanks for the information.
Hey!
Never forget the pact. Okay?
Mm-hmm.
It's a pact.
- Torsillo sure is a megalomaniac.
- Look who's talking.
What's up?
Uh, maybe I should head home.
No, no, no. Don't leave me. Hold on.
I can't go in there alone.
- You're crucial to the plan.
- What plan?
- Mine.
- Exactly. It's yours.
You don't know Torsillo.
I don't trust circus folks.
- You're scared, huh?
- Yeah, so scared! Brr.
You know what? If you hadn't stopped
to help those guys when we were kids,
the buggy would still be ours!
Come again?
I said, if you hadn't stopped
to help those guys when we were little,
the buggy would still be ours.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
So who's the one who gambled it away,
you dirty little cheater!
"You dirty little cheater."
- I don't talk like that.
- "I don't talk like that."
- Stop it.
- Uh, "Stop it."
Uh, knew it was coming.
Again.
- You know what?
- Mm?
- I don't wanna fight, okay?
- Ha.
Okay. Okay.
I'll go alone. I'll go alone.
But if I find the buggy, it's mine.
What a shack! Hello.
Ah.
Go with this one. Trust me.
Folks,
I'm looking for Torsillo.
I wanted to bring my brother here,
but he's way too short-tempered.
I even told him,
"I think those are good people
in a place like that."
So, if anyone here
is the front man of this group,
step forward.
Could you let me go?
Okay, I'll stay here.
What do you need with Mr. Torsillo?
- Oh.
- You have a deal waiting for him too?
Very close.
- Huh?
- Very close.
The Torsillo Tower.
Boutiques, spas,
heavenly beaches, dancing,
all on land that costs virtually nothing.
With guaranteed building permits,
police who cooperate,
and willing to turn a blind eye
to money laundering.
Mr. Tanaka wants more info
on the property conveyance.
Minor details.
A couple residents
have yet to sign the documents,
but I assure you that
the local administration is on my side.
Mr. Tanaka.
If you don't like it, then get lost.
The door is right here.
Don't let it hit you on the way out. Okay?
Uh...
Oh my God, please...
Please excuse Raniero.
I know he seems like...
I know it's hard to believe,
but he's my only child.
Are you kidding?
Sorry, Pop. I thought
you wanted me to be meaner.
Of course. But with this group?
You know kids these...
He's young, and he's...
He's a real asshole.
And so,
will you tell me one last thing?
Sure.
- I know he hates motorcyclists.
- Who?
These are bad.
Hmm?
What is this, Scaglione?
Ah, I wouldn't wake him up.
Excuse me.
Sorry if we interrupted
your meeting,
but we have a little problem
to figure out.
Your boy has stolen my buggy.
Ah, pardon. Our buggy.
A red dune buggy
that has a nice yellow soft top.
Yes, exactly.
Please excuse me one moment.
We're fine here, thanks.
See, if you give back, uh,
our special buggy...
...we'll just leave and pretend
that this was just a big error.
- Forget it, Dad, let's give them...
- Hey!
Or what else will you do then?
- Or what would we do?
- Hmm...
Uh... I'm not so sure yet.
We're not sure yet. Hmm.
Normally, I'd have the pleasure
of slicing your throats.
But you're in luck,
because right now I'm in a meeting.
And now... now go before I change my mind.
And I'll make sure
that your car is back tomorrow at noon.
Ah.
Well...
I'll see you at the garage.
Oh, I forgot.
A very important thing.
- Mm!
- The circus people are never leaving.
Hmm? Mm. See you later. Appreciate it.
Shall I leave it open?
Who would really...
Hell of a time to find
good workers these days now.
Translate it.
Yikes.
Hey! Ah!
Ha!
Hmm.
I'm telling you,
you'll die young at this rate.
And you'll die tomorrow.
What's up with you?
If it's Torsillo or the circus
or that I stole the model,
fine! I'm sorry if I didn't tell you.
We were only there for the car, okay?
Ah, okay. See, but it's only because
of Miriam that we knew where it went.
- Oh yeah?
- Mm-hmm.
Tell you what. You think
you're the smartest guy on Earth,
but you're always first one
to get screwed, man.
I told you I was only 13 and young!
If you'd grown up,
you'd know you shouldn't make deals
with circus people.
They first take your finger...
There you go.
You brought my heart with you?
Mind if we talk?
You should've seen me.
I kicked the door open,
knocked some of them out.
And then I took the model,
put it under my arm,
and said to them,
"The circus people aren't leaving."
- Sounds pretty good, you know?
- Yes.
See, but the war isn't over.
Torsillo must understand
that this land is ours.
So I get it, but war sounds a bit extreme.
I mean, I only want my car back.
And then we'd...
not complicate things with us.
- I'll see ya.
- Hold on, dear.
See? I don't want
to complicate things either.
Hmm.
Mmm. Mmm.
What's up?
I'm waiting.
Huh? But it's midnight.
Yeah. You better sleep up.
Tomorrow, I think you'll have a long day.
- Me?
- Mm-hmm.
Why is that?
Because you're leaving.
Mmm.
Breakfast for ya?
A dune buggy that's red
with a yellow-colored soft top.
Uh-huh.
Yep.
- Oh yeah.
- That's her.
- It's her.
See? Told you.
Yeah. Look, look, look.
- Beauty, huh?
- Yeah.
- Look at the stripe.
- I'll say. Perfect beauty.
Eh, do you...
I remember it being, uh, a bit... bigger.
- No.
- No, huh?
- No, no.
Mr. Torsillo.
Thanks so much. It's perfect.
Thank you.
It's just that... there's
a gritty little scratch here on the top.
A bit of scratch remover
will do the trick, you know?
Scaglione, this time
I want them hurt for real. Come on.
Scratch remover?
It's her though.
- Oops.
- Yeah, come on, Raniero.
Thank you.
Start. Come on.
We made fucking fools of ourselves.
You asshole!
Come on, he's running!
- He's running!
- Come on! After him!
He's getting away!
Isn't this an adorable little pooch,
you know?
Very cute doggy.
Don't touch my Geremia!
How do you sleep at night?
What did that ugly man do to you?
That's my bike!
And so, Smiley and Stroke
became two unlikely heroes.
"The Cobras won't be a problem anymore,"
the smiley one said.
The Woland Circus and all the inhabitants
of Tortuga were safe.
Torsillo was defeated and forced to flee.
The Cobras were all destroyed,
and they all lived happily ever after.
The end.
What are you
talking about, Scaglione?
I'll decide when it ends.
That clear?
Please let me apologize.
Apologize?
I messed up, Dad, and I'm sorry.
You say you're sorry?
Never say that you're sorry!
A deadbeat says that. A little dog
with his tail between his legs,
peeing on the carpet says sorry. Yeah?
Are you listening to me?
Where's your head?
- On dogs.
- Ah!
We should get a little doggy.
Did you, uh... get hit in the face, huh?
What? No.
So do you suffer
from early-onset Alzheimer's?
But I was just thinking, it seems like,
if we give them their buggy to them,
well, they should stay away
and leave us alone...
No!
- Why not, Dad?
- 'Cause that car is yours!
Use it, sell it, destroy it, my son,
for all I care!
But first, you have to show
those two hicks who's in charge.
Do you get it?
I see what you're saying,
but why would I sell it?
You know how many times
I've asked you if you get it?
- Tons. Many.
- Tons, son. Tons, son.
But go play with the buggy now, yeah?
Nobody should have it but us.
Such an asshole.
Don't worry. That's how he is.
I'm treated like shit all the time too,
but it's just his way he shows his love.
I can be mean too, just so you know.
Yeah, but remember
that just because he's your father,
you don't have to follow
in this footsteps and be like him.
If you don't have it in you,
you don't.
Let me handle those two you-know-whats.
- Bring the Cobras and follow me.
- What are you doing?
I'll be mean.
I'll be so mean
that I'll even scare myself.
Raniero!
Raniero. Raniero!
Make sure you don't say stupid shit.
Gentlemen and ladies,
now welcome to Circus Woland!
And we're starting our show
with the one and only elephants!
- Bravo!
Miriam!
Not bad, huh?
Whoo!
All right now.
- Oh, stop it! I love you.
- Whoo!
Bravo!
- She hasn't done anything yet.
- Oh yeah, yeah.
And so,
a new, most perilous act at this circus,
the act of knife throwing.
But... I'll need one volunteer.
A fearless,
courageous man,
willing to risk his own life.
Me! Here, here, here.
An applause now.
You know what you're doing?
- My first time.
- You're kidding.
No.
You're not kidding?
- Scared of me?
- Uh...
So if you don't kill me,
let's marry.
- Hey!
- Mmm.
There's no way.
Bravo!
- You didn't kill me.
- You're not my star.
I'm not?
The buggy! Ha!
Oh yeah.
- Would you like your buggy back now?
- Uh-huh.
It's her.
- Oh!
- Let's see if it ignites, huh?
Hey!
No.
Do something!
The buggy!
Let's see...
- Now what?
- Let's go! Let's go!
- Drive to the ocean.
- To the garage.
- No!
- Salt water will rust it.
No! Ow!
Here! Take!
Take!
Go! Go!
I told you, Scaglione.
Gonna make myself scared.
You even scared me.
Well,
could've been worse.
Geremia.
Geremia!
Come here.
I'm sorry I left you alone.
You're burning, huh?
Perhaps there's still time
to help out Miriam.
Let's go.
I'm not going anywhere.
Excuse me?
"Excuse me?"
Who's helping me? Hmm?
No one.
So guess what?
I'm not helping either, especially you.
You've been screwing everything up
since you were five years old!
And now you're still doing it!
What do you think,
that with a smile and a few jokes,
you would fix everything? Hmm?
Well, listen.
You, I'm not pissed at. I'm pissed at me.
Because I always said yes
instead of saying no!
And now this time, it's gonna be no!
Okay. I took a gamble, and I lost.
So excuse me. Sorry.
Once and for all, I'm sorry.
But you were with me.
I didn't point a gun at your head.
So hold yourself accountable.
You keep your precious kart.
I've always hated it.
And I hate you!
My dear cousin.
Soraya the tiger disappeared.
Now what do we do?
So now what?
We'll find her.
Circus friends,
the game is simple.
Now pay very close attention.
The joker wins.
- Win.
- Aces lose.
- Okay.
- Okay, Armandino?
- The joker?
- Wins it!
- Aces?
- Lose.
Very good.
Let's begin.
This one.
This one?
Oh... Okay!
Hey, I beat ya!
Now do it again but slower.
Slow! Like a snail.
It got?
I got it.
All right, folks. Remember that...
- The joker...
- Wins it!
- Aces.
- Lose!
Oh.
Okay.
This one!
Yeah?
Ready...
Hey!
Yeah! I win again!
- Hey!
- What's wrong?
Ah. Oh.
I can explain. I can ex...
Son of a bunny!
I'm gonna kill you. I'm gonna punch you.
I can explain.
Hey.
Pardon, ma'am.
Yes.
I'm not giving you 50, though.
Shh.
It's not about the 50.
I think you're going the wrong way.
Torsillo's mansion's over there.
Also, I'd let him go.
Probably gonna need him.
Did you eat a four-leaf clover today?
Thank you.
Check it out.
I was thinking and...
Something's not quite right.
- It's not, eh?
- Nah.
Gotta get it soft top.
- All right. We always liked it yellow.
- Yeah.
- Hey, we liked it yellow.
- Yellow, yes.
'Cause now it's more... smoky?
- Smoky.
You think we tell him?
- We can tell him, yeah?
- We better get moving now.
Best get it moving now.
Karakasho!
- Karakasho!
- Yeah!
Karakasho!
Grab the money.
Come on, let's go car.
Karakasho.
Thank you.
Thank you all for being here.
Oh, thanks.
Let's go.
Dear friends and business partners,
I'm elated to see you here today
on such an important day.
As you know,
the flames have burned strong all night.
But from this tragedy
has arisen a great opportunity.
On the one hand, we weep
for the terrible fire
that destroyed Circus Woland.
Alas though, how amazing will it be
when the concrete starts to flow
from our trucks
on this incredible...
Yo!
Uh... Where was I? A glitch in the program.
What was I saying?
Before the interruption,
you were saying, "On this..."
But I don't know what...
So on the one hand,
we weep for the terrible fire
that destroyed the Woland Circus,
but on the other, how amazing will it be
when the concrete...
- You've already said...
- Concrete! Concrete!
Scaglione, go and fix it.
Mmm.
Mmm!
Ha!
No, no, no, no, no, no!
How could you do this?
Uh, yeah.
The buggy you gave us won't do.
Yep. Plus, the soft top's gone.
It looks strange.
- True.
- Right. It's not yellow.
- It's not yellow.
- Now we want a new one.
Or what else will you do?
Uh...
- Or else we...
- Or we...
Or else we'll get mad, you know?
Oh yeah? Well, I'd love to see it.
Hold!
Belly rabbit, all of it's yellow!
Whoo!
Huh?
Bastards! Come on!
Back off with your fucking...
Piss off!
It's not fucking Halloween.
Ha!
Boo!
I'll show them.
Torsillo!
You're finished, yeah?
Oh really?
Oh no!
It really works, Father.
So yeah.
This is the real end of our story.
The circus was rebuilt,
the circus people had their home back,
and for the citizens of Tortuga,
everything went back to normal.
Even the red dune buggy
with the yellow soft top
was returned to our heroes.
However, there was
one tiny unresolved issue to settle.
How do you do it?
I guess it's a family thing.
Mm-hmm.
Keys on the table.
Hmm?
Yo, don't be cheap.
I need your money now, all right?
I guess that's fair. Pay up.
Well...
- Good.
- Mmm.
- Hmm.
- After you.
Ready?
What the hell are you waiting for, huh?
Everyone start to countdown.
Heya, three, two, one!
Freeze!
Oh no.
Hey, my beloved circus burned
for that buggy.
We made a pact.
I'm playing too.
Oh no. This is between us, okay?
If he wins, and he won't...
- Hmm.
- ...then you guys sort it out.
Oh.
Best of luck, hot stuff.
Best of luck.
Bye, karasho.
So, ladies and gentlemen,
we are back for more of this!
Let's see who wants to sit
in big boy driver seat!
Ready to fight? Ready to fight?
Three, a-two, a-one!
No, no, no, no!
That woman.
Huh? Huh.
Hmm?
♪ Come with me for fun in my buggy ♪
♪ Come along
Let's go for the hell of it... ♪
Yes, indeed.
Like all great stories,
this one doesn't end either.
Most likely the dune buggy
will never really belong to anyone.
♪ I'll bet you anything ♪
♪ Now she's with me ♪
♪ There'll be no trouble ♪
♪ Troubles around ♪
♪ Bet you'll never ever get away ♪
♪ Never ever get away ♪
♪ Dune buggy ♪
♪ I feel like a king
I feel like a king in my buggy ♪
♪ Just the crown is missin'
But that's all right ♪
♪ Come on, people, come on my buggy ♪
♪ Come and feel the power
Of a starry night ♪
♪ I feel like a king in my buggy ♪
♪ Just the crown is missin'
But that's all right ♪
♪ Come on, people, come on my buggy ♪
♪ Come and feel the power
Of a starry night ♪
♪ I feel like a king in my buggy ♪
♪ Just the crown is missin'
But that's all right ♪
♪ I feel like a king in my buggy ♪
♪ Just the crown is missin'
But that's all right ♪
♪ Come on, people, come on my buggy ♪
♪ Come and feel the power
Of a starry night ♪
♪ I feel like a king in my buggy ♪
There, look what they did.
Everything is smashed and ruined.
Look at the state you're in.
The cat was on me.
I punched it on its head and butchered it.
But it doesn't end here.
Or else what will we do?
Or else we'll get mad, you know? We will.
We will!
Absolutely sure, though?
It's so defeating.
Action!
Go!
- I can't break it.
- Action!
Go!
Stop, I got burned.
Think I don't know you.
Again!
- You know what?
- Mmm?
- I'm not in the mood, okay?
- Fine.
Agh!
Me? Let me try DP.
- Start rolling.
- You again?
Uh, yeah.
The buggy you gave us is no good.
It has a few scratches on the side.
Yes, and plus,
it doesn't have its top.
We would like a new one.
Wait.
Or else what will you do?
- Or else we'll...
...get mad.
If I ever...
It really hurt me.
- Me too.
- And cut!
♪ You're back on the road... ♪
- Now!
- Bravo!
Why did you talk before I said...
Bravo!
So I thought...
And now, Circus Woland's
most dangerous performance...
- Oh, oh, my line.
- ...knife throwing.
I can't. I can't...
Or else what will you do?
Or else we'll...
Are you sure, though?
That's so defeating.
Look at this.
Come on, let's do another one.
Good. Tell me it's a good one.
Good.
Three, two, one!
In what sense?
♪ You are my only friend ♪
♪ I'll never let you down... ♪
Action.
Or else we'll...
Or else we'll get mad, you know?
We were one voice, one person.
♪ You are my only friend ♪
♪ I'll never let you down ♪
♪ You are my lonely friend ♪
♪ We won't hit the ground ♪
♪ You know ♪
♪ I know what's it all about ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ You know ♪
♪ I know they are all around ♪