(building clattering)
(machinery rumbling)
- Hey, come on, guys.
We don't have all day.
- [Charlie] Help, help.
Help me.
Help.
(eerie music)
Help me.
(suspenseful music)
Get 'em off me, get 'em off!
Help me, help me, Frank.
- Charlie, Charlie, you okay?
Stop!
(suspenseful music)
(tense orchestral music)
- [Tony] That's it out there,
Lakewood County, the
Las Vegas of tomorrow.
- Oh, well, that won't
be for some time though.
- Oh, no, practically overnight.
We voted to legalize gambling
here, they cast the die.
- To die or the dice?
(both chuckling)
- Whatever.
We're all scrambling to
carve our name on 'em.
- I really hope that I can help you
carve your name here, Tony.
- I'll drink to that.
To our first adventure together.
At last.
- Oh, the better hotels
would be across that lake over there,
behind that clump of rocks.
I uncovered three
properties that are for sale
in our range.
There's a hotel that's close to the lake
and the other two are inland.
The Lakewood Manor is
the one near the water.
Maybe we could spot it.
- Your hair was in my eyes.
(Tony chuckling)
Just wondering, what hotel are we in?
- Oh, I book rooms at the Romer.
ZZZ?
- What?
- Rooms?
Put it this way, we'll be
working more closely together
this week than ever before, right?
Right.
And away from home, things
could be a little different.
I was just hoping you might
have taken it upon yourself
to have booked just one.
- (sighs) I do not believe in
mixing business with pleasure.
Now, come on, Tony, let up.
- Oh, come on, Gloria, letdown.
This is our first trip together.
- I really wanna do a good job.
And I think it's best
that we keep things strictly-
- Business.
- Right.
Before pleasure.
(Gloria groans)
(light orchestral music)
(parrot squawking)
- That's not good for his diet.
Save it for yourself.
If Teddy were younger,
it would be all right.
But do you know that that
bird is 32 years old?
- Really?
- Really.
Your mother met him when
she was just about your age.
Marjorie.
- Mrs. Adams.
Oh, it's so good to see you.
Thank you for taking the
reservation on such short notice.
- Oh, nonsense.
We'll have room for you
and your family always.
- Sort of like coming home
every time I walk through the front door.
- Is your husband coming
down for the weekend?
- I'm not sure. Maybe.
- Mom, Dad's not coming here.
(light upbeat music)
- [Linda] Can I carve my initials too?
- (chuckles) I don't think so.
- Hey, come on. You don't
have to do that because me.
- No, no. That's okay.
- My name's Linda, Linda Howard.
- I'm Richard.
You staying here?
- Do you know, do they have any vacancies?
- They might.
- On.
(sighs) Well, you know
I'm not really looking.
I've been backpacking on
the road with a friend.
She went off with someone
she met down around the pier.
Didn't come back.
- Well.
- I'll be on my way.
You know, all I really
wanna do is take a shower
and maybe take a nap in a real live bed.
You think you can help me out?
- Oh, well, I, I mean,
I'd like to, I just-
- I wouldn't want you to get
in any trouble or anything, you know.
I just really need some
real civilization right now.
(machinery rumbling)
- Hey, Vince, you seen Frank?
- Yeah. About five minutes ago.
Heading towards the hotel.
- Ah, how many times have I told you guys.
(tense music)
(eerie music)
(spoon clattering)
(machinery rumbling)
- Now that construction next door
would be the new Versailles
Hotel, 119 rooms.
- Mm-hm. And a new gambling permit.
The license to steal
with all of America lining up
to kiss their dollars goodbye.
We're not staying here.
I have an appointment-
- Tony-
- What?
- This is marvelous.
Why don't we change our reservations?
- What do you mean?
- The 11th commandment.
Thou shalt not live in plastic, hm?
Why don't we see if they
have a vacancy, okay?
Terrific.
- You can go back to town.
Oh, by the way, it's
costing me by the hour
so don't stop for a beer.
Oh, would you tell Mrs. Adams
Anthony Fleming is here.
(people chattering)
- Mother, please try and be reasonable.
You said you'd meet him.
Didn't you promise?
- I know, but I just
can't, I can't see him.
- Mother, we've been talking
about this for so long.
I thought you'd made a
decision that you agreed.
- I should have the
right to change my mind.
I'm not perfect.
- Mr. Fleming.
My mother isn't feeling well
and well, I'm afraid
she won't be able to see you, right now.
- Oh, I see.
Well, then it's for best
we're staying in the hotel.
It'll facilitate our
meeting later today perhaps
when your mother's feeling better.
- Yes.
(parrot squawking)
You're not supposed to be in here.
- I'm looking for one of my men.
- I don't suppose it has occurred to you,
but this is a civilized,
respectable place.
You and your men coming
in here trumping dirty in
like a bunch of apes, using this bathroom
like you would a gas station.
- Anybody in here?
What's the matter, Val?
- (sighs) You're not supposed
to start work until 8:00.
- We didn't.
- Well, you had that big
engine going at 7:30.
- Hey, what's the matter?
- (sighs) Oh, Mike.
Mom's changed her mind again
about selling the hotel.
She won't even see the man.
- (sighs) Well, you got her this far.
Just keep trying.
- I've got to get her to slow down.
She just works so hard
keeping this place going.
(sighs) Well, then we can make our plans.
Okay-
- I wanna get it settled.
- Uh huh.
- I know it.
Ah, oh. Hi, Mr. Robinson.
Just checking the paper towels.
(people chattering)
(machinery rumbling)
- Frank show up yet?
- Nah, I ain't seen Charlie either.
Huh.
(tense orchestral music)
- Vince, get everybody fast. Cave-in.
And get some light in here.
- Hey, over here!
Over here, we got trouble!
- Hey, man.
- Somebody's been hurt said Vince.
Come on!
- Let's go!
- Hey, What's happening?
What's going on?
(men shouting)
- [Man 1] Let's dig 'em out.
- [Man 2] Get this porch off.
- [Man 3] Gimme a hand.
(men shouting)
- That's right, haul this stuff from here.
If dirt didn't pack,
they're in an air pocket,
they still have a chance.
- Hey, you guys, get some
shovels, get some shovels.
(men shouting)
(men grunting)
- [Mike] Ha, hey!
They're both here. Get 'em out.
- I told you you should wait
for just the right person.
I think this Mr. Fleming just might be it.
There's no real estate syndicate involved.
He's independent.
He wants to run the place
the way it always has been
and he seems to have the money.
- That's not what we're talking about.
- But it is what we're talking about, Mom.
Money and security.
- I can't face leaving.
I grew up right here.
So many things are part of my life.
That grandfather's clock out there.
I remember the day my mother
gave that to my father.
It was his birthday.
Stood there with a big
rose-colored blanket over it.
And when she pulled the blanket away,
his eyes filled with tears.
Then it chimed and they
both laughed together.
I remember he used to check
the time every morning
and set it.
- Mother, things change.
The pressures on you now are-
- NO.
Ralph and I ran Lakewood Manor
as it always was, personal
service, handsome rooms,
and what Ralph used to
call a delectable menu.
- Mom, Mike has been
offered a terrific job
in San Francisco.
I just can't see you here alone,
trying to keep this place going.
- I can manage.
- Look, if you sell,
you can make it a
condition of the contract
that there's always a room for you here.
That way you can still spend time here
and time with Mike and me in San Francisco
and with Aunt Margaret in Florida.
- Margaret snores. She always did.
Do you know that?
(door clattering)
(door slamming)
(people chattering)
- Yes, yes, a cave-in.
We need a rescue unit as fast as possible.
- What's wrong?
- Val, I've got two men dying out there.
Tell 'em where to send the ambulance.
- Oh no.
Yes, operator, 1123 Lake view.
- He ain't breathing, Mike.
- Oh, he's just a kid.
Keep working on him.
- Get him breathing?
(light knocking)
Yes?
- Ready for some lunch?
Smuggled it from right under their noses.
- Wow. Cucumber sandwiches.
- Right. Only the best.
(sirens blaring)
- Looks like an accident.
- Stay with him, will you?
- Right.
(brakes screeching)
- Hey-
Come on, down here.
- [Man] Okay, go-
- I wonder what happened.
- Makes me dizzy.
- What?
- Even from the third floor,
I'm allergic to heights.
No, it just kinda freaked me out.
- Close your eyes.
Feel better?
(gentle music)
I better get back.
- Richard.
(sighs) Listen, just for
the record I wanna tell you.
My friends didn't run off
and lose me or anything.
I just said that.
- Why?
- I wanted to get off
sleeping on the beach.
It got really weird and scary.
We heard stories about people
getting robbed and hurt.
I guess...
I just wanted somebody to...
who wanna just take me in.
(siren blaring)
- They figure Frank will make it.
- Yeah.
What were they doing down
there in the first place?
- Hey Mike, it wasn't my fault, okay?
- Sorry.
(machinery rumbling)
Vince, they must a had a reason.
- Yeah.
But what?
(tense music)
- Come on.
(eerie music)
- [Hospital Announcer] Dr.
Kline, paging Dr. Kline.
Telephone please, Dr. Kline.
(machine beeping)
- Nothing we can do here.
- All vital signs are deteriorating.
He stopped breathing.
- Nothing, nothing, nothing!
Lungs are good, no broken
ribs, no punctures.
He should be breathing on his own.
- Dr. Hawkins!
(machine beeping)
- Half a milligram of atropine fast.
We're dealing with a toxic
situation, nerve damage.
- [Hospital Announcer] Dr. Karo-
- You gonna call Frank's wife.
- You do it, huh?
- Come on.
- Just do it, I can't.
- You the family?
- No, but we're it for now.
- Charles Hooper.
We couldn't save him.
- Oh.
(people chattering)
- (sighs) What about Frank?
- He's not responding.
We don't know why.
Complications are confusing,
almost mysterious.
- [Hospital Announcer] Dr. Warner.
- Was there anything you'd say
was different in that hole?
- Like what?
- I don't know.
Some kind of gas, maybe
you severed a pipe?
- There was a drain pipe.
- Oh yeah, but that's just water
from the hotel kitchen, nothing else.
- Dr. Nylan, reception area.
- What about a snake?
Well, they're poisonous.
That could attack them.
- NO.
I mean, I don't think so.
- I'd suggest you
give it a closer look.
We're dealing with something here
I can't diagnose or treat.
- [Hospital Announcer]
Dr. Jones, surgery please.
Dr. Jones.
(eerie music)
(machinery rumbling)
(suspenseful music)
(Luis speaking in Spanish)
- Everybody has a soft spot.
You find it, you get what you want.
- You know, you might offer
her a place to stay here,
a chance to stay on for a while.
Mm-hm.
Well, I'm glad to see you got a mind too.
- Oh, thank you.
What was that you were saying
about everybody has a soft spot, hm?
Everybody?
- Uh huh.
- What's mine?
- Oh, um, a handsome man
who finds you exceedingly attractive
as well as intelligent.
- Oh really? (chuckles)
Come on, let's go get some sunshine.
You know you may be
making so much money soon
you'll never see it again.
(people chattering)
- You go find a spot and
I'll get the towels, okay?
- I've never been. Never been.
No, I've never been to Europe before.
I'd love to though, if
I ever get the chance.
- Hey sonny boy, when you're
through basting the chicken,
give us a hand, huh?
- What can I do for you?
- Two baloney sandwiches on rye!
What do you think, dammit?
Two lounge pads and towels, huh?
Been standing there for 10 minutes.
We'll be over there.
- Unbelievable.
I'd send him the baloney sandwiches.
- And I don't think it'd cure him.
- Mom, look! This place
is loaded with bottles.
All deposit free money.
This one's 15 cents.
By the time we go home, I'll be rich.
- Tommy, we're not taking these
home. Don't be ridiculous.
- I'm not, I'm not being ridiculous!
- All right.
(sighs) I'm sorry.
Tommy, you don't need to take these home.
You don't need them.
- I do. I need the money.
- I don't see what you need the money for.
- To take care of you
now that Dad's not living with us anymore.
- Hey, we will be fine.
Don't you worry.
But you go find all the bottles you want.
Hey!
Find some for me too, huh?
- You gonna tell the guys.
- They'll find out soon enough anyway.
- Why don't we just to
go home and get smashed
and forget about it?
- That's why.
Peggy Kenter, Board of Health.
(machinery rumbling)
- Michael McGinn is Carr.
This is Lionel White from the
State Department of Health.
- What's up, Peggy?
- After an industrial accident,
the law does require a
preliminary investigation.
Come on, Mike, don't play innocent.
- I am innocent. It was an accident.
- This where it happened?
- Here.
- No shoring?
Was it posted as dangerous?
- Yeah, we had a sign, "Danger Keep Out".
- Is that the sign?
- That's where it ended up.
I mean, see when we
were digging the men...
One of my men...
- Look, Mike, if you
can prove that your men
were not sent in there, then
you have no major problems.
- If you can't,
criminal negligence can cost
you more than a license.
- You wanna look around and
ask questions, go ahead.
Every man here will back up the fact
that this pit was off limits and posted.
Look around, ask questions,
and then beat it, please.
- Look, Mike, I didn't come
all the way over here for nothing.
I do have a job to do too.
You stop being your own worst enemy.
(tense orchestral music)
Come on, Lionel, let's
go question the men.
(people chattering)
(light suspenseful music)
(suspenseful music)
- Worms.
(Mike sighs)
Ants.
Sea shell.
Mike.
- Oh, hi.
- Hi.
- Don't come down here.
- Why? What are you doing?
- Doctor told me to look
for something down here.
- I just wanted to see you for a minute.
(suspenseful music)
I was worried about you.
Okay-
- Well, we heard one of
your men didn't make it.
I thought you might
wanna talk or something.
- Listen, Val, I'm glad you came over,
but I think you better
get back to the hotel.
- Yeah, sure, okay, Mike,
if you can't spend a minute with me
that's fine with me.
- Oh now, come on.
Don't pout.
- No, no, no.
- We're not even married yet.
(both chuckling)
- You know, things are
beginning to look better
in that department too.
Mom seems to be willing to sell.
- Good, good.
(tense music)
- Mom, Mom!
Mom, Mom!
Mom!
- Help him! Stop him, please!
He can't swim!
Tommy!
- [Man] Help him. Go help him!
Help him out. Pull him out!
(people chattering)
Hold onto him.
- Get some of those towels!
- Some towels.
- Is he all right?
(people chattering)
- [Man] What's going on?
- Call an ambulance.
Give us some light. We're
looking for something.
- [Man 1] Anybody know him?
- [Man 2] I saw him run across the side.
- [Marjorie] Oh man. Be cautious.
(somber music)
- [Man] Are you sure he'll live?
Is everything okay?
- Yes, sir.
- They're not sure the
boy's gonna make it.
- I was thinking of his mother.
She had such a wonderful
smile when she was a child.
- [Tony] Go on up to the
room. I'm gonna take my shot.
- Good luck.
- [Ethel] People don't
die without a reason.
The doctors know what it is,
they're just not telling.
- I don't know, Mom.
Did you take your medicine after lunch?
- Yes.
- -[Tony] Ladies.
(light knocking)
I'm not intruding.
- Mr. Fleming.
- I thought this might be a good time to-
- My mother...
- It's all right, Valerie.
I'm Ethel Adams.
- Very pleased to meet you.
- Won't you sit down?
- Thank you.
- My daughter seems to have faith in you.
- Well, it's very kind.
But to be very honest, I do
believe I'm the right person
to handle this property.
It's very special with
a character all its own.
I think one actually has to stay here
to really appreciate it.
- Well, we like to think
that it's the outgrowth
of the taste of our family
for almost a century.
- Right.
You can sense it the moment
to walk through the door,
such tradition, such faith in the past.
I know now's not the
time to talk seriously,
but I did wanna meet you, Mrs. Adams,
to tell you that in the world of plastic,
this hotel has a duty to survive,
to see the next century.
And of course there could
always be a place here for you
if you want, perhaps
on a consulting basis.
Well, enough for now.
When you want, you call me later
and we'll really talk.
- Fine, Mr. Fleming.
Well, I must say he's not
at all what I expected.
- No, he isn't.
- I feel much better about things.
- Just talked to the hospital.
Frank's holding on, so's the kid.
They're gonna make it.
- Boy, that's good news.
- Doctor still wants us
to check out the hole.
He thinks it's the same
thing that killed Charlie.
On his skin was evidence of rash
or irritation, something.
He's testing out everything.
He seems almost certain
that it's some kind of a virus.
He's following up on that.
(somber music)
It's attacked three people, killed one.
Vince, you know what
I'm beginning to think?
- What?
- Whatever it is,
it's mad because we've disturbed it.
The answer must be here.
It's got to be.
- Well, what if it can attack us?
- What if it can attack everybody?
(tense music)
- Gloria! Gloria!
I think she's gonna sell!
And I was terrific.
(Gloria squealing)
Oh, you too.
You really helped me, you did.
- On.
Ah, is it a partnership?
(Tony chuckles)
Oh.
- A partnership.
- [Gloria] Mm.
(somber orchestral music)
- Linda, all done.
You Okay?
- I'll never forget that boy's scream.
Needing help and there was
nothing anyone could do.
- Yeah.
(gentle music)
Listen, I'll be off in a couple hours.
Why don't we get outta here for a while?
Like the pier.
They got great chili there.
Okay-
Meanwhile, I think I'll
write my parents a letter.
Boy, this place is beautiful.
- Doctor asked about some kind of gas.
And maybe he's right.
Why not?
Some unexpected pocket or crevice.
It still doesn't explain the kid...
What's the matter?
- They're biting me.
- What do you mean?
- [Vince] They're biting me.
These ants are biting me.
Yeah, they hurt. They really hurt.
They're biting me.
(Vince grunts)
- Hey, hey, come on.
Come on. Here.
- On.
(Vince grunts)
Whew!
- You all right?
- Yeah, I think so.
(both exhale heavily)
- Hey-
Slowly.
(Vince grunting)
- I can't stand up.
- What do you mean?
- Well, my whole leg is numb. (exhales)
- Can you feel that?
(machinery rumbling)
I better call an ambulance.
- No, wait, wait.
I'm all right.
(tense music)
A little woozy.
Let me sit here a minute.
Oh.
(Vince sighs)
(tense music)
(Luis humming)
(chaotic eerie music)
(Luis grunting)
Help-
(dramatic eerie music)
- [Mike] You sure you're all right?
(Vince sighing)
- Yeah.
Little woozy.
You know, I felt the first bites
and then about five seconds later,
it hit me.
(suspenseful music)
(machinery rumbling)
- Luis.
They found him on the kitchen floor.
He's dead, Mike.
- Val, they'd like to talk to you.
- Look, I'm really very sorry,
but the kitchen will
have to be quarantined.
No one is to enter.
And I'm afraid all of
the guests in the hotel
will have to be evacuated
as soon as possible.
- Hey, hey, hey, you're blowing smoke.
You need a court order and to get it,
you have to show cause.
- Isn't one death all we need
and what happened to the boy?
Although the boy is recovering.
As to the precise cause,
we're not absolutely certain.
There's something mysterious here,
but rest assured we'll isolate the virus.
- I don't think you-
- We have been in contact
with the Infectious
Disease Center in Atlanta.
We're coordinating our efforts with theirs
and hope to be on top of the
situation in a matter of hours.
- I think I know what
the cause of all this is.
- Who have you been in touch with?
- Nobody. I figured it
out by what I've seen.
And this may sound crazy,
but well, it's what I believe.
Anyway, the problem is
ants, regular little ants
like right here.
(Lionel laughing)
- [Lionel] I don't know
what you're talking about.
That's ridiculous.
- [Mike] That's what I think
and I the-
- The cause of death
is a virus.
There's no doubt about that.
We hope to be
on top of the situation-
- Ants.
Little damn ants, buddy.
- In a matter of hours.
Have you been in the kitchen?
- No.
- That's where it started,
from a virus.
- Okay, then how do you explain
my men in a pit 80 yards away?
- Simple.
There's an old drain pipe
which runs from the sink here to a sump,
no doubt a hundred years old.
You severed that pipe with your machines,
the disease thus infested the soil
where your men were working,
they came in contact with
it, and were overcome.
" By What?
- By whatever it is.
- No, I've been in the pit,
so have a lot of my guys.
We're around and kicking.
So it isn't in the air.
It isn't in the ground.
We've touched everything,
even the pipe itself.
It's ants.
I don't know how, I don't know
why, but that's what it is.
My foreman was bitten by them.
He weighs over 200 pounds.
Nearly knocked him off his feet.
- If what you say is true-
- It is.
- Then we'll find ants in the kitchen.
- But we've always had ants.
- Of course, everybody does.
Ants are ants.
- Not these ants.
- After you.
Find me an ant.
(suspenseful music)
You see.
(tense music)
- (sighs) I don't care.
I still say here's your
mysterious disease.
- All right, if you want.
I hope this doesn't
embarrass you too much.
I'm still standing, Mr. Carr,
and I don't weigh 200 pounds.
Nothing.
- (stammers) I don't get it.
I don't understand why it
didn't happen just now,
but I know what I saw.
- And these ants are supposed
to have caused what happened?
It's a ridiculous theory, Mr. Carr.
It's not ants.
- One of my men is in
the hospital, Mr. White.
One's dead.
If it isn't ants, then there's
something else in that pit
and I'm gonna find out what it is.
- Mike, what are you gonna do?
- Test my theory and
hope to God I'm wrong.
(Lionel sighs)
May I?
I'll be back in an hour.
(machinery rumbling)
- Hey, Mike.
What you gonna do?
(loud thudding)
(machinery rumbling)
- Do you know what you're doing?
My great-grandfather built this hotel
a hundred years ago.
We have guests who've been coming here
for over half a century
and you're driving them away.
- And you don't really care, do you?
- I am sorry, Mrs. Adams.
We will please inform all the guests,
speedily and calmly that they must leave.
Some have heard, but some haven't.
I expect the building to be
empty and sealed by 5:00.
- In two hours?
- [Lionel] Two hours.
- [Peggy] Is it possible?
Could these things kill people?
- How can I know that, Peggy?
They've gotta be tested.
It takes hours, sometimes days.
- (sighs) Wait, Tom.
I mean, ants can't really poison people,
I mean, at least the ones
around here, can they?
- In Africa, there's a
poisonous specie of ant.
Here...
- Tom, all I'm asking is is it possible?
- Look, Peggy, I've got to
finish this test and do a report.
I don't have time
to sit here and talk with-
- But please just give me
the answer, Tom, all right?
Is it possible for those
ants to kill people?
(Tom sighs)
- 20 years ago the
answer would've been no.
That's before they started
pouring poisons in the air.
- You mean all that stuff
we kill insects with.
- Exactly.
The old way, arsenic, was
simple and unchangeable,
but the poisons today are so complicated
they could turn on us.
Anyway, we're the ones who forced them
to live in a toxic world.
Why should we be surprised if
they found a way to use it?
I've got something to show you. Come here.
(machinery rumbling)
This should give you some
idea of the possibilities.
Ample food and water will allow colonies
to prosper and grow to
massive proportions.
The average ant colony
numbers 20 to 50,000 members.
If for some reason this
colony were jostled
by an innocent passerby,
the ants would consider it an attack.
Retaliation would be immediate and severe.
- Uh.
- [Tom] A colony of ants
will attack creatures
far larger than themselves
only when they are certain
they have sufficient numbers
to overcome their prey.
Docile in small numbers,
when there are enough ants,
a mysterious chemical signal
sets off savage biting.
- I don't like it.
(machinery rumbling)
(tense music)
(eerie music)
(tense dramatic music)
(machinery rumbling)
- You know, if you
bought this hotel today,
we could stay here forever.
- Well, maybe I could afford it
if we sublet the other room.
- Zzz.
(both laughing)
(Tony sighs)
- If she sells.
- We might have told her
how special you thought this place was,
that might melt her.
- Well, what do you think
I told her, I hate it?
I pushed the right buttons.
- Hey, I was only trying to-
- Let me handle the business, okay?
- (scoffs) Oh, right, partner.
- I only meant that-
- What you meant was that the only partner
you really want is a bed partner.
- Oh, come on, Gloria.
Let's not be so touchy.
- You come on, Tony.
Why do you think I've been avoiding this?
Do you think I wanted
it any less than you?
- Yeah?
- Come out of the Middle Ages.
(sighs) This is the easy part.
Give me a little more
credit than that, okay?
Look beyond all the bumps
and you may see that there
is a head up here. (sighs)
- I may not see it, baby,
but I sure do hear it.
(Gloria chuckles)
- Partners, bed and otherwise?
- Especially otherwise.
(Gloria sighs)
- I really wish I could believe you.
- Trust me.
I'm gonna build the best
lakeside casino hotel
in the world right here.
- Oh, you're not gonna tear
this place down, are you?
- The week after they sign,
we're gonna clams hell it into firewood.
(wood clattering)
What was that?
- Mm, don't go.
- Oh, come on, I gotta see what that is.
(chaotic eerie music)
(phone ringing)
- Hello.
- Hello?
This is Ethel Adams, Mr. Fleming.
- [Tony] Yes, Mrs. Adams.
- I'm sure you know what's
occurring in the hotel.
- Yes, yes.
- Well, I had hoped to
continue our conversation,
but in view of what is
happening, I don't think we can.
- Well, sure we can, Mrs.
Adams, whatever the difficulty.
- Really? Are you sure?
- Of course, I'd still
love to talk to you.
- [Ethel] Well, there are some things
we could take into account.
The land itself and the
furnishings are worth quite a bit.
- Name your time, Mrs. Adams.
- Well, how about right now?
- Great.
- So I'll meet you in the music room?
- Good.
Good news.
(door creaking and thudding)
(machinery rumbling)
(dramatic tense music)
(chaotic eerie music)
- Do you have to go?
- Oh, absolutely.
It's time to close this deal.
Magic time.
- See you later.
Good luck.
(door creaking and thudding)
(chaotic eerie music)
(people chattering)
- We can't get a taxi up here.
I told Mrs. Car swell I'd
drive her to the airport.
- All right, Peter, but
hurry back, will you?
Okay-
- Richard.
Would you take over the desk?
I'm gonna see what Mike's doing out here.
(machinery rumbling)
(Valerie gasps)
(chaotic eerie music)
(tense music)
(eerie music)
(dramatic music)
(Gloria screaming)
' Help me!
Help me.
(machinery rumbling)
(suspenseful music)
(chaotic eerie music)
- What in god's name does
that maniac think he's doing?
- No, not that way!
- Oh!
(Lionel grunting)
(eerie music)
- (whistles) Hey, Vince!
No, no!
Listen, we don't have much time.
This whole area's infested with ants.
- Well, how are you
gonna get the people out?
- I'm gonna try to get
through in this loader.
Get Jerry with a digger
and cut a trench around
the pit and the hotel
and fill it with water.
We've gotta contain these
ants before they spread out.
- What about the people?
Can they get in that loader?
- Go, will ya? I'll be
lucky to get in with it.
The ants are climbing fast.
Call the police, the fire
department, everybody.
We need as much help as we can get.
- Right.
(machinery rumbling)
(brakes screeching)
(footsteps thudding)
(Tony panting)
(suspenseful music)
(tense music)
(glass shattering)
Mike.
Oh.
- We'll be okay.
- Mike, they're all around us.
My mother.
How are we gonna get her out?
- I don't know.
(machinery rumbling)
- I'm telling you, Tom, forget your test.
We don't need them.
These ants are carriers of poison.
- Okay look, what are they
doing to contain them?
- They're digging a
trench around the hotel.
They're gonna fill it with water.
- No, no, look, tell them ants can build
their own bridge across water.
Tell them they'd be better
off filling the trench
with gasoline and lighting it,
containment by fire.
Look, I'm on my way
(machinery rumbling)
Out there right now.
- Right.
(chaotic eerie music)
- [Mike] We'll buy time upstairs.
Pouring in down there.
(Ethel panting)
You all right?
Stay in the corridor not the rooms.
- Right?
- Do you have any insecticide,
bug Spray of any kind?
- I don't know.
- What about kerosene for
the lamps in the dining room?
- Yes. In the cellar, in the storeroom.
(chaotic eerie music)
- Let's go.
(sirens blaring)
(machinery rumbling)
(people chattering)
- Hey, you in charge here?
- No, you are.
When this trench is finished,
we're gonna fill it with water.
Now, can you do it?
- There's a three-inch line. No problem.
- Excuse me, Chief. Peggy
Kenter, Bureau of Health.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Ants can get across water you know.
- Our reports are of ants-
- Look, I've just been
talking on my car phone.
We've got to fill that
trench with gas or kerosene
and set fire to it to contain those ants.
- Our reports are of
ants that poison people?
Is that right?
- And there are more people in the hotel.
We've gotta get 'em out.
- All right, get that hook
and ladder in here right away.
Come on, move.
- [Mike] ls everybody okay?
- There's a lot of
equipment on the street.
There's a fire engine with-
- What are we gonna do?
- Take this upstairs, will you?
- You take it.
(can rattling)
(Valerie gasps)
- Mike!
Look.
We gotta get upstairs.
- Go.
Oh, listen, before we
abandon on this floor,
can you operate that switchboard?
- Yeah, sure.
- Okay, you've gotta patch direct lines
into all the phones upstairs.
(machinery rumbling)
- Let's go, let's go.
- Trench is almost ready, Chief.
We're waiting for more gas to get here.
- Yeah, well, it better be soon.
We can't even light a
fire when we have to.
Come on, get that ladder moving faster!
Move it out!
- Mother, they're coming for us.
(can clattering)
- This stuff will get us
before it gets them.
(Linda grunting)
- We're taking a ladder.
(ladder whirring)
Let's get Mother out.
- (sighs) We can't now.
I'll have to carry her.
- No. You go Valerie, please.
- Mother, I'm staying right here with you.
Linda.
- Huh?
- [Richard] Heard of ladies first, huh?
- There's time for all of us. Let me go.
- You wait with the rest of us.
- Oh, I can't.
- You have to.
- I'm afraid.
- Come on, Linda, you can do it.
You're gonna be fine.
- Come on.
- I can't.
(Linda panting)
(Linda groaning)
Oh.
(tense music)
(Linda shouting)
Help.
Oh, oh.
(Linda grunting)
Ah, ah, ah!
- Bring that ladder in first, right away.
Right away, get it up!
- [Linda] Oh (grunting)
Oh ah.
(Linda grunting)
(people chattering)
Oh!
(dramatic music)
- [Firefighter] Come on, come on.
- [Linda] Oh!
(tense music)
- That's it.
(light upbeat orchestral music)
(Linda panting)
- All right, all right, good.
Now, easy with it, now down.
Easy, take it easy.
(ladder whirring)
(people chattering)
(Linda grunting)
- On.
(Linda panting)
Oh, ah.
(people chattering)
I'm all right.
- The ants!
The ants are coming into the hall!
- Mike, we gotta get outta here. Look!
- Wait, wait a minute.
Where are you going?
What about the ladder?
The ladder.
We have to get to the ladder.
(truck horn honking)
(can clattering)
- I think that ladder down there,
I think it wouldn't extend any higher.
Let's go upstairs. Tony,
help out, will you?
- What?
- There's only one more floor.
Before it's over, they'll be
all around us, won't they?
- (sighs) I can't see that far ahead.
Let's just take it one step at a time.
(suspenseful music)
(helicopter whirring)
- Why'd they land? Why
didn't they come for us?
- Hello, hello? Come on, answer!
I don't get it. I know
I passed it outside.
- Mike, she's got to have oxygen.
- No, I'm all right.
- Richard.
(cans clattering)
- This isn't gonna do any good.
You know that, don't you?
- No, I don't.
I was a lifeguard once and we had a rule.
Till you go down for the
fourth time, you keep swimming.
Got that?
(people chattering)
- Come on, get that
gas in the trench fast.
Let's go, move it!
Into the trench.
- Get, come on.
(machinery rumbling)
- Chief, chopper's ready to go.
- All right, great. Let's
get it in there, come on.
- Peggy- Peggy, Peggy-
- Tom. -
(people chattering)
- Let me through.
(people shouting)
I've had a terrible time finding you.
- Boy, am I glad to see you, Tom.
You're the only one with any idea
about this crazy stuff going on here.
- Not so crazy.
- Miss, we need communication inside.
Can I use your car hookup?
- It's yours.
- We're as high as we
can go, the balcony room.
We can't hold out much longer.
The building's like a sieve.
Okay, we'll be ready.
They're sending the helicopter.
(people ehattering)
- What's going on here?
- Move.
- Step back.
- [Woman] Let me go.
- [Officer] Back up, people.
Back, people.
- [Woman] No!
- [Officer] Step back, please.
- [Woman] I gotta go down there.
- See, these ants became immune
to the wastes and poisons
in the air then used them
themselves as a deadly weapon.
- It's unbelievable.
- This particular colony of ants
must have been living in earth
that soaked up poisons for
years then migrated here,
the perfect breeding
ground, near the water,
always a dampness in the earth.
Nature did the rest.
- It sure ain't natural though, is it?
- It happened.
And over the years, this ant
army grew to enormous size.
- Frank, tell that helicopter to hurry up.
(can clattering)
- Ants!
It was the last of the kerosene.
(helicopter whirring)
- See, ants don't sting.
- Yeah, but they have
a stinger, don't they?
- Well, they, not like
bees and other insects.
They bite.
All their strength, all their being
is in their mandibles or jaws.
- So they bite and carry on the poison.
- Which passes directly and
instantly into the bloodstream.
One bite is harmless.
50 could knock you down.
A couple of hundred, certain death.
And once you get them on
you, you can't get them off.
They have stickers on their
legs that cling to you.
(helicopter whirring)
- [Valerie] Mike.
- We'll tie her in. We
have to, she'll be okay.
(helicopter whirring)
- They're coming back
for you, aren't they?
- Of course they are, Mother.
- Well, anchors away.
Good company.
- Take it up!
- Mike, it's caught!
Mike! (crying)
(tense music)
- Oh God.
- Hey, hey.
Get outta the way, get outta the way!
(machinery rumbling)
(crowd cheering)
(people shouting and screaming)
- The ants, the ants, get outta here.
Get out!
Get outta here!
(people screaming)
- [Man] The ants'll get!
- Start the pump, start the pump!
- [Man] The ants'll get.
(fire engine radio chattering)
The ants'll get.
(people screaming)
(men grunting)
(Ethel grunting)
The ants, the ants'll get us.
(siren blaring)
- On.
- [Woman] Here they come.
(people screaming)
- What happened?
- [Man] The ants'll get.
- Get this under control right now.
All right, we're gonna
get this fire started.
Now, we're gonna keep these ants inside.
All right, everybody back off.
Back off. Fire in the hole.
Fire in the hole!
(people chattering)
(tense music)
- [Richard] Linda!
(romantic music)
- Hello?
Hello!
- Is there a carton out here?
- Is there anybody on the line?
- What in God's name are you
doing with that fire out there?
This place is soaked with kerosene.
- Now, we've got to contain the ants.
There's no other way.
We're gonna get you outta
there just as soon as we can.
- Great. There are three
of us left up here.
Get the helicopter back.
- No, no way.
No way, it's too dangerous.
The prop wash is blowing
ants all over the county.
- What do you suggest we
do? We don't have much time.
- Look, hang on, all right?
The Coast Guard is sending us
some special suits, self-contained.
Now, we're gonna come
up there and get you.
- How long?
- [Chief] No more than half an hour.
- Listen, I don't think
we've got five minutes.
- But the suits aren't here yet!
(Chief sighs)
Now look, you've got to hang on.
Can you hear me?
- Yeah. I hear you.
We'll do the best we can.
(somber music)
(siren wailing)
- [Firefighter] Fire service are ready.
(fire engine radio chattering)
- Are they okay up there?
- I don't know.
I don't hear anything.
(tense music)
(chaotic eerie music)
- Here, use this. Don't
let 'em go on your hands.
- [Tony] They're coming in the door.
- [Mike] Stop 'em!
- What? With what?
- Stuff something under the door.
- Tell 'em to hurry, please!
(tense music)
(phone ringing)
- Chief.
- Mike? Mike, is that you?
Look, is everything all right?
- You gotta get something up here now.
It's been 20 minutes. Now, come on!
- Look, the suits will be here any minute.
It can't be much longer.
- If you don't mind.
This is Tom Franklin,
Department of Health.
Listen, if you do what
I say, you can survive.
Ants are basically non-aggressive.
So if you don't move...
(chaotic eerie music)
- He said if we don't
move or excite the ants
or breathe on them,
then they won't bite us.
(fire crackling)
So that's what we're gonna try.
- Oh, you're crazy.
- I wish I was. I wish
I was in some mad dream.
Roll this up for a breathing tube.
Take it!
- On.
- Anything?
- Okay. Let's take a deep breath.
Calm ourselves.
And believe.
(Valerie inhaling)
(Valerie exhaling)
(people shouting)
- Where are those suits?
- We just got in on our radio.
They're about two miles away from here.
(Chief sighs)
(tense music)
- (gasps) Mike, I can't. (panting)
- Sure you can, Val.
Just hold on.
(suspenseful music)
- Mike, I know I won't be able
to stand them on me. (crying)
- Our only chance is
to stay perfectly still
and not to agitate them in any way.
(eerie music)
- They're on my foot, Mike.
- Val, just hold on.
Please.
For me.
- Mike, I'll try.
(eerie music)
- They're on my foot.
- Don't move.
Breathe through the tube.
We can't breathe on them.
Gently.
(eerie music)
- They're on my hand.
Like an army on my hand!
- Remember what he said.
One bite, several bites, can't hurt us.
Stay still.
- They're all over my leg. (whimpering)
- Don't move.
(tense music)
(Valerie panting)
(people shouting)
- All right, don't go
heavy on the insecticide.
Save it for when you reach them.
(tense music)
(chaotic eerie music)
(Spray hissing)
(heavy exhaling)
(chaotic eerie music)
(spray hissing)-
(suspenseful music)
(tense music)
(chaotic dramatic music)
(Tony shouting)
(dramatic music)
(Peggy screaming)
(Spray hissing)
(fire crackling)
(heavy breathing)
(dramatic eerie music)
(dramatic music)
(Spray hissing)
(somber music)
- Mike. (panting)
Is that really the sky
up there and we made it?
I never thought we would.
- Sure you did. You never gave up.
(people chattering)
- Can anybody, anybody
tell me where my mother is?
- She's all right.
I'll take you to her.
- Tom Franklin, Department of Health.
We spoke on the phone.
- Yeah, thanks. Thank you very much.
- Sure.
- Eventually this whole
county's gonna be dug up,
turned over, and rebuilt.
Will this be happening again?
- I don't think so.
Break up the nest, the home,
the special breeding ground,
the family scatters, losing its force.
Same with ants as with people.
- You realize this morning we
hadn't even met each other.
That seems like years ago.
- It was.
- And tomorrow do I get the
terrific chili you promised?
- Yeah.
And the day after that too, if you want.
- Thanks again.
- Michael.
Now, you two are going to make your plans,
get married, do anything you want
with never a thought for me.
- Ha ha, that's a tough order.
- Somebody will buy this land.
I'm going to Florida to
be with my sister Margaret
and I forbid you to worry about me.
- Oh you do.
And what are you gonna do with your time?
- I'll think of something.
I may learn to fly a helicopter.
(Mike laughing)
(Valerie laughing)
- You go along with her.
I'll see you in a while.
Okay-
Mike.
(romantic music)
I love you.
(emotional orchestral music)
(lively orchestral music)