THEY SAY
NOTHING STAYS THE SAME
Thank you.
I'll need a ride back...
at around sunset.
Boatman!
Hurry up!
Move it!
Faster, boatman!
Right away.
Hurry!
Thank you for waiting, sir.
Watch it!
You're in my way.
Get going.
Yes, sir.
Right away.
Off we go.
You can barely row!
Give me a ride.
Don't go back.
I'm in a hurry!
I'm sorry, but it's the rule.
What rule?
There are no rules for boatmen.
Just take me across!
Get a move on!
Get in, let's go.
Sorry. This thing's so heavy.
Stop fumbling around!
- Sorry to stall you.
- Go, boatman!
Faster, you incompetent fool
You're so clumsy.
Here.
Thanks.
You wasted my time!
I caused you trouble, Toichi.
I delayed you.
What an arrogant man he is!
I don't know him.
Maybe he's from upstream?
I bet he's involved...
in building the bridge.
All that banging is so noisy.
Hey, Toichi,
have you eaten?
Not yet.
I've been ferrying people non-stop.
I got potatoes upstream.
Want some?
Don't worry.
Go home and eat.
It's okay!
It's always better to eat with someone.
Let me cook them here.
You're so kind.
It's so heavy!
Hey, I want to cross.
Yes, sir.
Get in.
Thank you.
Toichi, here.
Thank you, sir.
Let's see what I shoot.
I'll be back.
Have a nice hunt, sir!
This'll make it even.
What's that?
My passenger...
Nihei gave me them.
That means I won't owe you anymore.
I lost out...
These look better!
Hot potatoes on a hot day
is hellish!
There they go again.
Are you okay, Toichi?
Doesn't the noise bother you?
I guess I got used to it.
Not me.
You know, Toichi.
When the noise is unbearable,
I think I'll destroy that bridge!
That bridge will be bad for you, tool
The villagers say
it'll be convenient,
but they're wrong.
I don't think it'll be good.
You've ferried people
over the river for years.
That's how we've always
got upstream.
Why change it?
I know the bridge
will be convenient...
but then we won't need
your boat, Toichi.
That's wrong.
It's just wrong!
Toichi.
Join me.
Let's destroy the bridge
before it's done.
I can't tell if you're fooling.
Me neither!
I'm not very smart.
...so I thought it was a boar!
I was shocked
when he jumped out of the bush!
I'd shoot, too.
Lucky I'm a bad shot.
He'd be dead if I wasn't.
Is he okay?
His ear was scorched
so he was in a daze for a while.
He would be!!
Thank God, he was quicker than a boar!
Damn, that noise!
The fish got spooked.
River hobos!
Get out of here, scum!
Eat this and die!
You brats!
Cut it out!
I'm going to eat you up!
You stupid brats!
Those kids are hopeless.
I want peace and quiet.
We need to cross!
Look at that bull!
Let me help.
Be care full
It'd be easier if there was a bridge.
Come on, this is nothing.
Right, Toichi?
We'll go where the water's shallow.
Come on.
Steady, boy.
- That's the way.
- Good boy!
This way.
Come on.
You can do it.
Let's go.
You okay, Genzo?
- Are you okay?
- Yes, it was no trouble.
We made it!
I thought I was stuck,
but you made it possible.
Your bull got wet.
It'll dry on our way upstream
in this heat!
And its hide is silkier.
Let's go.
It feels nice!
It'll be another hot day.
It's such a desolate village.
There's nothing there.
You from there, Mr. Boatman?
No, I'm not.
I came from another village upstream.
Right.
Well, I guess you had
your reasons for leaving...
Something like that.
Right. I knew that was the case.
Don't you want to go back?
I have no family or relatives there.
I don't think I'd belong.
I know what you mean.
Do you know the Chinese
character for loneliness?
Uh... no.
Oh, okay. Never mind that.
Don't be embarrassed.
The character for loneliness
is similar to fox.
There are foxes around here, right?
Foxes, raccoon dogs and even bears.
I bet.
So...
foxes always seem lonely to me.
Isn't that strange?
You're right.
I guess foxes are lonely, too.
Mr. Boatman, I was sold
as a child so my family could eat.
I worked for a medicine maker.
They had many books,
so I learned to read.
Good for you.
I was born very sturdy.
I've never been sick.
I sold medicine,
but I never needed any!
I did okay for a child who was sold off.
Even so...
I've become sentimental
about the old village.
I thought I'd never go back but
I keep thinking about the past lately.
Isn't that funny?
So I went back to the village...
but there's nothing for me there anymore.
What? A kid was drifting
in the river?
The boat hit something
and it was a human.
Let me check.
A person?
I thought she was dead,
but she was breathing.
I did what I could.
What the hell!
I need more mugwort.
Is there any around your place?
Yes, there isl!
So...
I'll get some!!
Thanks.
Okay!
Okay! I'll be right back!
Mugwort. Mugwort, mugwort...
Hey, Toichi.
She looks better.
Her breathing's steadier.
That's good.
Your mugwort medicine worked!
That's right.
It works very well.
She'll be well soon.
But I worry that she hit her head.
You're right.
She was bleeding around here.
We don't know how far she floated.
If she got a bad blow to the head,
mugwort won't help.
Boatman! I need to cross!
Yes, sir.
- Stop fishing!
- I'm sorry.
Hurry up!
You're vain,
that's what you are.
Lay off! I got laid.
That's all that matters.
You splashed me!
Don't rock the boat.
Careful, you idiot!
Bad things happen.
Imagine having your throat slit!
I heard that you squeal
like a wild beast and die.
- You make sounds?
- It's more like air releasing.
It's terrible.
The entire family was killed...
It was some kind of grudge.
Right. He even killed the children?
Merciless bastard.
Did you hear about it, Boatman?
No. Only what I heard you say now.
Is that right?
There's a village called Ichi-nomiya,
20 kilometers upstream.
It's a spooky place.
No one told you about it?
Rumors have legs, right?
What happened?
Apparently a whole family was massacred.
Throats slit.
Yes, they were slit, it was savage.
Ichi-nomiya is creepy!
It's horrible.
The killer is at large.
Oh, wait.
I heard that a boy or girl...
is missing.
The killer might have taken one of them.
After killing the rest?
However it went, it's cruel.
Everyone's talking about it.
I see.
Toichi!
She's awake!
She's awake but she won't
say a thing!
She won't answer my questions.
When did she wake up?
A while ago. While you were
taking someone across.
How did it go?
How? She just sprang up!
I was surprised.
I think there was a "Whoa" or "Ugh"|
She said, "Whoa" and "Ugh"?
No, me! I did!
I was so surprised I said, "Ugh"!
I'm not talking about you, Genzo.
Right.
She sprang up and looked around...
Then she stared at me.
Okay. I'll go see how she is.
Toichi, I have to go!
Okay, thank you.
Are you...
okay?
I...
I row a boat.
I'm a boatman.
And...
I found you.
So...
you can rest here
until you feel better.
Are you hungry?
Here...
Eat this.
Remember what I told you
about the Ichi-nomiya massacre?
It wasn't the son who was kidnapped.
It was the daughter.
A girl!
Either way it's horrible.
You must ferry across
many people every day.
That's right.
You might have taken the killer!
Watch for anyone with a girl.
When did it happen?
A couple of days ago.
Are you okay now?
You look well now...
thanks to my medicine.
I mix mugwort with bear bile.
Do you...
remember drifting in the river?
I bet your family's worried.
Why were you floating in the river?
What's your name?
You remember your name?
Did you come in a giant peach?
She won't even tell me her name.
Maybe she can't remember?
Beats me.
She stares at the river.
Yes, all the time.
Toichi.
Is that girl on the rock related to you?
Yeah.
I have to look after her for a while.
Is that right?
Someone upstream asked me to--
Just for a while.
I see.
I've never seen her around.
It's complicated.
She's a relative?
Something like that.
Toichi, why did you lie to them?
I...
I couldn't say I found
her in the river.
I know but...
lying isn't the way to go.
What will you gain
from taking care of her?
You're right.
It's okay now but...
the villagers will start
getting suspicious.
Rumors will start.
You!
I saw you before.
You were on the other side of the river.
You live around here?
No, I don't live around here.
You don't!
But...
I know a lot about you.
About me?
I've been watching you.
I know a lot about you.
Gone? She's gone?
I woke up and she was gone.
Oh right.
I was worried for nothing.
Toichi, I'll be off early today.
I'll see you soon.
Am I in the right spot?
I need to go across to the village.
I was told I could cross here.
Can you take me there?
Yes, sir.
- Please get in.
- Okay.
You're the boatman?
Yes, sir.
In the center, please.
I thought I'd have to row myself.
Is it hard?
Sorry?
You row the boat every day?
Yes, sir.
It must be tough in this heat.
There's nothing else I can do.
Rowing boats is all I'm capable of.
- You can make a living?
- Sort of.
You get paid?
Yes, sir. I don't charge
the villagers though.
I charge city folk five rin.
Oh, okay.
Pay me when we get there.
I see.
So do you have...
many passengers?
There used to be a lot of passengers.
Not anymore?
No.
See the rock over there?
I heard there was
another boat there.
Ah, over there?
Oh, I could've crossed the bridge!
The bridge hasn't been completed yet.
Right. They're still working on it.
Once it's done,
it'll make things easier.
I guess the area will get busier.
I guess so, sir.
But then...
you'll lose your job.
Well I don't know, sir.
If it's there,
I guess folks will use it.
It'll be convenient
for everyone.
What's important is that
folks can commute with no trouble.
So I wouldn't worry about myself.
Right.
As they say, nothing stays the same.
Life's hard.
- Here we are.
- Yes, sir.
Go ahead.
Thank you.
Oh, I have to pay.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you!
It was nice.
Will you be here later?
Yes, sir, I'll be here.
If you can't find me,
check the hut.
I'll do that!
The river is nice.
I'll see you when I return.
Boatman! We need to cross.
It's her ass...
She's an ugly bitch but what an ass.
Hey, how about you?
You ever got laid?
- Me?
- You.
You row a stupid boat all day.
I guess not!
Of course not!
An ugly old man like you
has no chancel!
And it costs money to get laid.
Girls wouldn't do you.
You're too spooky.
I wouldn't if I was a girl.
I wouldn't do you if you were a girl!
You smell like a corpse.
Lay off. It's depressing.
Think about it, boatman.
What we do every day...
We put our blood,
sweat and tears into that bridge.
Show us gratitude!
The villagers are very grateful, sirs.
They can't wait for it to be finished.
Of course.
How about you?
I'm asking about you.
Not the villagers.
Will you be happy when it's made?
Yes. I'm looking forward to it.
Then we'll make it sooner for you.
The villagers will be glad
not to use this dirty boat any more.
Useless things disappear.
Understand?
Once it's done,
it'll make things easier.
But then you'll lose your job.
They say it'll be convenient.
We won't need your boat.
You're too spooky.
We'll make it sooner for you.
That bridge will be bad for you!
Let's destroy the bridge
before it's done.
Hello!
You look dazed, boatman.
Are you all right?
- Sorry.
- Weren't you listening?
You said that the village
was quite pretty.
I said that before I got on the boat.
Come on, I give up!
You really weren't listening.
I'm sorry.
You asked me why I went to the village.
I told you that I was going
to see my patients.
Do you remember that?
Certainly...
Oh boy, you don't look like you do.
- So?
- Sir?
- Should I continue?
- Please do.
I lost my enthusiasm...
I'm sorry.
I was preoccupied.
You can do the talking.
No, really...
Where was I?
You know Nihei's father, right?
Yes, Nihei gave me potatoes
the other day.
You told me that already!
Nihei's father and I go back.
His legs are getting weak
and he has a bad cold.
That's not good.
So I went over to see him.
But then there were more patients.
I ended up seeing a dozen patients!
I see.
If a town doctor has an easy life
he's no longer a town doctor...
Whatever I say,
you only half-listen to.
Here.
That doctor's got a screw loose.
He needs this bag!
How can he forget something so important?
I think he's a great man.
He comes all the way from town
to see his patients.
Right.
It's really something.
You've got a point there.
We sure owe him a lot,
but it's not good to forget this!
The doctor left in the late afternoon.
We only noticed his bag late at night.
We would've noticed it sooner,
but he put it by a pot
in the dark doorway.
I wonder how he'll work today.
Right?
It'd be strange if he saw
patients without this.
That man's going to deliver
a bag to the doctor!
The doctor did his rounds
here yesterday.
He left his bag at that man's place.
He's a bit of an odd character,
but...
I feel like...
he sees straight through me.
The doctor said he'd come back.
You should talk to him
if you're still in pain.
Do you have any pain?
No.
Okay.
He's a good man.
You should consult him
if you need to.
My job is to help people
cross the river.
You can see that.
Every day, I meet all sorts of people
crossing the river.
It makes me happy
to help out folks a little.
Well...
I guess it means nothing to you.
I thought you went
back home or something.
You didn't go home?
Right.
Do you have anywhere to go?
Well, I have little to offer,
but you can stay...
as long as you want.
I live alone so you won't be
putting me out.
Toichi, how are you doing?
Genzo!
Going upstream?
No, not today.
She came back?
Yes, last night.
Right.
Ah well... I brought some bean paste
that someone gave me.
I'll cook it on a hot rock.
I thought I could give you some.
Oh, I'd love that!
Are you sure?
No problem.
It'll last longer cooked.
It goes with eggplants.
And also this!
I have some millet to eat.
Why don't you eat with us, Genzo?
You don't mind?
I never say no to kindness.
I'll take care of the paste!
What's that smoke?
You cooking?
Yes. Genzo dropped by,
so we'll eat together.
Oh, sorry to bother you.
You want to join us, Nihei?
Thanks, but no thank you.
I have to go back.
My folks are waiting to know
if I returned the bag.
Right. How was the doctor?
Was he able to work without the bag?
Well...
He was like, "Oh, I had no ideal"
But his maid told me that
he looked all over for the bag.
He even sent his patients away.
Right.
It sounds like you saved him.
What would he have done
if I hadn't returned it?
He talked about you.
He said, "The boatman is quiet,
but very humane."
What's that mean?
Well I have no idea what he means.
He offered to help you
if you ever need it.
That's so kind of him.
Nihei.
How about the rumor
about the incident upstream?
What rumor?
I just overheard it but some folk
were killed in Ichi-nomiya.
Pass me the paste.
And this.
To cook it.
Like this.
What a nice smell!
This is really delicious.
They say cooked bean paste
won't last three months.
You can't stop eating it.
You want a go?
Try it.
On this one.
Watch out!
If you don't,
you'll get burned!
I haven't seen her recently.
She's been back for a while.
Right.
How's it going, Genzo?
Hey, Nihei!
- On your way home?
- Yes.
I haven't seen your dad around.
How is he?
He's in bed with a summer cold.
He's getting old.
Is that so?
Watch out. Summer colds can take
a turn for the worse.
Sure.
Have you eaten?
Toichi invited me to join you,
but I can't today.
Are you sure?
What's that?
Bean paste.
Is it grilled?
Sounds good.
I'll bring you some later!
Only if you have leftovers.
Don't overcook it.
It'll stick to the rock.
Sure thing!
Thanks, Toichi.
The...
Take it off!
Get the paste off before
it burns.
- See you, Genzo!
- See ya!
Watch it! It's burning!
Today's meal is really impressive!
Thank you, Genzo.
No worries, Toichi.
Most of it's yours.
Want this?
Is your village...
over that way?
This way then?
You came from upstream.
So I think that's where your home is.
Do you remember your village?
It's okay. As long as you have
some memories.
A hit to the head can make you
forget who you are.
You remember, right?
No.
You forgot?
Yes.
Nothing at all?
Nothing.
You know...
You can't remember, right?
Since when?
When?
Yes. I mean...
What do you remember?
What is your name?
Do you remember?
My name is Toichi.
How about you?
You don't remember?
Well...
I'm sorry.
I mean...
No passengers today.
I've never seen that girl!
What weird clothes!
She must be a monster.
- Monster!
- Die! Go away!
Sssh! Leave us alone!
Go on!
Do you think you've been
in a boat before?
Do you want to try?
The boat?
Yes.
Can I?
Okay.
Let's go then.
Yes.
There are no passengers so...
Let's do it.
There's some fish! See?
The river is calm here
so the fish come out.
Actually...
it's Fu.
That's what it is.
It's Fu.
You mean your name?
You mean, she's not that girl?
No one's even heard
that story you told me.
Nothing about any murders...
I see.
Thank you for visiting Ichi-nomiya for me.
Wind?
Your name...
If your name is Fu,
it might mean wind.
Why?
No reason, but it might be
what your name means.
Wind...
Yes. It's possible.
How about Toichi?
My name?
I don't know...
Maybe Toichi doesn't mean anything.
It doesn't?
I don't know.
If Fu is wind,
what is Toichi?
I've never thought about it.
Why not?
You think about my name,
but not yours?
That's how it goes.
Really.
I thought it'd be interesting
if your name meant wind.
You know?
The wind can make the river
flow faster.
It even changes the river's character.
If I'm a boatman and you're the wind
I thought it'd be interesting.
Thank you.
Can you stack them there?
Wipe it for me.
Watch your step.
Thank you.
Go easy.
You want to come?
It's almost finished?
Looks that way, ma'am.
They have more people working on it.
They look busy lately.
I hope we can use it by autumn.
I hope so, too.
Particularly with a baby,
it'll make things easier.
Boatman, can we cross the river?
Certainly.
I'll get the boat ready.
- I hope it goes well.
- Yes.
- You practiced?
- Yes but it's not easy.
It's difficult.
- I want sugar candy.
- Toffee for me!
Forget food!
This is your first festival performance.
I know but candy's better
than flowers.
You talk about food, men and...
How about focusing
on your performance?
But it's a festival!
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
You want to try?
Over to the shore?
When I first started I was told
three days to use oars
and three years for the pole.
Poles are that difficult.
Keep rowing.
That's good.
When the bridge is complete...
how different will it be?
Back when I started rowing boats
the river was much cleaner.
I saw lots of fireflies at night.
I bet you've seen fireflies?
Yes.
According to the villagers,
fireflies only thrive in pristine water.
And boy, those fireflies
were beautiful!
But gradually...
there seem to be less fireflies.
Why's that?
Well...
What do you mean?
Is the water dirty now?
Since they started building the bridge...
I don't see many fireflies.
Poor fireflies.
Bridges aren't important.
I prefer fireflies to bridges.
Fireflies and...
clean rivers are better.
Me too.
I prefer fireflies.
But when something new comes along...
the old things go.
That's how it is.
Like a wind can send
a boat out of control,
a breeze eventually
changes the way of the world.
It'd be better...
if there was no wind.
Go ahead.
It's rocking.
Yes, the wind's strong today.
I felt a drop.
It might get stormy.
Right. It's kind of unpredictable.
I guess no passengers
will come in this rain.
What are you making?
Oh, this thing...
Well, it's a...
I'll show you something nice.
Is it treasure?
Something like that. Here.
Beautiful, isn't it?
Someone gave it to me.
That person is no longer around.
The last time she crossed the river...
she gave it to me.
She said she'd never
come back here so
she wanted me to keep it.
And never show anyone.
It's a secret that she shared with me.
Why?
Maybe it's that precious.
You know...
Her face is stuck in my mind.
I don't know why
she gave me that picture but...
I can't forget her.
She had...
a slight resemblance
to the woman in the picture.
How can I put it?
She was sorrowful.
And...
her sorrow...
was unforgettable.
Toichi!
It's me, Nihei!
What is it?
Why are you here in this rain?
I need to cross.
It doesn't have to be this minute.
But please take me when you're ready.
Certainly. Come inside.
It's okay.
Thank you.
Sorry to ask when it's raining like this.
Toichi.
It's Dad.
He died.
My Dad...
He's dead.
As you know, Toichi,
Dad hunted for a living.
He always hunted rabbits,
deer, and boars across the river.
He shared the game,
if he did well.
One day he told me,
"I've been living this long
thanks lo the lives I took.
"All the lives I was given...
"When I die, give my body
to the animals in the hills.
"Without my soul, I'd just be flesh.
"I'd be happy if you fed me
to the animals.
I want to return their favor.”
But some folks might find it spooky
to leave a body
to animals to eat.
So Toichi.
I want to do it secretly
So no one knows.
In the night hours...
before the daybreak.
I want to fulfill his wish.
I It's a lot to ask...
but please help me.
Sorry I got you involved in this.
You always helped Dad cross.
With your boat you helped him
carry the lives he was given.
Dad would've been so happy...
Thank you, Toichi.
Fireflies.
Fireflies...
They're still there.
Yeah.
Maybe one is Nihei's dad's soul departing.
I always thought...
Nihei's dad was a great man.
He dedicated his life
to helping others.
How difficult is that.
But me...
I'm helping others.
I like to think I'm doing that but...
I feel they owe me.
I hope the bridge never gets made.
I can't help thinking like that.
I'm full of myself.
But for Nihei's dad...
others came before him.
Even after he died...
he wants to be of benefit.
That's the kind of man...
I'd like to be.
The troubadours!
How festive!
What funny costumes!
I can't wait for the festival.
It's going to be fun.
We heard that the bridge
isn't finished yet...
Thank the Lord for the boatman!
Every year I'm in the festival but...
No bridge.
Builders nowadays are quick!
- They sure are.
- I can't wait!
- It's all about convenience.
- We need a bridge.
It'll be great once we can walk across.
Next year we can do that.
Then we won't get wet.
And it will be quicker!
It'll be great.
It'll be much easier.
My kid hates boats.
- We won't need the boat any more.
- It'll be easier.
- We can cart things over.
- It'll be so easy.
- How convenient.
- I can't wait.
Look. Is that smoke?
- Where?
- You're right!
Is it the bridge?
Isn't it almost done?
I hope it's okay.
...but I know a lot about you.
About me?
I've been watching you.
I'm a ghost and I live here.
That's nonsense.
You don't have to believe me,
but I know a lot about you.
That's why I came lo you.
That girl has the life owed to me.
She was meant to die that night...
and I was lo replace her
while her soul waited to reincarnate.
Reincarnate?
What?
But you saved her.
You interfered with our fate.
She'll cause you grief someday.
I know you well.
1 advise you to think well.
Toichi. Are they ready?
I don't know...
Maybe you can do better?
Oh, well.
I'll come back for them.
It's time.
I'll go see the doctor.
Old Toichi is kind of losing it.
Maybe you're a burden to him now.
Surely you don't want
to stay here forever?
It's time you left.
It'd be good for both of you.
I never told you,
but I went to your village.
Toichi asked me to.
Was it Ichi-nomiya?
What I heard didn't really add up.
You know what I'm saying?
Let go.
I can take care of you.
You look pale.
I bet you're not eating well.
Well...
Toichi.
You need to take it easy.
It's bad to think too much.
You'd lose your mind if you did.
Life is short.
Might as well enjoy it.
Right?
You know why we reincarnate?
We need to live many lives...
to grow wiser.
We're brought to this world to learn
one thing before we depart.
What you learn varies
from one person to another.
You live to find that thing.
And you cross a river
to move on to the next life.
I know!
Since you're a boatman...
you'll have no problem
crossing the Styx.
Toichi.
Toichi, I haven't seen you
for a long time.
You went to town?
Yes, I visited the doctor.
Right.
Sorry, Toichi.
After this was built,
I hardly visit you.
It's okay...
All the villagers...
Since we got the bridge
everyone acts so busy.
Many villagers went to live in town.
What will happen to us?
I miss the times you took us across.
Back when we weren't in a hurry
like we are now.
Toichi...
can you take me
out on your boat someday?
Certainly.
What happened?
What is it?
Tell me what happened!
It won't get worse.
It won't get worse than this.
Calm down.
I won't blame you for anything!
You've done nothing wrong!
You just protected yourself!
You're not to blame!
I'm not so righteous as to blame you!
I'm just a selfish nobody!
But I...
thought...
I could protect you.
I wanted to...
I've got nothing left here anyway.