Not my hand only,
but my mouth.
Not my mouth, but my heart, also.
Granted, that I may know nothing but you.
Count the blessings ...
Amen.
Yes.
I know that my redeemer liveth,
and He shall stand at the latter day
on the earth.
And though after my skin, worms destroy
this body.
Still in my flesh shall I see God.
Whom I shall see for myself.
And mine eyes shall behold.
And not another.
Amen.
Sister Adana?
- I fear I can't, sister -
- Sister Adana,
we are in the midst of prayer.
In the midst of paying respect to our
- late Sister Irene.
- I'm mean no
disrespect to Irene.
Your actions speak the contrary.
Amen, Adana.
But I fear a misjudgment in our faith.
What has brought you to these
- twisted perceptions?
- I'm sorry sister but
I know I lack the confidence
of His control.
Causing an uncontrollable spiral.
Watch what you say in moments
of weakness!
Times like this
are our real test.
This is a test which I feel I am not
failing.
I cannot explain with
any reason what -
Father, forgive her.
She does not know of what she speaks.
The deeper I think of these events
the emptier they become.
We must trust what He does
that it is for the greater good.
We may only understand so much.
Trust,
must do the rest.
And this is why second by second,
- my faith weakens --
- Adana.
I hope God will never suffer you to come
to this disorder again.
Adana, may speak some truth.
To have one look upon these events
would trouble any soul mightily.
I fear darker spirits are playing.
You must stop this talk.
If you were to seem
fit to live.
The Lord will serve what we deserve.
Cast upon our souls the rightful
- judgment from our Father.
- The stories
which we study often tell a common tale.
One of unexplained deceit.
A name which I dare utter.
Finding new ways to terrorize souls.
This tale,
could be the thick and corrupt web of
which Horus -
Fall in line.
Or find yourself burning in the eternal
punishment of neglect!
Never,
endeavor to be transformed like
this again.
I've done what you asked of me.
My loyalty
knows no bounds.
Your wish
is my...
Please, come quick!
Father.
Sister.
How long have you shared my presence?
You shouldn't fear, sister.
Not now,
and not tomorrow.
Your youth has gotten the better of you.
Come to me, sister.
Let us repent your soul.
For your way has been lost.
I fear I'd no longer belong here, sister.
Your path to rediscovery is being
revealed as we speak.
Come to me.
Listen, sister.
And open thy soul.
Oh, Lord forgive our Adana.
Take her.
Forgive her.
Her faith is strong.
I forgave
I forgave, my trust.
- I wavered
- I have sinned,
but
- I love
- I love.
Endeavor to be transformed, sister.