♪♪
[Whip cracks]
- As English ships
bore down on St. Augustine,
the people of the town grabbed
their valuables and fled.
- They realized that they
could not hold them off.
They didn't have the weaponry.
They didn't have the personnel
to hold them off,
and so the best thing you can do
is try to save yourself.
That's why most of
the townspeople run.
- You had 23 heavy ships,
19 auxiliary ships,
2,000 armed men.
What did St. Augustine have?
Couple of sloops and rowboats
and a handful of soldiers
in the fort.
- They were no match
for Sir Francis Drake,
the man known as The Dragon.
- They called him El Draque,
The Dragon.
It's a play on his name,
and they feared him.
They thought he was in league
with the devil.
- Because he was this rampaging,
fire-breathing,
appalling monster of a man
that they feared.
- [Speaking Spanish]
- Only about 80 soldiers
stayed at the fort
to prepare for the onslaught.
- The governor summons
the three other royal officers
in St. Augustine
to his residence,
and one of his real worries,
one of his concerns was,
"What are we going to do
with the treasury box?"
- The treasury box contained
the yearly allocation
from the king of Spain.
Any gold and silver
would undoubtedly
be the pirates' main target.
- Privateering is
state-licensed piracy.
The privateer has a piece
of paper which says,
"I'm commissioned by
the government of this country
to do this against the ships
and property of this country."
- The treasury box was moved
to the fort.
- So the money was left there,
and the food and clothing was
taken into the woods for hiding.
- St. Augustine wasn't even
in Drake's plans
when he first sighted the fort.
The town was hardly
worth looting,
but it did have strategic value
now that the English were trying
to establish a colony
in Roanoke.
- As soon as Drake saw
that watchtower,
realized St. Augustine
was behind it
and realized it was
a threat to Roanoke,
the writing was
on the wall for it.
Nobody was going
to threaten Roanoke.
- Drake had been harboring a
personal vendetta against Spain
ever since he was a young man.
It happened in 1568.
His fleet had just seized
a Spanish island
when a storm forced them
to seek refuge in its port.
They negotiated a cease-fire,
but the Spaniards went back
on their word and attacked.
- [Yelling in Spanish]
♪♪
- Drake's ship escaped,
but the others did not.
- That burned in the heart
of Sir Francis Drake
his entire life, that he
was betrayed by the Spanish
and that he saw
all of his friends die.
He hated the Spanish
with a passion from then on.
It was personal.
- Drake's fury with anyone
who crossed him was legendary.
- Now!
- Yes, sir.
- It's said he even once ordered
the beheading of his own friend.
- Certainly, there are examples
of a fierce temper,
particularly during
his circumnavigation
where he insisted on
the execution of a mutineer
or a supposed mutineer.
- Queen Elizabeth capitalized
on that anger,
turning Drake into her
personal weapon against Spain.
- Queen Elizabeth allowed him
to do what he did best,
which was plunder her enemies.
This is politics.
King Philip of Spain
controlled most of the world
- England saw great advantage in
attacking the Spanish Empire,
which was incredibly wealthy
but also incredibly vulnerable.
When the Anglo-Spanish War
broke out in 1585,
this is exactly what
Elizabeth I set about doing,
ordering Drake to set off
on a pillaging mission
across the Atlantic.
- Which is how St. Augustine
inadvertently became a pawn
in that undeclared war
between England and Spain.
Drake and his men had been
on their way home
after looting several
Spanish towns in the Caribbean
when they spotted the fort.
Drake knew that
attacking Spain's
first settlement in La Florida
would deliver a crushing blow
to King Philip and his legacy.
Drake sent his men
to scout the fort,
but they didn't anticipate
what was waiting for them.
- Well, they're attacked.
♪♪
They killed some of his soldiers
when they came on land
on that island.
- A map published
three years later depicts
Drake's version
of what happened.
It was drawn by
an Italian cartographer,
Battista Boazio,
who accompanied
Drake on the voyage.
- It's the first map of
any city in the U.S.
In the very back
in the cornfield,
there was a little murder
taking place,
and you have to look carefully.
It's really in the cornfield,
and here's a man down
on the ground
with his hands like this,
and there's another man
with his sword raised,
and it's the killing
of Captain Anthony Powell,
who was Drake's kinsman
as well as his best captain.
- No!
- Drake didn't really
lose an assistant.
He more lost a personal friend.
- He will be avenged.
- One of the accounts holds
that that is what
precipitated Drake's rage.
[Chatter]
♪♪
- Fire!
- Drake then landed
and despoiled the city
of anything of value.
♪♪
- After two days,
St. Augustine's garrison
had completely run out
of ammunition.
♪♪
A Spanish officer later
described the attack
in a letter to the king.
- He said, "We fought
valiantly under odds
that almost had
never been seen,"
and then they were
forced to flee.
And he said, "We had to flee
with such speed
that we didn't even have time
to carry the treasury box,
and the next morning, Drake's
forces took over the garrison."
♪♪
- Drake and his men burned the
entire town and the wooden fort.
Everything went up in flames.
♪♪
- Imagine what it was like
for the community
and the soldiers
and the governor
to behold what they saw when
they emerged from the woods.
It was a site of smoke and ruin.
♪♪
- I think we found the
archaeological evidence
for Drake's raid.
St. Augustine archaeologist
Carl Halbirt
believes the city imploded,
collapsing into
a thick layer of ash.
- We found a burned deposit
that dates to the 16th century,
and we're not talking
just a little lens.
We're talking about lens
about 2 inches thick
of carbonaceous material.
Within that
carbonaceous material
were just lots
of broken pottery.
♪♪
- But the reason why Drake
burned St. Augustine
is still a matter of debate.
According to the governor's
official account,
Drake made off with the entire
hoard of silver and gold
from the treasury box.
[Laughter]
- Or so the governor claimed.
This was his story.
- And that was
Drake's story as well.
- Two years after
the Drake attack,
a fascinating character, a guy
by the name of Pablos Juan,
who was a soldier
in St. Augustine,
he arrived in Seville
and immediately sought an
audience with the king of Spain,
with Philip Il,
and he said that
the four royal officials
took their keys
and opened the box,
took all of the money,
the gold and silver,
out of it
and filled it with lead.
He claims that the
governor distributed
the money amongst his cronies
and their allies
and bought off some of the other
Spaniards who knew the story.
- Some believe that
this was the real reason
Drake burned down the town,
that he became enraged
when he found
the treasury box empty.
♪♪
- Take this away from me.
- But we may never know
because historians believe
Drake would've never admitted
he'd been tricked.
The Boazio map,
which Drake commissioned,
greatly exaggerated his victory.
- Drake wanted to brag,
you know, "Here's what I did,"
and so if you look at the town
that's portrayed there,
the buildings that are
shown there are things
that probably would never
existed in St. Augustine,
but of course, the grander
the town that you raid,
the grander and greater
your accomplishments.
♪♪
- In the meantime, Sir Francis
Drake returned to England
to his opulent estate,
a former monastery known
as Buckland Abbey,
not far from the port of
Plymouth from which he sailed.
It was here he fashioned
himself a legend,
entertaining the elite
in a mansion furnished
by his ill-gotten gains.
- Drake sets himself up
as a gentleman,
which he hasn't been before,
and makes himself into
the iconic English hero
of the 16th century.
- Yes, the pin-up boy,
so to speak,
he was the man you wanted
to have to dinner.
You know, he was the man that,
if he came through your village,
you took the kids out to see
and certainly was courted
almost godlike status
down in Plymouth.
- His was the classic
rags-to-riches story,
a commoner who had earned the
respect and favor of the queen.
- Try to picture
a ruthless entrepreneur,
a television personality,
a gang boss,
and sprinkle into that
an occasional touch
of Revivalist preacher,
and I think you can probably
picture Francis Drake.
- The collateral damage
left in his wake
was overlooked back home largely
because these acts of piracy
had not only been
sanctioned by the queen,
they had been funded
by her as well.
Documents in The National
Archives at Kew, England,
confirm the extent
to which Queen Elizabeth
backed Drake's raids.
- Right here is the name,
Francis Drake,
and the Elizabeth Bonaventure
and the aid,
and the sum, 20,000 pounds.
So the queen was a stakeholder
in this adventure.
- She made a lot of money
out of this.
Just to give one example,
during Drake's
circumnavigation of the world,
her share of the profits
was 300,000 pounds.
That was a huge amount of money.
So he was a hot property.
You don't throw away men
like that, do you?
- The queen not only didn't
punish Drake for his misdeeds,
she had him knighted.
- It was unheard of to knight
a commoner like Drake.
- She makes him kneel,
and she gets the sword out.
Then she hands it
to the French ambassador,
and it's classic Elizabeth.
She wants to do something grand,
but she knows the king of Spain
would then say, of course,
"He's your pirate,"
so she gets this French
ambassador to do it.
- So what she's saying to Spain
is, "Look. I've got friends.
If you don't like
what I'm doing with Drake, well,
let's go to war
and see what happens."
♪♪
- The sacking of St. Augustine
was barely a notch
in Drake's belt
in terms of monetary gain,
but it was a huge
strategic victory.
Drake's attack caused
the residents
of another Spanish settlement
about 220 miles to the north
to fear that they would be next.
- The people in Santa Elena
were so afraid afterwards
that what happened
to St. Augustine
could happen to them
that they wanted out of there.
They were exposed.
- And so the decision was to
consolidate in St. Augustine.
- Some British historians say
this was a pivotal moment
when Spain began to lose
its hold on La Florida.
- Spain was forced to withdraw
from all its
more northerly settlements
on the coast of Carolina,
so Spain was never then a rival
in what is now North America.
- The refugees from Santa Elena
were pouring into St. Augustine.
It nearly crippled the town,
which was already
struggling to survive.
♪♪
A stunning new
archaeological discovery
buried under the streets
of modern-day St. Augustine
was recently unearthed
when the city needed
to lay underground utility lines
on Charlotte Street.
City archaeologist
Carl Halbirt and his team
were called in to dig test holes
before construction began,
and what they found turned out
to be one of the most
significant discoveries
made here in decades.
- There's the arm bone,
the bones themselves,
and there's the pelvis
right there,
and there's the vertebra, the
lumbar vertebra, right there.
- According to historical maps,
these bones were buried inside
the first parish church
in America,
known as Nuestra Señora
de Los Remedios.
The church had been
rebuilt after
Drake burned everything
to the ground,
but the many natural disasters
that followed took its toll
on the population.
♪♪
- The feet would be pointing
toward the altar,
and the head would be
pointing toward the doorway,
and then, at resurrection,
the body would rise up
and face the altar.
Hey, what's this?
- Archaeologists have identified
other burials
farther away
from the waterfront,
but this one is believed to have
been the floor of the church
where some of the oldest bones
would've been buried.
- It's just right...
- You think that could be floor?
It's tabby. It's...
- [Indistinct]?
- Yep.
I mean, it's right on top
of the bone.
- Los Remedios served as the
parish church
from 1572 to 1702.
- I've been here
in St. Augustine for 25 years.
You know, during that 25 years,
we've literally uncovered
hundreds of thousands
of pieces of trash,
pottery, broken glass,
nails, hundreds of thousands
if not millions of pieces
of animal bone.
You know, these are the items
that people used every day.
What we have now are the actual
people who used those items.
These are the people who enabled
the city to survive.
Yeah, so this is it now.
I guess the question is,
what should we do?
You know, I mean,
we could remove them,
but they're in such
bad condition,
we'd end up destroying them.
- I know.
- Ultimately, the decision was
made to keep the bones buried
and not disturb
the final resting place
of these early settlers.
- I'm excited.
I'm... You know, it's...
I don't think I'll ever have
this experience again.
If I was to rank this
on a scale of one to 10,
this would be a 10.
- Some of the bones buried
on Charlotte Street
could well date back
to this period following
Drake's raid.
♪♪
- With his people
barely able to survive,
the governor of St. Augustine
turned to a Timucuan tribe
just outside of town for help.
They were led by a chieftainess
named Doña María,
who was also a Catholic.
- Among the Timucua people,
there were many women chiefs,
and some scholars think that
the number of women chiefs
may have become greater
once Catholicism was introduced
because, apparently,
among the Timucua at least,
the women were the most
receptive to conversion.
- So, this is her signature,
Doña María,
Chief of Nobre de Dios.
She says,
"I might not look Christian,
but I've been Christian
ever since I was a little girl."
- Doña María was a member
of the Timucuan noble class,
whose mother had been
converted by missionaries.
Doña María provided enough
corn to save the town
from starvation.
- And she received all kinds
of honors and privileges
from the Spanish Crown.
She was an ally.
She was a loyal ally.
♪♪
- Back in Spain,
King Philip was anxious
to finally put an end
to the English curse.
Holed up in his bedroom
above the altar at El Escorial,
he hatched a plan
to conquer England.
♪♪
Philip still held fast
to his vision
of bringing about
the Second Coming of Christ,
and Protestant England
was standing in its way.
♪♪
In 1588, just 2 years after
Drake's raid on St. Augustine,
Philip sent his Armada
to claim England
return it to
the Catholic Church,
but the invincible Armada
was defeated,
and one of the key leaders
of the battle against Spain
was none other than the
queen's pirate,
Francis Drake.
- This gave rise to a myth
of English sea power,
this idea that England
was wedded to the sea
in a way that no other
nation in the world was.
- Without Drake and the
other Elizabethan seamen,
England would've become
a Spanish possession.
The world would've been
very different,
America's world
and England's world.
♪♪
- But in 1595,
Drake finally met defeat,
and it was largely
due to a Spanish admiral
named Gonzalo Méndez de Canço,
who would soon become
a key figure
in the future of St. Augustine.
- [Speaking Spanish]
- He's my 12th grandfather
on my father's side.
- Javier Cancio-Donlebún Ballvé
is a direct descendant
of the admiral.
♪♪
- He had a brilliant military
career, almost novel-esque.
We know he crossed the Atlantic
more than 10 times
and shipwrecked twice,
and he fought the French
and English pirates.
- In a chance clash
on the high seas,
Canço and his men
captured a ship
which turned out to contain
Drake's handwritten orders
for an attack on Puerto Rico.
[Speaking Spanish]
- This is a list of instructions
captured on Francis Drake's
ship, the original from 1595.
- The Spanish use the information
to plan their defense.
Canço headed up
the Spanish artillery.
- [Speaking Spanish]
- He fired the shot that killed
the legendary John Hawkins
on November 22nd, 1595.
- The man who Javier claims
his ancestor killed
was an infamous outlaw.
He was also Drake's cousin
and close comrade.
Several hundred of Drake's men
were also killed
in the Battle of San Juan,
and the cabin
of Drake's flagship
was hit by a cannonball.
Drake survived,
and his remaining fleet
retreated off
the coast of Panama.
There, after two unsuccessful
attempts to attack
that territory,
Drake fell ill to the fever.
He died of dysentery
and buried at sea.
- [Speaking Spanish]
- This heroic deed
was very popular in Spain,
and even the great poet,
Lope de Vega,
composed a poem
based on this event.
- Gonzalo Méndez de Canço
was now Spain's iconic hero.
He had defeated
his country's archenemy.
The dragon was slain.
Canço was appointed
governor of St. Augustine,
but when Governor Canço
arrived in St. Augustine,
he reported that the city
was on the verge of ruin.
Five Spanish shipwrecks had
recently occurred off the coast
in short order,
and St. Augustine had
absorbed the survivors.
- It really was probably
like a refugee camp.
- About 500 people in
St. Augustine are castaways,
and, of course, with that
many more mouths in town,
there's a famine.
- Famine in a land
that had always been
barren and unproductive.
- One of the Jesuits in 1570,
he said,
"Basically, the East Coast
is one long sand pile,
the most miserable land
ever discovered by man."
St. Augustine couldn't grow
enough food for itself,
so they always trying to tap
the Indians for surplus.
- Canço knew their only
salvation was to form
an alliance with the Indians,
but that would not be easy.
♪♪
As far back as the late 1400s,
slave traders from Spain,
Portugal and England had been
capturing Indians in Mexico
and the Caribbean
and selling them, causing
a deep mistrust of Europeans.
- Well, imagine what it must
have been like for a native
to see this huge example
of European technology,
this ship with
its huge black hull,
with its spread canvas
with various designs,
possibly crosses,
on it and so forth,
white, bearded men.
That might've been enough
to scare anybody.
It would be like
an alien spaceship
coming down in your backyard,
so naturally, they fought
it off in these places.
- They knew from being seafaring
people, trading with others,
these strange men with beards
and who were always armed,
that they did not come in peace.
They came to enslave.
They came to rob.
- Our people know these people
as kidnappers and slavers,
you know, people who created
great hardship for our people
and changed our world
as we know it.
- When we talk about
the word civilized,
I can't help but smile because,
in many ways, indigenous people
were far more civilized
than the conquerors that forced
their way into their lives.
♪♪
- The brutality of
the Spanish Inquisition
only served to fuel natives'
fears of Europeans even more.
The Inquisition was
a ferocious reign of terror
in which thousands
of non-Catholics, Jews,
Muslims, and Protestants
were barbarically tortured
and burned alive
for their religious beliefs.
Out of this period
came the Black Legend,
the belief that all Spaniards
were ruthless murderers.
- Panfilo de Narvaez
came into Florida,
marched north
as far as Tallahassee,
and there, he made the mistake
of seizing the food stores
at the Apalachee encampment,
and those natives gave him
a 24-hour rain of arrows
that made it impossible for him
and his men to survive,
and they had to go down to the
coast, build rafts, and escape.
- So I think it's unfair to
describe the natives as hostile.
They were simply protecting
their territory
against foreign invaders,
and that's clearly
what the Europeans were.
- And while the explorers
saw natives as savage,
the Spanish seemed equally
barbaric to the Indians.
- On these expeditions,
when they're hungry,
they eat shoes
and they eat horses
and they eat saddles, I mean,
and they eat each other.
- And then you have
Hernando de Soto,
who was a moral monster
in the way in which
he treated aboriginal peoples,
and he maimed and killed
his way north through Florida,
cutting off Indians' ears
and noses and sending them back,
saying, "This will happen
to everybody
unless you give me
and my men safe passage."
What was left behind?
Collapsed native societies
all along the range
of nine American states
as we know them today,
4,000 miles of travel,
and for what?
♪♪
- But in 1542, King Carlos V
issued new laws,
ordering that native people
who lived in the Americas
were to be treated humanely,
so by the time
St. Augustine was founded,
enslaving natives
was prohibited.
- King Carlos V issued what
were called The New Laws
specifying that the native
peoples possessed souls
deserving of respect
just as white Spaniards did,
saying that any abuse
of the Indians
would be punished
by the king and his officers
and just laying it down
that all natives had souls
that were equal of
the souls of white persons.
- There's a period
right about now
when there's a shift
from conquest by the sword
to conquest by the Gospel,
and the king now
wants pacification.
♪♪
- If these people could show
themselves that they were human
and that they would be
respectful of their word,
then that would determine
if we went to war with them
or if we consider them an ally.
♪♪
- By the late 1500s,
nearly 2 centuries
before their famous
missions in California,
the Spanish had already
built a system of missions
throughout La Florida.
The friars often lived
in isolation in remote areas
several days or weeks
from St. Augustine.
♪♪
- Of course, they're preaching,
but they're also helping
with any number of other things
that they could offer,
perhaps how to raise
certain crops,
how to domesticate some animals,
things of that nature.
The Franciscan friars embrace
them as brothers and sisters.
- The problem is that nobody
told the Indians,
and they're not always ready
for a conquest of any kind.
- If you're seeking people
to convert them,
there's still
that superiority that,
"My ways are better
than your ways."
- Instead of engaging in the
types of spiritual diplomacy
that native people are used to,
they're trying to sort of
push them towards
complete conversion.
- So that's where
the gifts come in.
- The gifts were really
important symbols
of spiritual
and political connections,
to have networks, to have
information, to have goods.
These were things that helped
leaders of native communities
become more powerful themselves.
- You make alliances
with Indians by doing
what they do with each other,
which is exchange gifts.
- So by 1597,
when newly appointed
Gonzalo Méndez de Canço
saw that St. Augustine
was struggling,
he immediately began brokering
native alliances with gifts.
- You're going to say, "Yes.
Yes. We'll accept your tea,"
but that's because the Spanish
are accepting your chiefs,
and so those chiefs are having
their power strengthened.
- But not all tribal leaders
were willing
to accept the Spanish.
In Gaule territory
in modern-day Georgia,
resistance to these Christian
missionaries had grown.
- After a generation of people
had been subjected
to proselytization
and conversion,
some of the groups
really became very hostile,
particularly the Guale people.
- The Guale uprising
happened just four months
after Governor Canço arrived.
It was allegedly started
by the heir apparent
to the paramount
chief of Tolomato.
He was known as Don Juanillo,
or Little John.
- Don Juanillo wanted
to take a second wife,
and the resident Franciscan
friar at Tolomato said,
"I don't think so."
- [Speaking Spanish]
- "You've been baptized.
You're going to behave
as a good Christian,
and you'll be quite content with
the one wife that you have."
- The friar threatened him
with preventing his rise
to chief of the tribe
when his father died,
and that angered the young man
just as much as being told
he could only have one wife.
- Don Juanillo did not
appreciate this interference
in his private affairs,
so he ventured
into the interior,
gathered a force of "infidels,"
the Spanish sources tell us,
and he returned,
and he ordered
the friar decapitated.
And then he put
the severed head...
He put the head on a pike
and placed that at Tolomato's
boat launch as a warning,
"Don't interfere in local
affairs in Tolomato."
- The war party then moved on
to other Guale communities,
and five more friars
were attacked.
♪♪
- Two of the friars
to be executed
asked to celebrate mass first.
- [Speaking Latin]
- And the executioners
sat around on the floor
while he celebrated mass...
and then when he finished,
they killed him.
♪♪
- Governor Canço was concerned
that the unrest could spread.
Although he lacked any
hard evidence
about who led the massacre,
he blamed the incident
on Juanillo's decision
to take a second wife.
He also blamed the friars
who were killed.
- It's a convenient
story for him.
So as he writes the letter,
he concludes by saying,
"The friars deserved it.
They were interfering
in political matters,
in matters over which
they had no jurisdiction."
- In fact, a new theory
actually points
to a different perpetrator.
Witnesses claimed it wasn't
Juanillo who led the war party.
It was another Guale chief
named Don Domingo,
who then convinced the governor
that Juanillo was to blame.
Canço asked him to bring
Juanillo in to face trial,
but instead, Don Domingo served
up his own brand of justice.
♪♪
- When the battle ends,
there on the ground
deceased were Don Juanillo,
the paramount chief,
Don Francisco,
and every single male member
of the ruling family
of Tolomato, gone.
Tolomato was wiped off the map.
- The death of the chief
and all his heirs
left Don Domingo
the new successor.
Some historians now believe
that the uprising
was nothing more than a takeover
and that Little John was framed.
- That, essentially, the friars,
when the hostilities begin,
kind of got in the way.
- But several still believe
the friars were killed
for standing by their beliefs,
and the Vatican is now
considering sainthood
for the five martyrs of Georgia.
- These were apparently men
of great Christian courage
and peacefully went
about the celebration
of the highest form
of religious worship
they knew, the mass,
and then submitted
themself to the sword,
and they were ready to give up
their lives if necessary
and did so
without fighting back.
♪♪
- Whatever the reason,
there were no further challenges
to the work of the missionaries,
and peace was restored.
- The atmosphere in the
coastal islands was pacific.
People went back to
their ordinary tasks in life,
the friars and the
Indians together,
and health was restored to the
mission activity in the islands
and may even have profited.
♪♪
- And new missionaries arrived,
continuing to spread
the Gospel unharmed.
- One of the most famous
of the Franciscan friars
in the 16th
and early 17th century
was Francisco Pareja.
He learned their language.
Eventually, he wrote
a grammar of the language,
a dictionary of the language
and wrote out the prayers
of the Catholic Church
so that a typical Timucuan
could read it.
This is how the opening
sentences of The Lord's Prayer
sounded in Timucuan.
[Speaking Timucuan]
It has a kind of
musical charm to it,
but this was the Timucuan
language in sound
but written out in Spanish
consonants and vowels.
- The Indians are using books.
They're learning how
to read and write,
and this is a time
when some children
in great European cities
don't even have books.
- A recent study
of Timucuan manuscripts
have led to the realization
that not only did these
natives read Spanish,
but they also wrote
in their native tongue.
- We have about 1,000 pages
of Timucua.
Timucua is the first indigenous
written grammatical language
in the United States.
- Flagler College distinguished
professor of religion
Dr. Timothy Johnson has been
working with other scholars
to compare the Spanish
and Timucua versions
of 17th-century
religious writings.
- And interestingly enough,
sometimes,
the translations
don't always match up.
There's one story
of a shepherdess
where it's set in the mountains,
and reference to
mountains is eliminated.
Why?
Because there's no mountains.
People can't relate.
They rewrite the story
in such a way like
any great storyteller, right,
like any great preacher
or teacher,
redoes the story so it
resonates with the audience.
- Another example is
from The Confessionario,
a document written by Father
Pareja to help friars decide
whether someone had sinned
in the eyes of the church.
- There is a whole series
of what are called superstitions
in The Confessionario,
and the priest is supposed
to ask the Timucua,
"Are you doing this?
Are you doing that?"
One, for example, says, "Do you
take the antlers of the deer
and praying
believe that you will then
be able to catch another deer
as part of this
devil's ceremony?"
So that's the Spanish,
but the Timucua leaves out
any reference to the devil,
so when the Timucua person
puts it into Timucua,
he or she drops the whole
demon part of the text.
- We understood the creator
the same way
everyone understands
the creator, the breath-giver.
The conflict came amongst
a lot of tribes
when friars would try
to define what the devil was.
- You might have ideas of gods
who are evil, gods who are good,
but to wrap it all up into one
and say that anything
that has to do with spirits
that are malevolent is
the devil is a big, big jump.
- This disagreeable spirit
that has been identified
as the devil could be
that same spirit
that have came into our village
and protected us from a bear.
You know, these are what
they call good medicine.
- It's believed that
these Timucuan books
were written in the late 1500s.
They were published
in the early 1600s.
- So we're talked about a level
of literacy that,
simply up to this point in time,
has not really been recognized,
literacy among many
of the indigenous peoples.
- But while culture
and education flourished
at the missions
in the outlying countryside,
the town of St. Augustine
was still struggling to survive.
It seemed, every time the town
managed to rebuild,
it fell to the mercy
of another disaster.
♪♪
In early 1599, another fire
ravaged the town,
destroying 14 houses
and the Franciscan friary,
and then, just
a few months later...
♪♪
A devastating hurricane struck.
- Basically, the water came up,
passed right over the city.
It was enough to inundate
the whole city.
- They reported that the water
was face-high in the streets.
- One more raid,
one more epidemic,
one more hurricane
where it looked like
the very survivability
of St. Augustine
was at stake.
- Governor Méndez de Canço
realized
that the settlers
would always be vulnerable
as long as they had to rely
on others for food.
He brought in new groups
of Timucuan and Guale Indians
from the north
and used them to cultivate the
savannas and make them arable.
- [Speaking Spanish]
- It was swampland,
a mosquito-infested area
that couldn't grow
much of anything.
According to documents
in the Archives of the Indies,
corn production increased
more than three times
what it had been in the
entire decade before he arrived.
♪♪
- This is one of two
wooden chests
that survived the trip across
the ocean with Governor Canço
when he sailed back to Spain,
carrying maize seed
from St. Augustine,
but Javier says it was Canço
who introduced corn
to the northern part of Spain.
The corn from St. Augustine
would become the first export
from what later would
become the United States.
One year before Jamestown
was founded,
the settlement of St. Augustine
had already made a major
contribution to Spain's economy.
♪♪
In the nearly half-century
that this colony
had been in existence,
it had finally become
a viable city
with many of the amenities
of life back in Europe.
It had established
the first parish school
and the first indigen hospital
in what is now America.
♪♪
But by the early 1600s,
Spain began to wonder
if St. Augustine
was worth keeping.
The history of St. Augustine
almost came to an end.
King Philip Il had died,
and his son had taken over.
- [Speaking Spanish]
- The Spanish empire radically
changed from Philip Il
to Philip Ill,
who wasn't a powerful king
and didn't rule the empire
in the personal way
Philip Il did.
Philip Ill handed the empire
over to the bureaucrats,
who questioned the convenience
of keeping garrisons
like at St. Augustine.
♪♪
- Governor Méndez de Canço
and the missionaries pleaded
that they have come too far
to leave everything behind.
The king deliberated
for more than a year
and finally agreed
to keep St. Augustine
as a Spanish colony,
but by then, it was 1608,
a whole year after the English
had brazenly staked a claim
in Spanish territory
at Jamestown.
- By the time it came
into being,
St. Augustine was up
for urban renewal.
♪♪
- The king's unwillingness to
stop English encroachment
would turn out to be
a grave error.
Unlike his father who had
routed out the French
when they had violated
Spanish sovereignty here
40 years earlier,
Philip Ill decided
not to challenge
the establishment of Jamestown.
♪♪
It was a decision that would
ultimately affect the battle
for Spain's supremacy
in America.
- King Philip Ill
issued an edict
that there was no more going
up and down the coastline,
putting out fires.
Concentrate on building up
your own cities and defense,
and really, there never was any
need to worry about Jamestown.
It never had a military force,
was never a threat
to Spanish Florida.
- The Jamestown colony may not
have posed much of a threat
by itself,
but England did.
- Shortly after Jamestown,
other settlements began.
Spain could not put out
all of those fires.
- For the next 50 years,
Spain turned its energies
largely to Latin America
and the western part of
what's now the United States.
That allowed England to gain
a foothold in the U.S.
from Massachusetts
to the Carolinas.
♪♪
By the mid-1600s,
the vulnerability of the
only Spanish settlement
left on the East Coast
was about to become
tragically apparent.
It was May 29th, 1668.
A French physician
named Pierre Pique,
who had recently been forced
to leave St. Augustine in shame,
was on a ship headed to Havana.
He was about to get his revenge.
- And he and the governor
have become very acrimonious
towards each other.
- St. Augustine was now
under the leadership
of Governor Francisco
de la Guerra y de la Vega,
a reputed ladies' man.
- The governor apparently
has a number of women
that he is spending time
with inappropriately,
according to the records.
- Some of the governor's
paramours had also
shared confidences with Pique.
♪♪
- Pique ends up
insulting the governor,
and the governor publicly
insults him, slaps him,
which, of course, in the 1660s,
was a terrible breach of honor,
and actually orders him
to leave the town.
- But before Pique's ship
reached Havana,
it was captured at sea
by a pirate ship
led by the English sympathizer
Robert Searle.
- Now he is a nasty pirate.
He'd probably shoot
his own people.
- Searle and his men
boarded the ship
and took his passengers captive.
Pique realized he had
valuable information
that could not
only spare his life
but could also serve to
retaliate against the governor.
He asked for an audience
with Searle.
He told the pirate that a
large quantity of silver bars
had recently been recovered
from the wreck
of a treasure ship
off the coast,
and it was being held for
safekeeping in St. Augustine.
- And he's feeling vengeful,
and so he gives Searle
all the information he has
about how the best way
to get into St. Augustine,
what the timing would be,
when the guards might be on
alert and when they wouldn't be,
and so he helps them
get into the town.
- And you better not be lying.
- Searle knew that no one
at the fort would suspect
that this Spanish supply ship
had pirates onboard.
And that was his Trojan horse.
- He came in on a different ship,
not on a pirate ship
but on this treasury vessel
under disguise.
♪♪
- They attacked at midnight.
People were asleep.
They liked to catch them
literally in their beds.
♪♪
- There was chaos in the streets
as people tried to escape.
Official reports describe what
happened to one 18-year-old girl
and her baby sister, remarkable
because women and children
were usually left out of
the documentary records.
- One of the stories
that probably grips us
more than some of the others
is the young girl,
Estefania de Cigarroa,
who runs out of her house and is
carrying her sister with her,
and one of the pirates shoots,
and the ball from his gun
kills the child in her arms
and actually lodges
into Estefania's chest.
♪♪
- Estefania survived.
When the carnage ended,
Searle's men had killed
over 60 people,
and they'd taken about 70 men,
women, and children as hostages.
The governor managed to
negotiate a trade with Searle,
giving the pirates
wood and water
in exchange for the release
of the hostages,
but Searle didn't
release everyone.
He kept the natives
and Africans as his spoils,
then headed to the Caribbean
to sell them as slaves.
♪♪
When Spain heard of this,
the Crown realized it could
no longer risk losing La Florida
to foreign invaders and outlaws.
- It pushed the Spanish crown
into appropriating
more money to build a new fort.
- And that's why Castillo de
San Marcos was built.
- It had now been more
than a century
since St. Augustine was founded.
During that time, its residents
had built nine wooden forts.
None of them had lasted.
But a unique kind of stone
had begun to be quarried
on Anastasia Island
known as coquina.
It was made of tiny
shell fragments
that had been compressed
and fused together
over centuries
on the ocean floor.
It wouldn't burn,
it wouldn't rot,
and it appeared to be impervious
to gunfire.
The structure is now
the oldest masonry stone fort
remaining in the U.S.
- It was a major turning point
in the history of the southeast
because this building
of Castillo de San Marcos,
the strong fortress,
really scares off,
I think, a lot of attempts.
♪♪
- They were about to find out
whether this new fortress
would hold.
In 1702, English colonists
from South Carolina
launched their first attack
on Spanish Florida
as English troops marched
through the Florida countryside,
destroying Spanish
missions along the way.
The entire town of St. Augustine
took shelter
inside the Castillo.
♪♪
- On November 10th, 1702,
the gate is shut...
♪♪
And the 1,500 people
are in there,
and they don't know
for how long.
- There was no way to know
whether this new fort could
actually hold off the British...
♪♪
Whether they had enough
supplies to outlast the siege...
♪♪
Or whether they'd be
taken captive or killed
at the end of it all.
♪♪
All they could do was wait.