THE JOURNEY OF "ANANYA" STARTED IN
RAMNARAIN RUIA COLLEGE AS A ONE-ACT PLAY.
TODAY, I FEEL EMOTIONAL WHILE
PRESENTING IT AS A MOVIE.
I THANK ALL MY GURUS,
FRIENDS, AND COLLEAGUES
FOR HELPING ME ON THIS JOURNEY.
- PRATAP MADHAVRAO PHAD
Mr. Sarpotdar, think about it.
You can still back down.
Are you sure you can do it?
Ms. Deshmukh, I promise.
This ride…
will be the most memorable
ride in your life.
-The IV.
-Yes, sir.
Move, please.
Everyone, please move.
Step aside. Come on, move.
-Please wait outside.
-Sorry.
Patient's name?
Excuse me, sir.
-Yes.
-What's the patient's name?
Please tell me the patient's name!
This year, the M.Com gold medal goes to…
Ananya!
Ananya Deshmukh!
Congrats.
Thank you.
-Ananya!
We're proud of you, Ananya!
SAVITRIBAI PHULE PUNE UNIVERSITY
GRADUATION CEREMONY 2019-20
Three cheers for Ananya Deshmukh,
-hip, hip…
-Hooray!
-Hip, hip…
-What's with all the cheering?
-Hey, come on!
-Don't be so modest all the time.
-Hey…
I mean show some excitement.
I just got a first class,
yet I'm more excited than you.
-Congratulations on that.
-Thank you.
-Congratulations.
Hey, Ananya, will you marry me?
What are you--
-Sorry.
-Sorry, dude.
-Better luck next time.
-Okay.
-Hey, shut up. What are you--
-You know you're a serial heartbreaker.
-That must be the 100th guy you rejected.
-Shut up.
You know I'll only think about
all this after I become a CA.
-Madam, you're great. You're impossible.
-Hey--
-You are--
-What rubbish! I won't spare you, wait!
Hey, what is this? She's been waiting
for you for so long. This is not done.
-Hey, don't say anything about her.
-Oh, really?
I agree your dad gifted you this bicycle,
but you just love it too much.
She might even replace me as
a bridesmaid at your wedding.
No, babe.
-I want both of you as my bridesmaids.
-You're impossible!
-Oh my God, I'm dead.
-What? What happened?
Ananya, I've gotta go!
-Would you just tell me what happened?
-"Mom has summoned me.
So, I'd better hurry up and flee."
-Wow.
-Just go, dude.
-Just go.
-That was great.
Okay, bye. I'll see you later.
-Yes, have a safe ride.
-You too.
-Please step on it. It's urgent.
-Yes, sir.
This veranda.
-What about it?
-It's in the southwest.
-Isn't that great?
-Not at all.
I have been avoiding
this topic for so long,
but not anymore.
Because now, I have understood
the science of architecture.
-Okay.
-We changed the direction of the cupboard,
-and boom, Ananya got a medal.
-That's right.
And poor Ananya thinks she got
a medal because of her studies!
I mean--
Anyway…
I agree with you. A hundred percent.
-We'll do as you say.
-Okay.
Close the veranda permanently.
Build a wall there, and then you'll see.
What can I see after
building a wall though!
Nikam, come and help me, please.
Please!
Ananya.
Where will you keep your new medals?
There is no space left in your cupboard.
Idea!
You can keep your medals in his cupboard.
I mean it's completely empty.
He hasn't won any medals, so--
-What did you say?
-Hey, careful! Don't pull my hair!
-You know what?
-What?
Great people believe in rewards…
-not medals and awards.
-Really?
Just watch.
One day, Mr. Dhananjay's cupboard
will be filled with money.
No, listen.
-Your friend here is a scholar, right?
-Yes, she is.
Then tell her to clear the CA
final exams on the first attempt.
She will. What will you do in return?
I'll sing her praises in public.
-Done. Ananya, challenge accepted, okay?
-Yes--
You'd better not run and hide
when she clears her exams!
Guys, I mean…
I know we're just joking around,
but I can't accept this challenge.
-Why?
-Why? Are you scared?
-Hey, shut up. She's not scared.
-No,
-he's right. I am scared.
-Why?
Because then I would have to see
my brother lose the challenge.
What a great comeback!
-You're dead meat!
-Bro, no. Stop it.
-Stop it, bro!
-Hey, careful!
-You'll hurt yourself!
-Hey, what's happening?
-Guys, you'll fall, careful.
-Dhananjay, what happened? Calm down.
-What is it?
-Yeah, tell me.
Priyanka, tell them what happened.
You are so going to lose.
-We'll see.
-Yes, you will.
Dhananjay, you don't have to wait
for her results to sing her praises.
I have fixed Ananya's marriage with a guy.
-What?
-Is this really true?
-Yes.
-What? Ananya, don't tell me! What's this?
If you hear the guy's name,
then, even now,
you'll shower her with your praises.
-Wow, that's great.
-When did this happen?
Wait a minute.
Who is this guy?
Hello.
This is Madhavrao Sarpotdar.
Yes, I know.
They're big shots in our village.
But they're not concerned
about our financial condition.
They just want a beautiful, educated,
and a well-behaved girl.
But Dad, what about my CA finals?
You know it's my dream.
It's our dream.
And now, theirs too.
That's why we've only agreed
to do the engagement now.
The wedding will happen after your exam.
Still, don't you think we're rushing it?
You trust me, right?
-Of course, Dad.
-Then just wait and watch.
Your life will be filled with so much joy
that both of your hands won't
be enough to contain it.
Do one thing.
See the guy's photo.
If you don't like him,
I'll respect your decision.
Please wait outside.
The doctor will speak
to you once he's here.
This is a small gift from us.
Thank you.
-Where is he?
-Please have a seat.
-This is Suhas Nikam.
-Namaste.
-He's an LIC agent.
-He's our neighbor.
-I live right there.
-Oh, God!
-What are you doing?
Dad's blocking my view.
Please sit.
He is hot.
He's my son, Dhananjay.
-He's got a distinction in MBA.
-I see.
He's currently looking for a job.
-That's great. All the best.
-Thank you.
Dhananjay…
check on the refreshments.
Auntie…
something's fishy.
I mean…
Dad is an ordinary officer.
And they are the owners of MS Corporation.
They just knew each other formally.
Then where did this marriage come from?
He saw Ananya's photo
and fell in love with her? Just like that?
Is it that easy?
This only happens in movies.
Don't you think it's odd?
Which direction do you face
while sleeping?
Go.
-Go and serve them this.
-But--
-Just go.
-Tell me--
I sleep upside down.
Ask them if they'd like to have something.
No, thank you.
But I must say,
the carrot halvah is amazing.
Yes, it's delicious.
-Ananya made it.
-Really?
Dad-- Dad made it.
She hates lying.
Okay, but I loved that she lied.
They're childhood friends.
She loves Ananya.
-Okay.
-I see.
Anyway, if you want
to ask her something, please…
Not at all.
In fact, if she asks me
to sing, I'll gladly do it.
Even my wife and Shekhar won't
mind showcasing their skills.
Right, Shekhar?
Hey, stop it.
But on a serious note,
I'd like to say something
if you guys don't mind.
-Why an arranged marriage?
-Sorry?
I mean…
did you not like…
anyone until now?
Honestly,
it's not like I didn't like anyone.
But very honestly,
I never met anyone who would make me go…
"This is it.
She's the one."
-We'll take your leave, Mr. Deshmukh.
-Yeah.
-We'll be waiting for Ananya's answer.
-Yes, sir.
-Goodbye.
By the way, Mr. Dhananjay,
please come and meet me in my office.
I'd like you to join our company
as a business development manager.
-Congratulations.
-Thank you.
-Congrats.
All the best.
-Okay, bye.
-Bye.
See you, dear.
Keep it up.
-Dude…
-Congrats, dear.
Congratulations.
-Dhananjay…
-Yes?
Where is your dad?
-How did this happen?
-Ananya was on her bicycle
when a tempo hit her.
Deshmukh, what did the doctor say?
Deshmukh!
-No, Deshmukh--
-I'm very happy today.
-No…
-I won't listen to you.
What's this behavior? Oh, God!
Ananya found her happiness,
but even I found something today.
I never told you this.
But today, I will.
Back in our village,
our family…
was well known.
We had a big house and our own farm.
We were rich.
We were respected.
We were happy.
My dad was a simple man.
He was very naive.
My uncle…
took advantage of my dad's simple nature.
He cajoled money from him
in the name of so-called brotherhood.
We never even realized it.
My dad…
couldn't bear that shock.
Relax.
That night, I decided
to go and question my uncle.
But Sunita stopped me.
We left our village, our home, and came
to Pune only because she insisted.
We started afresh.
We worked hard.
We raised our children.
Everything was going well.
But then, all of a sudden, Sunita left me.
Again, I ended up being alone.
I just didn't know what to do.
And these scoundrels from our village
were laughing at me.
They would say,
"He's acting as if he's some big shot."
Now, I'll show them…
who I really am!
I'll make sure my uncle witnesses
the grandeur of Ananya's wedding.
At the wedding,
I'll be standing tall…
right next to Mr. Sarpotdar.
At the wedding, these scoundrels will
raise their hands to bless the couple,
but their heads will be hanging in shame.
That's it.
I can't wait to bruise my uncle's ego…
at Ananya's engagement tomorrow.
-Tell me.-Are you sure?
Remember me? I am Shekhar Sarpotdar.
We recently got engaged.
I'm sorry.
I know I have been
ignoring you a lot lately.
But what can I do? Tell me.
You are distracting me.
I read your WhatsApp messages
more than my books nowadays.
At the library,
I sit in the corner…
and listen to your voice messages.
I talk to you every day on my way home.
And then, you FaceTime me, and I…
JANAKI HOUSE 1950
What are you doing here?
We're going on a long drive.
You're joking, right?
Not at all.
I'm going to fail.
I'm surely going to fail.
What do you mean?
Are you planning to see me
directly at our wedding?
-You're overreacting.
-No, I'm not.
By the way, what is it called?
-What do couples exchange at the wedding?
-Vows.
-Yes.
Are you directly going to see me then?
-Yeah.
-What?
Did you forget that your parents want
an educated girl as their daughter-in-law?
What if I fail the exam
and they refuse to accept me?
Not a problem. I'll leave them for you.
-Thank you. Thank you so much.
-No, I'm not joking.
I'm not doubting you.
Okay, I promise.
I promise once I feel
I'm well prepared for the exam,
I'll see you…
once a month.
Twice a month?
-Okay, thrice a month. That's it.
-Okay, done.
Okay.
But only on one condition.
Right now, we're going on a long drive.
Why don't we go…
-on a long drive next month--
-Okay, fine.
Keep studying hard. Do well in the exam.
Make your family proud.
Who am I, anyway? Right?
-No problem. Bye.
-Listen to me-- Okay.
Okay. Done.
But even I have one condition.
Let's go.
Magic.
Thank you.
Mr. Sarpotdar, think about it.
You can still back down.
Are you sure you can do it?
Ms. Deshmukh, I promise.
This ride…
will be the most memorable
ride in your life.
Sh…
Shekhar…
He's had a minor injury.
There is nothing to worry about.
No!
No.
I shouldn't have said yes to her.
We should have gone by car.
Shekhar, please don't think about it now.
Relax, okay?
Relax.
Mr. Deshmukh…
Shekhar has been discharged.
-Okay.
-Please take care of Ananya.
-If you need any help--
-No.
Thank you.
Mr. Deshmukh, don't worry.
We're all there with you.
Take care, okay?
Dad…
I'll go and see Ananya.
She's asleep.
I'll come later.
Shall we go, Dad?
Bye.
Hey, you're up?
What happened? Are you in pain?
-No, there is something in my eye.
-Okay.
I'm fine.
You just missed him.
Shekhar was discharged.
So, he had come to see you.
But he said you were asleep.
He said he'd come to see you later.
He was feeling really bad
about what happened to you.
He loves you so much.
In fact, all of us love you.
You know what?
Mr. Sarpotdar had come to see me.
He held my hand tightly…
and said, "Don't worry.
We're all there for you."
They're very kind people.
Hey.
Don't think that everything's
finished, alright?
Don't ever think that I'd be
embarrassed to walk with you
just because people stare--
No. You'd better not think that.
I…
Are you mad?
Just take care of yourself, dear.
Don't worry about anything else.
Take care.
Everything will be fine.
He loves you so much.
He said he'd come to see you later.
They're very kind people.
Don't think that everything's
finished, alright?
Don't ever think that I'd be
embarrassed to walk with you
just because people stare--
You'd better not think that.
AVINASH M. DESHMUKH
-Priyanka…
-Yes.
Let's go.
You didn't take me seriously earlier,
but at least, listen to me now.
Throw away that broken bicycle!
Rama, it was just an accident.
Here.
Careful.
OFFICE
Hello.
Mr. Sarpotdar, it's me. Yes.
Ananya was discharged from
the hospital yesterday.
We took her home.
So, I thought I should inform you.
Yeah. She's fine.
How is Shekhar?
He had said he'd come to see her.
He went abroad?
For work?
Oh, you'll be coming to see her together!
When-- Hello?
-Hello!
-Deshmukh.
Hello?
-Deshmukh, come on, hurry up. Sir--
-Yes, coming.
Hello?
Bro, is Dad alright?
He's just worried about your wedding.
Nothing else.
Don't worry. Everything will be alright.
You know how he is.
Bro, I think we should tell him…
that what he wants is
not going to happen now.
-Because Shekhar--
-Won't say no to you.
Am I right?
I mean, we all know…
how much he loves you.
Exactly.
Bro!
You know…
Mr. Sarpotdar had told me…
that he would fix my meeting
with his company's HR for my job.
So…
Don't worry about Dad.
Ananya.
Ananya!
-Dad--
-Dad, I don't want to get married.
What?
Yes. I don't want
to be a burden on anyone.
-Burden?
-Wait, Dad.
Hey…
you were telling me something
else before some time.
No, bro.
I was telling you exactly this,
but I guess you didn't get it.
Dad, please try to understand.
Call them right now
and tell them
that I don't want to get married.
Ananya, do you think marriage is a joke?
I have already told everyone in the
village. All our relatives know about it.
Dad-- Listen to me, Ananya.
You will have to get married
someday, right?
Everything might not be so easy then.
I don't care, bro.
Dad, why don't you understand?
Just break off the engagement
before they break it off.
-But why would they break it off?
-Exactly.
Dear, Mr. Sarpotdar held my hand
and promised me.
Do you not believe me? Let's call them.
-Let me call them.
-Dad!
-I'll talk to them.
-Dad, don't. Please tell him.
-Why are you being impatient?
-Please tell him to stop.
Wait. Let him call them.
Dad, that day, Shekhar--
-Hello.
-Yes.
Mr. Sarpotdar…
-Tell me.
-Yeah.
I called you to ask…
you were going to come
to see Ananya, right?
When are you coming?
Actually, Mr. Deshmukh…
I wanted to tell you
this face-to-face, but--
Please don't get me wrong.
But we don't think
we can go ahead with this wedding anymore.
And…
I hope you understand
where we're coming from.
Hello?
That day…
Shekhar purposely left
without meeting me, Dad.
But Dad, don't worry, okay?
I'll manage. I'll live on my own.
Bro, please talk to him.
Dad…
you are most important to me.
After what happened,
my family should have felt bad.
-But they are feeling angry.
-Can you blame them?
After what the Sarpotdars did to us…
anyone would feel angry.
But I didn't expect him
to marry me after the accident.
In fact, I would have requested
him not to marry me.
What surprised me is that…
he didn't even say goodbye
to me before leaving.
What is your password?
Password!
Shekhar.
Now, listen to me carefully.
From now on,
you will not think about Shekhar ever.
You will not even talk about him…
swear on me.
Now, you're single.
And your new password is… "Ananya."
Bro.
Bro!
Ananya!
She is not here.
-Ananya--
-Dad, stop.
Call Priyanka.
Thirty thousand?
It's too much.
Okay. Thank you.
What happened, Deshmukh?
-Sir, tea.
-I am looking for a nurse for Ananya.
But it's expensive.
Isn't your son MBA?
What is he doing?
Bro--
Don't lose hope.
You will get a job.
I know that.
But Dad doesn't seem to understand.
What happened?
He says that even though I am an MBA,
right now, my degree is of no use,
so I should just do…
some clerical job.
In short, he's okay
with me doing a random job
as long as I'm earning money.
-But why?
-Because of you.
Because he wants to hire…
a full-time nurse for you.
I told him that we should call some girl
from the village who needs work.
But he just wouldn't listen.
No one listens to me anyway.
Leave it. Pass me that file.
-Sorry.
-No, it's--
-Your friend here is a scholar, right?
-Yes, she is.
Then tell her to clear the CA
final exams on the first attempt.
She will. What will you do in return?
I'll sing her praises in public.
-Ananya!
-Yes, Dad?
Come out now. If not for you,
at least, take a break for your books!
-Dad, I'm almost done. Just two minutes.
-Okay.
You mean two hours.
Dad…
Dad!
I was thinking--
I was thinking…
that once they remove my dressing,
I'll start my CA preparations again.
Priyanka will write my exams for me.
And yes, you don't have
to get a nurse for me.
I'll manage.
Don't--
Careful.
Hey, drive slowly.
-Would you please stop irritating me?
-No! What will you do?
-Do whatever you want!
-Alright! That's it!
Bro!
What are you doing?
If my certificates don't have any
value, why keep them?
Right! What else can you do!
Run away from your responsibilities!
-You can't do anything anyway!
-That's right!
-Bro, please wait.
-I can't do anything.
-After all, I am your son.
-What did you say?
Your uncle stole your property
from right under your nose.
-He couldn't do anything about it.
-Bro, please stop.
-Listen, bro--
-Ananya, don't come between us!
My situation right now
is not that different.
Everything is happening right
in front of my eyes, but I'm helpless.
Tell me, am I wrong?
-What did you do?
-Are you really asking me that?
Even in that situation, I stood
on my own feet. I raised you both.
But you forgot all that.
You only remembered
that your father didn't do anything then!
But let me tell you one thing!
I was just waiting patiently.
I was waiting for a perfect opportunity.
And I had got that opportunity.
I had planned to go to the village
after Ananya's wedding
and show off in front of everyone
who had laughed at me once.
Everything was going as per my plan,
but then, this happened and--
Hey, but don't think that…
I have lost, alright?
We can't do anything now, Dad.
I can still teach them a lesson.
Forget about it, Dad.
I swear I will teach them a lesson!
I won't spare them!
It's of no use now, Dad.
You should have stood your ground then.
I don't know about your respect,
but you could have surely
saved our property.
-It'd have been of some use to me today.
-What?
What do I have? Tell me.
I am begging for a job despite
having a distinction in MBA.
Apparently, a distinction is not enough.
Because others have strong contacts,
or luck, or money that they can offer
as a bribe in exchange for a job.
But what do I have?
What should I do?
By the way, who told you to go
on a long drive on a bicycle?
-Dhananjay--
-Answer me!
Shekhar was insisting
on going by car, right?
But no, you just had to go by
your stupid bicycle, hadn't you?
And then we all know what happened!
I'm telling you…
I got a job,
but she just couldn't be happy for me.
Why would she be happy?
After all, since childhood,
all she ever wanted to do was outshine me.
-What are you--
-And you!
You only cared about Ananya!
Did you ever think
about anyone else other than her?
Ananya's laugh, Ananya this, Ananya that!
You were only bothered about her!
There she is! Your Ananya!
Go ahead and praise her to the skies!
Have you gone mad? What are you saying?
-Because of you, I lost my job--
-Stop it, Dhananjay!
Step back! Have you gone mad?
Go inside!
-Throw away that damn bicycle!
-Just go inside!
A flock of birds
Flew away
One of them
Got left behind
The one who used to fly high once
Is afraid of heights today
The one who used to sing once
Is not even chirping today
The sky is filled
With dark clouds
One of them
Got left behind
There is no strength left
In these wings now
There is no home
To go back to
The branch has broken
The leaves have fallen
There is nothing but
A dark shadow everywhere
There is no ray of hope
All the doors
Have now closed
A flock of birds
Flew away
One of them
Got left behind
There seems to be
No way out
Is anyone there?
Priyanka!
Priyanka, can you--
Is anybody there?
Help! There's a fire here! Help!
Priyanka!
Help!
Can anybody hear me?
Oh my God!
Look at the condition of this room.
I wonder how she put out the fire!
It's nothing but a miracle.
She said she was going to sleep.
And I was going to be late,
that's why I locked the door.
It's my fault.
-Can this be fixed?
-I'll have to check, sir.
-Okay, I'll be right here.
-Okay, sir.
Hello. Hello!
Stupid network!
-Hello!
-Hey, what happened?
-Whom are you calling?
-This is it.
Now, I will find a nurse anyhow.
I don't care how much it costs.
Mr. Deshmukh, calm down.
Priyanka, get some water.
Why are you worrying so much?
So what if Priyanka got a job?
I'll still be here.
I'll take care of Ananya.
You have already done enough for us.
-Hey, come on!
-You consider me your friend, right?
-Nikam, don't get me wrong. I just mean--
-I'll find a job.
Okay now?
We'll cross that bridge
when we come to it.
Let's not discuss this anymore.
Sir, the bicycle can be fixed.
Do you want me to fix it?
No.
We don't.
-You can take it.
-Okay, sir.
Ananya!
Today, I told myself…
that humans don't have hands since birth.
They only have two feet.
You are a burning fire
You are the strength in wings
You are the tune of a song
You are a fighter
You are a storm
You are fearless
You can carve your own path
The world will salute your determination
What can she do?
Nikam, don't you know?
She's completely dependent on us now.
So? Do you want her to stay
at home all her life?
Shouldn't she go out?
I don't know all that. All I know is that…
I'm not going to have unreal
expectations from now on.
Let's go.
The world will salute your determination
CHILD WELFARE ORGANIZATION, PUNE
CHILD WELFARE ORGANIZATION
Don't worry. We're all with you.
Thank you.
Come on, Ananya! You can do it! Do it!
Come on, quick! Quick! Right!
One, two, three.
Now, bend slowly.
Go slow.
Have patience
Turn your pain into your strength
Let your emotions fly high
The sky is the limit
Let your mind wander
It's your time to shine
You can carve your own path
The world will salute your determination
Priyanka!
Priyanka, I got a job.
And you are the first person
with whom I'm sharing this news.
Please, don't be mad at me.
You are so concerned about how I feel…
but you hurt your sister
who loves you so much!
And by the way,
she doesn't need your help anymore.
Just wait and watch.
Soon, Ananya will be back
to being her own independent self.
Flowers of hope
Have bloomed again
Doors have opened
To new opportunities
A bright new day
Is waiting for you
It's time
For you to stand up on your own feet
Smell the fragrant fresh air
Come on, get up
And start anew
Let your emotions fly high
The sky is the limit
Let your mind wander
It's your time to shine
You can carve your own path
The world will salute your determination
You are a lotus in the mud
You are a real diamond
You are fearless
You are unbeatable
You are a star
Shining bright in the night sky
You are the fiery lightning
You are the flowing river
You're a champ
You're a warrior
You're Laxmi, Sharda, and Durga
You're unstoppable
Knock down the obstacles in your way
You can carve your own path
One, two, three, four, five, six,
seven, eight.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
Ananya!
You did it!
Come on, you can be happy now!
You passed the exam!
TWO FEET OVERPOWERED 30,000 HANDS
She insisted on not telling you anything.
Because she wanted to prove herself first.
She's the one who had an accident,
but you two were behaving as
if you became handicapped.
Your daughter is pure gold.
She stood up on her own feet…
and inspired many like me in her journey.
It doesn't matter if we're heading
in the wrong direction.
As long as we have a strong determination
and we are honest,
the universe will help us
reach our destination.
I never realized…
that my daughter is my real treasure.
She is my pride.
Like an idiot,
I was looking for it outside.
I feel ashamed to even ask
for Ananya's forgiveness.
Priyanka.
When will we be getting Ananya's
final result from the institute?
In two days.
Okay, then I need your help.
-Excuse me.
-Yeah.
Thank you.
Welcome.
-May I?
-Sorry.
-What--
-Hi, Ananya.
Excuse me?
You became a CA on your first attempt.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
I'm sorry, but do I know you?
That sorry was not needed.
-Sorry?
-Yes.
This is perfect,
but the one before that was not needed.
What do you mean?
You don't know me because
we're meeting for the first time.
-Okay.
-Jai. Jai Dixit.
Can I get some chilled water?
-Can you please tell me who you are?
-"Please"?
Come on, don't be so formal, Ananya.
Had you not been so formal,
I would have given you a better answer.
Actually, it's not important whether
I'm being formal or informal.
-It's important to know who you are.
-There you are.
-Who are you?
-Jai Dixit.
-How do you know my name?
-Someone from your building told me.
Have you been stalking me?
Not exactly. That would be odd.
I have just been following
you to your library.
You mean you come to my library?
Yes, the corner near
the window is my spot.
Now don't tell me you have also
taken the CA final exam with me.
No, I wouldn't lie like that.
But yes,
I have clicked your many pictures.
Here is the latest one.
Today, I am giving it to you because…
Wish you a very happy birthday, Ananya.
Okay. Now, can you tell me
why you're doing this?
Yes, sure. In fact,
I was dying to tell you this.
Actually, Ananya, I love you.
I love you.
What?
I love you. Yes.
Okay.
Now what?
Nothing. Don't think about it much.
Just say yes.
-Then we'll get married.
-And why would I do that?
Because I deserve it.
Look, Ananya, I'm ready
to tell you everything about me.
But what if I don't want to hear it?
Doesn't matter. So, you already
know my name. It's Jai Dixit.
I'm 28 years old. I passed my
BSc exam on my second attempt.
To be honest, I don't earn a lot.
But I'm happy with whatever I earn.
I wake up at 11:00 a.m. every day.
I drink when I get bored,
and I smoke… often.
What a personality! What a biodata!
God bless you. Now, please leave.
We haven't even gotten
to the best part yet.
-Oh, we're not done?
-No.
-Talk to the table then.
-Ananya!
Ananya, just hear me out.
At least, accept my gift.
You didn't even finish your meal.
More importantly,
you didn't let me finish my intro.
Come on, kid. Let the wooing begin.
The only thing that has managed to impress
me more than you is this camera.
I swear, Ananya. It has taught me a lot.
Listen, Ananya.
This camera taught me a lot.
It taught me how to focus
on important things in life
and ignore the unimportant ones.
-Listen--
-See this.
Just click this button,
and your favorite moment
will freeze forever.
Then you can carry it your whole life.
Interesting, right?
This is my passion now.
-Are you done?
-Not yet.
-Yeah.
-Are you done now?
-Just a minute.
-Hey--
-Yeah.
-I am not interested.
Ananya! Listen!
Ananya.
-Please don't think that--
-Excuse me!
Don't worry,
I'm not feeling pity for myself.
I want a life partner.
But even I have a choice.
Let's go.
-Happy birthday to you!
-Happy birthday, dear Ananya!
Enjoy the cake.
God bless you.
Priyanka.
It's time to fulfill my promise.
-Bro, please don't. I'll fall.
-Hey, be careful.
-Hey, don't let her fall.
-Bro, please stop it now.
-Walk slowly, please!
-Careful!
-Hey, she'll fall!
-Be careful!
She'll be scared.
Come on, get her down now.
-Careful.
Slowly.
He's so loving.
-Guys, let's take a photo.
-Yes!
-I want her to do this in the photo.
-No way.
-We should ask someone to take our photo.
-Let's ask someone--
-What if you had dropped me?
-Hey, it's a brand-new phone. Be careful.
-Ready?
-Smile!
You!
-What are you doing here?
-Photo.
You forgot to take it from me that day.
I thought you must be
feeling bad about it.
And I didn't want you to feel bad.
-That's why I came here.
-What happened, dear?
-Who is he?
-Hello, Dad. I'm Jai Dixit.
Hey, Dhananjay. How are you, buddy?
Auntie, namaste. You're looking beautiful.
-Uncle, all okay?
-Hey…
Priyanka, nice dress.
-Nice choice, actually.
-Are you done?
Give me the photo and leave.
-Why is she--
-Why is she being so rude?
-Photo.
-Why…
-That was a bit rude.
-Hey, sorry, but…
have we met before?
-And yet you know me?
-Yes.
And how do you know me?
-The same way he knows me.
-Yes.
What's with the silly questions?
He must be Ananya's friend. He must
have come here to wish her. Am I right?
No, Dad.
-Who told you he's my friend?
-He's not?
-Then who is he?
-Jai Dixit.
-What the--
-Jai…
We heard that.
Wait a minute. Ananya.
-He is not from our college, right?
-Right.
-Was he in our CA class?
-No.
-Would you stop?
-Wait, wait!
-He was not in your college.
-No.
-He was not in your CA class.
And yet he is here?
Not just me, all of us are here.
Then tell me one thing.
Why don't we sit somewhere
-and discuss this?
-No, listen to me.
Good point. Let's sit and discuss this.
-Yeah, let's sit here.
-Excuse me, get us some bhel poori!
-Guys, don't entertain him.
-Come. Please sit.
-But what exactly are we…
-Dad, please sit.
What are you guys doing?
-Would you guys have bhel poori?
-Well…
-Bhel poori?
-Right now?
-Yes.
-Alright. I'll have…
-the plain one.
-Oh my God!
Do you have sev poori?
One plate of sev poori.
What would you have, Dhananjay?
-Anything would do.
-Dad.
-Dad, what about you?
-I'll just have a taste.
Okay.
Now, if you have any questions--
Hello!
I'm leaving.
-Ananya!
-Stop her. What happened to her?
The girl just wouldn't let us eat.
-Ananya!
-What…
Should I make it or not?
Go ahead. Somebody will eat it.
-Ananya!
-Ananya, wait!
-Listen!
-Ananya! Stop!
-Ananya!
-No, you guys continue.
Have bhel poori.
I think she's upset about the photo.
Okay, but whose photo is it?
-Ananya's.
-Why do you have it?
He must have clicked it.
Don't you see he has a camera?
-I got it.
-What?
Ananya, please wait.
-No.
-They are going to find out someday.
-Find out what?
-Oh, God!
-What are they going to find out?
-That I want to marry you.
-You--
-What?
-I knew it.
-What are you saying--
-What happened?
Why are you staring at me like that?
-You want to get her married, right?
-Yes.
Then what's the issue?
She is a nice girl. She is beautiful.
You are right.
We want to get her married…
-but--
-What?
Nikam, Dhananjay, help me here.
-Ananya, how could you not tell me?
-You should have talked to us.
-Tell her…
-Please keep quiet!
Now, only I'll speak!
If someone interrupts me,
-I'll jump in the water.
-Hey, come on.
Listen,
I have nothing to do with him.
In fact, he met me yesterday
for the first time.
Even yesterday, he was talking rubbish.
And now, he's come here too.
Got it?
Except for the "talking rubbish"
part, everything else is true.
-That's exactly what happened.
-Wait.
How can you talk to my daughter like that?
-Exactly.
-How else should I have talked to her?
I mean how can you just
say you love her like that?
-You--
-Is there any other way to say that?
No, I mean,
how dare you propose marriage to her
right in front of me!
Marriage is the next step of love, Dad.
It does sound a bit funny, doesn't it?
-Okay, that's enough.
-Keep quiet.
Nikam, Dhananjay, are you guys
going to do something, or should I--
No, Dad-- Bro, wait. Let me handle this.
Listen, you…
leave from here right now.
Otherwise, we'll be forced to make
a complaint against you. So, just leave.
No, please don't do that.
It's not going to help anyone.
Instead, if you just say yes to me,
it'll be very helpful.
Priyanka, I can't handle him anymore.
-Hey, behave yourself--
-Priyanka, wait.
-What!
-Listen--
Dhananjay, wait.
Dad, wait.
You know what the problem is?
We need to have communication,
but there is only confusion.
See, I can understand.
You guys are very happy.
This news is hard to digest.
But it's okay. We'll talk about it later.
Okay? Now, I'll get going
because I'm a bit busy.
Bye, Dad. Ananya.
You--
-This guy was a pain in the neck.
-I know, right?
I still don't know who he is!
Jai Dixit.
Was that a joke?
CHILD WELFARE ORGANIZATION, PUNE
Ananya.
I need to go somewhere urgently.
I have talked to him.
-Will you please show him around the NGO?
-Yes, ma'am. Don't worry.
-Alright. I'll leave now.
-Yeah.
Let's go.
Hi, sir.
How are you, Ananya?
I'm good, sir.
Ms. Smita asked me
to show you around the NGO.
I know…
you must have been surprised…
to see me here.
I have been trying to get in
touch with you for a long time.
Today, we're finally here.
I'm really happy.
You'll be happier after meeting
the kids in the NGO, sir.
Shall we?
Please come, sir.
This NGO has been doing phenomenal work
for the welfare of physically handicapped
children for the past 12 years.
They allow admission
to only 50 students every year
so that they can attend
to each of them personally.
Ananya, listen.
I want to talk to you.
Yes, sir. We will talk to the kids.
But before that, let me give you
a brief introduction to the NGO.
Here, we have two types
of handicapped kids.
Those who are born handicapped and those
who became handicapped after an accident.
Their agony is similar.
But the struggle of those
who become handicapped
after an accident is unimaginable.
Please, this way.
Ananya, I know I have hurt you.
-You are upset with me.
-Hello.
You might even be mad at me.
But these things happen.
Sometimes, we end up doing things
that we never intend to do.
Mental grooming.
It's our first task.
Please come, sir.
Because of certain bitter
experiences in our lives,
we feel weak and helpless.
Here, they teach us
to overcome those feelings.
After that accident,
everything changed, Ananya.
What else could I have done?
It sure does feel
difficult in the beginning.
-But eventually, we learn to deal with it.
-Even I was hurt because of what happened!
Sorry.
Let's talk to the kids, sir.
Our second task is to teach
children to be independent.
-I agree I should have come to see you--
-Satish.
-Hi.
-I should have talked to you--
-That's Saket.
-But…
I didn't know how my friends
and family would react to my decision.
-I just didn't know what to do.
-Santosh, Sangita,
-and Irfan.
-Why don't you understand?
And this is Shailendra.
He's a part of the Indian
Wheelchair Cricket Team.
-How is the practice going?
-No matter what happens…
Mom and Dad would have
never agreed to this.
This is Om, sir.
-Om.
-Hi.
This is Mr. Shekhar Sarpotdar.
-Hello.
-He's a businessman.
Sir, he just finished
the trek of Fort Sinhgad.
And he wishes to go to many
more such treks, right?
Right.
Thank you.
A few months ago, Om was not even
able to step out of his house.
Because his parents were
not allowing him to go out.
They were ashamed to go
out with him in public.
But today, his parents proudly
tell everyone that he is their son.
It's possible, sir.
If we change the negative mentality
of the people around us,
everything is possible.
That's our third and most important task.
I hope you liked the work
that our NGO is doing, sir.
If you want any more information,
our staff will help you.
I'm sorry. I need to leave urgently.
Thank you so much, sir.
Have a nice day.
Everything is possible.
You just have to set your mind to it.
Even if you lose all the organs
of your body, it's still possible.
-Hello.
All the best.
-Thank you.
You just have to take
care of your one organ.
And that is your mind.
Let me tell you a quote of Nick Vujicic
who was born with no hands or legs.
He is one of the top ten
motivational speakers in the world.
"God does not make mistakes.
He makes miracles.
I am one of His miracles.
Are you one too?"
Today, even I want to ask
you the same question.
I am also one of His miracles.
Are you one too?
-Yes.
-Are you a miracle too?
-Louder. Are you a miracle too?
-Yes!
You should keep your hair open, Ananya.
I don't understand.
After so many months,
what made you come back and say
that you want to marry Ananya?
Courage, Dad.
I finally have the courage to say it.
And why now suddenly?
Do your parents know you're here?
I don't care about what they think.
Dad, please. Please trust me.
I really want to marry Ananya.
-Shekhar--
-But I don't want to marry him.
That night, along with my hands, I also
lost the ring that Shekhar gave me.
I would have found the ring
if that was really my destiny.
Sorry.
Ana--
-Ananya, please.
-You know I have countless stories of An--
Oh my God!
-Please hear me out.
-Look who's here! Shekhar!
-Shekhar!
-Shekhar's here?
He's even come to our house now!
Forget the house,
he's even gone to the bedroom.
Hey, Shekhar! What's up, buddy?
How's everyone at home?
How are your mom and dad?
Any special occasion for the visit?
Who is he?
Jai Dixit. He's our friend.
Friend?
When did he become your friend?
Just now while coming home.
Oh, God!
It's weird, but it happens.
But how does he know Shekhar?
Of course, I know Shekhar.
He's the one who was supposed
to marry Ananya but ran away, right?
Yes, that's right. Now, he's here
because he wants to marry her again.
Do you have a problem with that?
This was unexpected.
But it's expected from a person like you.
I'm sorry, dude. You were a little late.
I feel bad for him, Dad.
He can't marry Ananya now.
-Because I am going to marry her.
-What?
Exactly what I thought! Yes!
How is that possible?
-What's happening here?
-Our marriage discussion.
So, Ananya's marriage
has already been fixed?
And yet you guys let me
ramble on about myself?
Didn't you guys feel like
I should know all this?
Wait a minute.
First of all, Ananya's marriage
is not fixed with him.
And even if it is fixed,
who are you to question us?
Yeah. He's questioning us
as if we went to him…
-No, I didn't mean to--
-Hey, that's very rude, okay?
-You have no idea what we went through.
-Why did he come here in the first--
Can I get five minutes?
Priyanka. Please.
You know why this issue
was stretched so much?
-Why?
-Because you are the one with the issue.
See, the instant reaction should always
be constant than being constantly instant.
What? I didn't get it.
Don't worry, I'll explain it.
Priyanka, what were you telling me about
Dhananjay when we were coming here?
-Please tell everyone.
-About me?
Yes, about you.
-Here?
-Yeah, of course.
Come on, shoot.
I just said that…
when Dhananjay…
told me about Ananya's
surprise birthday party,
I was really happy. Obviously.
We had argued just before that.
But I knew that Dhananjay
is not like that…
because we have known each
other for so many years.
I knew it was all just a misunderstanding.
But actually, you are a very nice person.
Dhananjay, reply.
Me?
What can I say?
-You have to.
-Dad!
-Come on.
-But--
-What am I supposed to say?
-Just say it.
Let's just finish this
topic once and for all.
Dhananjay, say it!
Okay.
No…
I mean I just wanted to say that…
you are also a nice girl.
Sometimes, you behave like a child, but…
I find it sweet.
And most importantly,
I can't thank you enough
for what you have done for Ananya.
So, thank you very much.
Is it?
-This is interesting.
-Hey--
I want all the deets, okay?
So, buddy…
did you get my point?
See,
these two had a constant belief in
their instincts about each other.
They didn't change their beliefs instantly
just because the situation changed.
I don't love Ananya.
Had I really been in love with her…
I would have not let that accident happen.
Yes, Ananya.
I was standing right behind you…
to hold you.
I had a few seconds.
If I had worried a little less
about my own life,
I would have been able to save your hands.
That guilt…
brought me here today.
I was just being selfish.
He's right.
He's absolutely right.
I don't deserve you.
Can you please do something for me?
Can you forgive me?
Shekhar…
I was not mad at you…
and…
I never will be either.
Today, because of you, we were able
to close Shekhar's chapter forever.
Thank you.
Now, let's talk about you.
You come here so easily,
talk about everything so casually,
and to be honest, that's confusing.
We're just not sure if you're
really serious about Ananya or not.
What should I do for you to believe me?
You accept her the way she is, right?
That makes her feel at ease.
I am also doing the same thing, but…
you are not believing me.
Okay, convinced.
Convinced.
So, let's fix an auspicious date for
the wedding and just get done with it.
I am serious.
What is the worst that could happen?
Maybe, after a few years,
he'll realize that this was a big mistake.
It's fine.
He'll say sorry and leave me.
I'll handle it.
It's okay.
I am strong.
Mr. Jai Dixit,
marriage is a big deal for me.
It's not as easy as you think.
Why do you think you love me?
Tell me.
What's so special about me?
Or are you just trying to do something
extraordinary by marrying me?
Remember one thing.
Tomorrow, if you say that
you regret your decision,
I'll be completely shattered.
No one would be able to help me then.
Not even me.
You are not doing this because
you feel pity for me, are you?
If that's the case,
then thank you so much,
but I really don't need it.
So, Mr. Jai Dixit,
you'd better not take me lightly.
Instead of telling us what you feel,
tell yourself that.
Think about it.
And then we'll talk.
I'm getting late. Bye.
Okay, I quit.
I quit.
Because I fell in love with that Ananya,
who had completely forgotten
that she had lost her hands.
But this Ananya…
can't seem to forget that.
This Ananya doesn't believe
that a normal guy
who has two eyes, one nose, two legs,
and especially, two hands…
can fall in love with her,
can ask her to marry him.
In fact, she doesn't believe that
he can be happy with her forever.
I am not interested
in spending my life…
with someone who is so weak
and has such a negative mentality.
Bye.
-He…
-That's Jai, right?
Ananya, listen. Listen, please.
Ananya, listen to me! Ananya!
I never liked anything ordinary.
I was always looking
for something exceptional.
Then I found you.
You know what, Ananya?
Photographers wait all their
lives to find their best shot.
But luckily, I found my best shot
very early in my life.
And that shot is you, Ananya.
Now, you tell me,
what do you want me to think about?
And why?
I believe we only rethink our decision
when we have options.
And I don't want options.
I only know that I love you,
and no one can do anything about it.
Except you.
You can say yes to me.
Guys, a little help here?
-Yes.
Never mind.
You always say,
"God never makes mistakes.
He makes miracles," right?
Jai!
Wow. Finally.
JAI-ANANYA
Welcome to our newly-made home…
Mrs. Ananya.
I know you liked my surprise.
Just tell me how much you liked it.
I expected something crazy…
but this is very sweet.
Sweet?
You know what, Ananya?
It can be naughty too.
Jai…
when I think about this,
I feel scared…
whether I will be able to do it or not.
What are you talking about?
I want to be a mother.
I want to experience motherhood.
I want to do everything…
that a mother does for her child.
I'll be able to do it, right?
Of course.
Everything is possible.
You just have to set your mind to it.
Did I say that right?
Jai…
would I be able to bathe
my baby with my feet?
Yes, why not?
I will…
also massage it.
I'll also get it ready.
-What about its clothes?
-I'll change its clothes.
And then I'll put it to sleep.
I'll do everything for my baby.
Wait a minute.
What am I supposed to do then?
You can change its diapers.
-Diapers?
-Yes.
Okay.
Jai, today,
I am very happy.
You're happy, right?
Then let's dance.
Ananya…
how about ballroom dance?