Hey baby, my place upstairs later.
What's up?
Yeah!
Okay, later baby.
Okay l am going to check out the
consignment myself right now.
Separate the live ones
from the dead ones.
Jimmy.
Yeah it's me.
l asked you for 30 girls and you sent
me 17, and half of them are even dead.
This is not how l do business!
l already sold them to
our friends in Romania.
l tell you what, l can't
even unload these girls..
..not even to my new customers.
So this is what you are going to do!
You send me 30 girls, and good ones!
When l say good, l mean
fresh clean ones.
l got a reputation and l am not going
to let you mess with my business!
lf you can't do this work..
..l am going to call someone who can.
Listen Jimmy if l have to..
l will call the Russians!
They might cost me more..
..but atleast they will give
me a decent consignment!
We sure go back, but not
so far back that..
She is still alive!
Hey! Hey you stop!
Hey, where are you going?
Hold it man! Stop!
Hold it! Hold it.
- Stop.
Stop! - Hey stop!
She is getting away!
Hey hold it!
Where do you think you are going?
Stop!
There! There! There!
She is over there!
Halt! Hold it!
Surprise!
No!
You are fast.
Let me go!
No, leave me!
l want to be free!
Leave me!
No!
No, please leave me!
Shivam, come on.
There is a problem.
Room number 203.
The room is booked in
the name of Ronnie..
..maybe that's why no one stopped him.
Hey Shivam, good that you arrived.
Take care of this, take
care of this shit.
Hey, listen.. this is not my fault.
Ask him.
Tell him!
She was talking very frankly
sitting here..
..but l don't know what happened
to her on the bed.
She started to abuse me she
scratched me like a cat!
Look! Here!
That's why l killed her.
Take care of her.
Tell Malik uncle, it's my fault.
l was drunk..
Shivam, please.
You scoundrel, who are you calling?
Are you calling the police?
Keep the phone down!
Ask him to keep the phone down!
Look, l have 4 more bullets,
l will shoot you with two..
..and two on him, understood!
Shivam no!
No Shivam!
No!
Leave him Shivam!
Shivam, listen to me!
Hey move!
Shivam, enough Shivam!
Enough Shivam!
Leave him!
Have you gone mad!
Why are you doing this Shivam!
Leave him Shivam!
Shivam!
And in local news, the Hong
Kong police department..
..have arrested Manoj Malik,
a.k.a. Munna..
..for the suspected murder
of Sylvia Thomas.
A hotel employee of Hong
Kong lnternational.
Manoj is the only son of
the local business man,,
..Mr. Rajan Malik and nephew
of Bharat Malik..
..the owner of Hong Kong
lnternational hotels.
The Malik family moved to Hong
Kong about 12 years ago..
..from lndia. lt is believed that
the Malik's were involved..
..in various illegitimate
business and activities.
lf you want to know the
stature of a person..
..then you should find
out about his enemies.
The more dangerous his enemies are..
..the higher his stature is.
You are progressing nicely.
Will you have food?
The auditors were saying,
that your single hotel..
..does seven times more business
than all our other hotels.
Whereas we have casinos
in our hotels..
..and call dancers from all over
the world and make them perform.
But even then, your
hotel is number one.
lt is true, when you can
progress the right way..
..then you shouldn't think
of using illegal means.
Sorry sir, you can't go.
- Don't touch me!
What was the need?
You didn't do the right thing
by getting Munna arrested!
Dad, whenever l try to do business
with Rajan uncle, this Shivam..
Don't interfere in my business
relationships..
..you are just a servant,
behave like one!
Or else..
- Or else what?
What?
Do you understand business?
You had booked the room in the
hotel in your name for Munna.
Papa, listen..
The hotel is Shivam's.
The business is Shivam's too.
You will not go to that
hotel behind my back..
..and neither will you talk
to Shivam in a high tone.
Understood.
Understood!
- Yes.
The condition of the grieved
cannot be narrated..
..whose tears are concealed
in his heart forever.
l never saw you drinking like this.
Are you fine?
Come, l will take you inside.
Come.
Come on.
- l want to talk to you.
Yes.
A girl, Reema.
She is a Pakistani.
She is no ordinary girl, that's
why l have kept her secluded..
..from everyone's eyes.
A few days ago l had gone to meet her.
l talked to her a lot, l
gave her a lot of love.
But when she was in bed with me..
..for the first time l realised..
l have her body..
..but her heart is far away from me.
lf this girl starts meeting
someone else..
..or if she falls in love
with someone else..
..then l won't survive Shivam.
l am going to London for 2 weeks.
This is her address, keep a watch
on her, follow this girl..
..and find out, if l am the
only one in her life..
..or is there someone else too.
This better be my illusion,..
..but
if it is true, then call me
Good bye.
Goodbye.
- Bye.
Yes.
Malik sir has sent me.
Can you speak a little louder, please?
Malik sir has sent this
parcel for you.
Oh hi.
No l cannot come now.
No, it will take me some more time.
Yes, l will be ready.
Just a minute, will
you hold on please.
Excuse me.
Yes.
- You can leave.
Malik sir has sent the car for you.
No, l will not need the car.
l will talk to Malik sir myself.
- Okay.
This is my card..
- No, no l won't need that too.
Okay.
Listen.. okay give me your card.
Who knows when l might need it?
Good bye.
You are a strange man,
you are not leaving..
..even after saying goodbye.
- Good bye.
l am sorry.
Let it be..
- l am sorry.
l will do it.
Let it be.
What is this?
- l am so sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry.
l have been waiting for so long.
Enough now.
Shall we go?
# Somewhere out there, l
know there is someone.. #
# ..out there, who is waiting
for me beloved. #
# He is going to set me free, beloved. #
# Who is just love for me in his eyes,
there is someone, beloved. #
# l am waiting for him, beloved. #
# Someone who is missing
only me in his life.. #
# ..who is restless for me, l
am waiting for him, beloved. #
# He would love only me. #
# Everything related to him
is connected with me.. #
# ..who would love me eternally, who is
more loyal than loyalty, beloved. #
# How long must l keep
dreaming of a fantasy? #
# Why can't he be a part
of my reality? #
# l think only about him in my dreams. #
# The one that will have
all the vibrant colours. #
# The one that l always thought about,
he must be somewhere, beloved.. #
# ..my sweet heart, my beloved. #
# Somewhere out there, l
know there is someone.. #
# ..out there, who is waiting
for me, beloved. #
# He is going to set me free, beloved.. #
Kabir l am messaging
you some numbers..
..find out whom they belong to,
and monitor them 24 hours.
l have a lot of work to do. ls it so
necessary to find the numbers?
Will you do the work without
asking any question?
Okay. - Please.
# l know that he is going
to be my destiny. #
# lt's all a part of
cupid's conspiracy. #
# l am waiting for him to arrive
l will hide him in my heart. #
# The one that my heart
has said yes to. #
# l will find that companion,
my sweet heart, beloved. #
# l have trust, beloved.. #
# Somewhere out there, l
know there is someone.. #
# ..out there, who is waiting
just for me beloved. #
# He is going to set
me free, beloved.. #
# Someone who is missing
only me in his life.. #
# ..who is restless for me, l
am waiting for him, beloved. #
# He would love only me. #
# Everything related to him
is connected with me.. #
# ..who would love me eternally, who is
more loyal than loyalty, beloved. #
Bye.
- Bye, good night.
Good night.
Bye.
Hello. - Guess whose back?
Back again, Shady is back.
Back again.
- Hello.
Guess whose back? Guess whose
back?
Who is this? - Guess whose back?
Hello, l am back!
And so is my friend Johnny!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
You will send me to jail!
You scoundrel!
You scoundrel, l am going to kill you!
Listen.
Munna's bodyguard took the
blame for Sylvia's murder.
Since he has come out of the jail..
..he has made my life hell.
Always keeps calling me.
Where is Shivam, where is Shivam.
l tried to explain uncle..
..it is a very small matter,
let it go.
He doesn't understand.
After all, we have not committed..
..the rape and the murder.
But no, that scoundrel Shivam..
..that rascal Shivam!
Look, listen to me, call up
uncle and apologise to him.
There is no point in stretching
the matter.
Listen to me.
Son of a..
Here talk to him, make him understand.
Make him understand.
Shivam!
Say whatever you want to.
But not like a coward on the phone..
..say it on my face.
l made him understand.
What did you do?
Shivam! Shivam listen to me.
What do you think of yourself?
You can shoot and abuse
whoever you want!
What are you?
Your stature and your pride..
..that's all because my
father is supporting you.
Once he stops supporting you then
see what happens with you.
Did you hear!
The day Malik sir stops
supporting you..
..that day, your corpse will
be lying in this sewer!
Rajan Munna, are they your family?
Ronnie, they are just using you..
..so that one day they can just take
over your father's business..
..and ruin you!
lf possible, try to understand it.
Good bye.
Yes sir.
- Where are you?
At home, anything special?
Tell me Shivam, is there
loyalty or betrayal..
..in Bharat Malik's fate.
Don't worry sir, there is still
nothing like you had thought.
Okay.
Okay, atleast today l can sleep
without having to drink.
But still keep a watch on this girl.
The heart of a woman and
the depth of an ocean..
..are never easy to measure Shivam.
Such loneliness, such helplessness..
..why does love give you so much pain.
Good that you keep far
away from all this.
Good night.
What a day friend, today we
have hit double jackpot.
You are right Kabir, today
we have hit the jackpot!
Faster! Come on drive faster!
lt doesn't go any faster.
We have found a nice party.
Yes.
What happened?
What timing!
This has to happen now.
Come on hurry up.
Yes take the tyre out.
Shivam, get aside.
We are done for, Shivam
get out of here.
They don't recognise me..
..if they see you it will
be a big problem.
Go from here.
You go, l will do it. Come on go.
You are looking very scared, sir.
No matter, release these birds..
..Allah will shower his grace on you.
What?
- Only for 20 rupees sir..
..one bird is for 20 rupees.
Set them free, and then wish
for whatever you want..
..Allah will surely fulfil your wish.
You will not get a better
chance than this.
Take the blessing of
the devotees of Allah
Neither do l need your birds..
..nor the grace of your Allah,
now go from here!
Are you an atheist, sir?
- Yes.
That's a very big sin.
Come on.
You don't believe in Allah at all?
This is a strange way
to run your business.
First cage the birds then set
them free taking money..
..and then say that if you
will set them free..
..then Allah will shower
his grace on you.
Great, first commit the sin and
then teach us about good deeds.
Look sir, l have not
committed any sin..
..these birds belong to someone else.
l just bring them to the
market and sell them.
Then why don't you just sell them..
What is the need to talk
about sin and grace?
There is a need, do you
know 1400 years ago..
..the Prophet Mohammad,
he would buy the slaves..
..of the Mecca and the
Madina at any price.
And then he would set them free.
There are no more slaves now.
That's why l sell these birds,
so that people buy them..
..and set them free in
the greed of grace.
There are such fools too.
- Again nonsense.
lf you don't believe me,
then free these birds..
..and when Allah will shower
his grace on you..
..and your soul will find peace..
..then you will start believing it.
Shivam what are you doing here?
Come on, let us go from here.
Come on.
l searched the entire market
for you, you know that..
..and you are sitting here.
The party is waiting for us.
lt is a question of 30 lakhs,
where is your concentration..
..l am not talking nonsense.
Yes, how are you?
We have picked up the goods, yes.
lt is in the trunk.
Yes, we are reaching, we are reaching.
What a party we have found.
Let us quickly hand over
the fatso to him..
..and then the 30 lakh is ours.
Just think that the
entire world is ours.
'There is a need, do you
know 1400 years ago..
..the Prophet Mohammad,
he would buy the slaves..
..of the Mecca and the
Madina at any price.'
'And then he would set them free.'
'There are no more slaves now.'
'That's why l sell these birds,
so that people buy them..
..and set them free in the
greed of Allah's grace.'
'Again nonsense.'
'lf you don't believe me,
then free these birds..
..and when Allah will shower
his grace on you..
..and your soul will find peace..
..then you will start believing it.'
With great style, isn't it Shivam?
What happened, why did
you stop the car?
Shivam.
What are you doing.
Don't.. don't kill me.
Don't kill me! Don't kill me!
Don't..
- Quiet, get lost fatso.
l spared your life.
- Don't kill me!
l will not kill you.
What are you doing Shivam?
- Nothing, listen to me.
Fatso, come back and sit inside.
Go, go.
- l can give my life for you..
..but he is worth 30 lakhs!
Go, go from here fatso.
You are God for me, you
have saved my life.
Come on fatso, sit inside!
Thank you so much.
The fatso is not listening.
Where are you going, stop!
Stop!
Shivam, what are you doing?
What has happened to you?
You will die, and kill me too.
What has happened to you today?
Let it be, you will not understand.
You have gone mad, mad.
l am saved.
# Lord. #
# You are my love, you
are my companion. #
# You are my religion,
you are my faith. #
# You are my body.. you are my soul. #
# You are my heart, you are my life. #
# My Lord, O my Lord, my lord. #
# You are my destination,
you are my journey. #
# You are in my dreams,
you belong to me. #
# You are my dawn, you are my dusk. #
# You are in my thoughts,
you are in my promises. #
# My Lord, O my Lord, my lord. #
# You are my most cherished treasure. #
# You are my most treasured fortune. #
# You are with me in my bad phases. #
# You are with me in my good phases. #
# You are the robe that covers me. #
# You are with me in my cumbrance. #
# You are in my dreams. #
# You are in my eyes. #
# My Lord, O my Lord, my lord. #
# You are speech, you are my worry. #
# You are the reason of my pain. #
# You are the one that makes
me forget my pains. #
# You are my worship. #
# You are my direction. #
# You are my mosque. #
# You are my temple. #
# My Lord, O my Lord, my lord. #
Hello.
- Hi, this is Reema speaking.
You had said that l call
you if l want something.
l didn't want to trouble you,
but something important..
..has come up.
lt is just a question of 2-3 hours.
How long?
- ln half an hour.
Hello. Don't hit me, don't hit me.
Didn't you recognise me?
Me, didn't you recognise me?
- No.
Try to remember, we had met.
Try to remember,
Remember you had spared my life.
No, l don't remember.
Sood, Siddharth Sood.
l was having food in my hotel
and you kidnapped me..
..in Jodhpur, remember.
Do you remember?
- Yes.
You changed my life by sparing me.
Now l am the CEO of God.
l show the right path to the
one that have strayed.
Here, here l live in the monastery..
..outside of Hong Kong.
Do come and visit me someday.
Okay, l will come.
Do come.
Hello, excuse me.
- You..
You are so strange Shivam..
..l have been waiting
for you for so long..
..and you are standing
there talking to him.
l am sorry, l am sorry.
You had to wait for him because of me.
Because of me.
Please excuse me.
l don't know why we monks feel that..
..just because we have
renounced the world..
Everyone else has too.
l am very happy to meet you.
Very happy.
- Okay.
Do come and meet me.
Sorry.
Okay tell me, what do you do?
l am in charge of Malik sir's hotel.
l had given you my card.
Yes. By the way he was saying that..
..you are a very dangerous person.
l mean.. you get angry soon.
You had said that you have some
important work with me.
Actually.. since Malik sir
has left for London..
..l sense a strange fear.
And you won't believe but..
l feel that there is
a ghost in my house.
The ghost is in your mind
and not in your house.
And that's your loneliness.
Even l used to run and be
afraid of my loneliness.
Then one day l befriended
that loneliness..
..and everything was fine again.
lf you take my advice, then
befriend your loneliness..
Okay, if you say so then l will
try to befriend my loneliness.
But that will take sometime..
..right now, there is another way.
- What's that?
That.. l had made a talisman for me..
..from a priest here.
lt might be ready by now.
l will tie it to my door.
l will have faith that
Allah is with me..
..he is protecting me.
Please, will you go in..
..and bring that talisman
from the priest.
l cannot go in.
Temples, mosques and other
places of worship..
..l don't like them..
..its better that you keep
me away from all this.
l am sorry but, it is forbidden
for women to go inside..
..and l need that talisman.
Please l request you, please go
in and bring that talisman.
Yes.
- Tell me.
Ms. Reema has sent me.
The priest is conducting
the prayer, take a seat.
As soon as he finishes praying
you can meet him. - Okay.
Aliyah, you take so much time.
- Shivam.
Come here.
- No Shivam.
What?
- Leave me Shivam.
The prayers are only for 10 minutes..
..and you don't concentrate
for that long too.
That's the limit.
How did you stay in your mother's
womb for nine months?
There is something called as patience.
When you pray l feel very lonely.
What happens to you?
You cut off yourself from me.
l cannot tolerate this distance.
And today you were praying
for a really long time..
..to your Allah.
You were not ready to get up.
Today l was talking about
something special..
..about you.
You were complaining
about me to Allah.
l wasn't complaining,
l was praying for you.
l was telling Allah
to make you believe..
..to make you a believer
from an atheist.
No matter in what form and
way you believe in him..
..but do believe in him.
Are you listening Shivam?
- Yes, l am listening.
That's the problem with you people..
..except for God you understand
everything else.
When there is no God, then what
is there to understand?
lt is difficult to talk to you.
l want us to be together even
after we are dead, in heaven.
And only those people stay
together in heaven..
..who believe in God.
Otherwise you will be somewhere else..
..and l will be somewhere else.
l will have to live
without you Shivam.
Aliyah, all l know that the
love that l have for you..
..that's my only desire,
and my only religion.
For me, you are my God and my faith.
Oh God, Shivam that's enough.
And about God, if he really
exists and if he..
..has united you with me.
Then one day he will
make me his devotee.
When he does it, how he does it..
..l have left that to him.
But Shivam, listen to..
- Enough about the Lord..
..come let us talk about
something else.
Let us talk about love.
- Shivam.
Let us talk about me, about you.
- Leave me Shivam.
Aliyah.
- Leave me.
Listen to me.
Where will you go now?
Where will you run now?
You have crossed all the
limits of shamelessness.
You are openly flirting
with your lover..
..in front of everyone!
Fearless, you dare to face me too!
Lower your eyes, ill-mannered!
l love your daughter.
l want to marry her.
lf you agree, and even
if you don't agree.
Don't you dare touch me!
First of all you are from
a different religion..
..and you are a criminal too.
Didn't he tell you, what
his profession is?
He is a thief! He is a goon!
And because of these crimes,
he has been jailed twice..
..he has been jailed twice!
You will marry my daughter!
Will you use your illegal
means to feed her!
lf you will allow me to
marry your daughter..
..then this weapon,
this life of crime..
..l am prepared to leave everything.
Forget about this weapon
and this life of crime..
..you are going to die right now!
Aliyah!
Nothing will happen to you.
- Shivam.
Shivam.
Aliyah! Aliyah!
Your talisman.
lf you don't mind, then can
l say something to you?
Tell me.
l don't know, but l feel
that l have never seen..
..anyone more alone
and lonely than you.
Maybe you are still surrounded
by that loneliness.
You need this talisman more than me.
# So come again and trouble me. #
# So come again and make me cry. #
# My heart was filled with sorrows. #
# My eyes started crying. #
# l gasped so heavily. #
# Like the wind blows. #
# So come again and trouble me. #
# So come again and make me cry. #
# Come back, come back, come back. #
# Come back, come back,
come back, come back. #
You have to come back. Aliya!
# Take back all your sorrows. #
# All those that you have given me. #
# Or else tell me,.. #
# ..how will l tolerate them. #
# So come again and trouble me. #
# So come again and make me cry. #
# Come back, come back, come back. #
# Come back, come back,
come back, come back. #
Your car is standing in
the middle of the road.
Shivam, what happened?
Shall we go.
..l am too sexy, Ayesha,
Ayesha, Ayesha.
Shivam.
They have come to talk peace, relax.
Munna please, not now.
Not now, Ronnie. Listen to me.
Munna later, please listen to me.
Sit. Please sit down.
Sit.
By profession.. l am a business man.
My business is not killing people.
But if someone interferes
in my business..
..then l kill him.
You are interfering in my business.
ln my business too.
Along with my son.
But l will forgive you, because
you are a slave of my brother.
But for that you will have
to apologise to me.
Touch my feet, apologise.
What are you doing?
Hey don't shoot.
Hey, hey.
What are you doing?
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
Shivam! Shivam!
Shivam, do you know
what you are doing?
What had l said to you, never
come back here again!
Never come back here again!
Did you understand!
Lower the guns!
Lower the guns.
Relax.
Shivam, Shivam, Shivam relax.
l am not that easy a target,
that you can kill me..
..whenever you want to!
You had come to talk about peace..
..then listen to me carefully.
Never again try to interfere
in my matters again!
l will give you and
your men two minutes.
You will regret it.
Give me a drink.
Enjoy your drink sir.
Rajan is Malik sir's brother.
l am not asking you to touch
his feet and apologise..
..l am your friend.
l worry for you.
But l don't know why, you
have again become what..
Bye.
Good night, see you.
- Bye.
Hello.
- Yes.
Take your bag.
- Oh, sorry, sorry.
Or else you will trouble us
in the middle of the night.
Good night.
Bye.
- Bye.
lt is a very bad thing..
..following someone in the
middle of the night..
..keeping a watch on them, it
is a kind of an invasion.
That.. l..
- Don't try to give reasons.
l know that you are just following
Malik sir's orders.
So what are your intentions now?
You have followed me.
lf you are still not satisfied..
..then keep sitting in the
car the entire night.
lf you want, shall l send
a coffee for you?
No, there is no need for that.
You go home, l am leaving.
You go.
Yes Kabir - Where are you, Shivam?
- What's going on in the club?
Ronnie is here.
No l don't want to talk to Ronnie.
Tell him that..
You scoundrel!
Hello, hello.. are you alright?
Shivam..
Hello Shivam.
ls there any problem?
No, a car..
Car? Shivam, what are you talking?
Shivam..
l will call you later.
No Reema, l have come
all the way here..
..from Pakistan, just
to take you back!
For the sake of Allah,
let's go from here.
Bilal, when Malik sir brought
me here from Bangkok..
..then l made a compromise with life.
Now l am just his slave..
..l don't dream about freedom anymore.
Reema you are advancing towards hell..
..and l will not let
that happen Reema.
Listen to me let's go back
to our country Reema.
Why don't you understand,
l cannot risk your life..
..for my freedom.
And if Malik's men see
you here, then..
Then he will kill me, isn't it?
But l cannot see you
enslaved here Reema.
But Bilal..
- Those people..
Listen to me, we only
have tonight Reema.
Today even Shivam is not
keeping a watch on you.
l.. l.. l have booked two
tickets for Lahore, Reema.
Don't worry about me Reema.
Just pack your bags, and come with me.
No, not more than that..
..we are going to finish
it within 4 months.
Wonderful.
- Thank you.
Tell me Shivam.
- Sir you were right..
..there is someone in her life.
Sir, his name is Bilal and he
is with Reema right now..
..in Reema's house.
They are planning to go
to Pakistan tonight, sir.
Kill her.
What sir.
Yes sir.
Reema! Reema, open the door..
..it is almost time for the flight.
Reema, we might be late..
No! No!
No! No! No!
No, leave her.
- Bilal. - Go!
Shivam!
No Shivam!
Shivam, no please leave him!
Leave him.
Shivam!
Shivam, please Shivam!
Please leave him!
Please Shivam!
Shivam no!
No Shivam, please leave him!
lt is all my fault!
Let him go!
Please listen to me, for
the sake of Allah.
For Gods sake.
Please! Please let him go!
Please Shivam!
You want to kill, don't you!
Kill me!
But you cannot force me like this!
l don't want this life of slavery!
lt is my right to be free!
You cannot snatch my right from me!
Leave me.
lt is my right to be free!
Please Shivam, please.
For Gods sake.
Spare us, let us go!
Please.
Let him go!
'No matter, set this bird free..
..Allah will shower his grace on you.'
Shivam, please Shivam!
For the sake of Allah!
'lf you don't believe me,
then free these birds..
..and when Allah will shower
his grace on you..
..and your soul will find peace..
..then you will start believing it.'
For Gods sake.
Please, spare us!
Hello.
Why didn't you kill her?
Why couldn't you fire?
Tell me. Tell me.
l don't know l fired 6 bullets
from the distance of 6 feet.
But not one hit her.
l don't know how l missed my aim.
My hands did not work.
Like.. like it was some miracle.
l don't believe it that
you are saying all this.
You are an atheist, aren't you?
Since when did you start believing
in all these things?
You are talking nonsense.
You couldn't fire, as if the
Lord descended himself..
..and saved her, isn't it.
Shivam the truth is that you
didn't want to kill her.
Now because of her,
both of us will die.
Malik will not spare both of us.
Now you tell me what we should do.
Tell me.
This is my bank account number.
There are 8 lakh dollars in it.
Withdraw it as soon as possible.
We are going back to lndia
in the first flight.
Back, that means we will
have to run again.
Three years ago we fled from
our country and came here.
We were doing fine here.
We have got a chance
to earn good money..
..and you are asking me to go back.
Why Shivam, why should we
lock horns with Malik sir..
..for a Pakistani girl.
We are not going anywhere!
And we will not risk our
life for some girl.
Do you understand?
l will kill her right now!
l will take all the decisions
in our friendship, and not you.
Will you do what l am asking you to?
Will you do it?
lf you want l can even
give my life for you.
l will reach the airport in
two hours with the passport..
..you reach the airport
too with the money.
Where is Shivam?
Why are you surprised
to see Kabir with me?
He is just your friend..
..you meant to me more than my son.
l had asked you to kill Reema.
She is alive.
What has happened between us Shivam..
..that today you are
standing against me!
Do you know Shivam, the river
that flows near the villages..
..sometimes enters the villages
too during the rains.
But then we don't change the
direction of the river..
..but we wait, for the
storm to die down.
l will give you one more chance.
The work that you have
left incomplete..
..complete it.
No sir.
l cannot do this.
Now you will kill Reema.
You will kill Reema, only you.
Make him suffer until he doesn't
realise his mistake.
A man progresses with the
decisions that he takes.
You did the right thing.
You'll surely achieve something one
day if you remain the same way.
Can l come in?
Ronnie.
Ronnie!
Ronnie, No! Stop!
Ronnie, No! Stop! Ronnie!
Do you know Gini?
Once l thought of adopting a pet dog.
l went to the market.
There were many good dogs,
of high breed.
But l did not like anyone.
Suddenly my eyes fell on a bitch
(Female dog) in the corner..
..she was very weak, dirty and puny.
l liked her.
The shopkeeper told me,
don't take her.
She is ill.
She will die.
l didn't listen, l brought her home.
l gave her a bath, brought
her up took care of her.
Gini and your story
is exactly the same.
There is only one difference.
She turned out to be loyal.
Congratulations.
You even defeated death Shivam.
But l can't understand..
..has your life increased
or your pain.
Come here, dig another hole.
Let's give him a bath.
Before burying the corpse, we
will have to give him a bath.
A gift for you, dad has sent it.
Open it, open it.
You have lost your pride
but not your ego.
Here.
Call and apologise to Malik sir.
You are a very fortunate guy..
..you have got another chance.
Do what Malik sir has asked
you to, kill Reema.
You have ten minutes.
l know him.
He will not apologize.
After ten minutes, kill him.
l am sorry sir.
l don't believe this.
You apologised.
When your life is at stake..
..then the principles of life change.
Yes sir, yes sir.
Yes dad..
Kill him!
Dad.
Uncle Rajan has come.
So.. l heard that Shivam has fled.
Stop him! Catch him!
l don't believe this.
lf you would have handed
this work to me..
..then he would have been dead by now.
Because of him, you took up
enmity with your own kin.
All your cleverness has failed.
The child is right.
l don't know how to
recognise a person.
l am tired baba.
Now l can't handle this
business alone.
l want your support.
ln return, money, partnership..
..l will give you all that you want.
Just bring Shivam to me.
Bring him to me. Alive.
l want to kill him myself.
Shivam is already dead.
Only his last rites
are to be performed.
Now only the Lord can
save him in Hong Kong.
Don't get up, don't get
up, don't get up..
..keep lying.
Whatever happened, you
are safe here. Keep lying.
# Why didn't l believe you? #
# Why did l stay away from you? #
# Life kept committing
atrocities on me. #
# You are the one that
has given me shelter. #
# The relation between you
and me is very old. #
Where is he?
Look, my men will find that
boy sooner or later.
lt will be better for
you that you tell me.
Your silence will be
your biggest enmity.
l will take you back
to the same place..
..from where l had bought you.
That's the right place for you.
You will never fall short
of lovers there.
You will look for one, but
you will find many..
..and they will use
you so many times..
..that you will never ever think
of falling in love again.
From now on you just
wait for that day.
'l was telling Allah
to make you believe..
..to make you a believer
from an atheist.'
'No matter in what form and
way you believe in him..
..but do believe in him.'
'l want us to be together even
after we are dead, in heaven.'
'And only those people stay
together in heaven..
..who believe in God.'
# What is this suffering?
What is this punishment? #
# Why did l think of you today? #
# My days are restless, restless
are my nights. #
# Tell me what l should do. #
# My feet are my chains,
free me from myself. #
# The relation between you
and me is very old. #
You will leave for lndia
today evening..
..l have made all the arrangements.
We have a monk that has
a shipping company..
..he will take you to Kolkata.
Without the passport.
You don't worry, everything
will be fine.
What are you thinking?
These people, just to help people
in their sorrows and pains..
..had given up salvation and nirvana.
And me, who is running from
here to save my life.
How long can l run?
How long will l carry
on with this useless..
..and disrespected life.
What will l do with such a life?
l will become the slave
of some other Malik..
..and follow his orders, that's all.
Do you know Sood.. when
Aliyah's father..
..had pointed the gun at me,
then l moved from the way..
..to save my life.
l survived but she did not.
And l just kept watching.
l am doing the same thing today.
l am hiding like cowards,
l am running.
How long will l keep running?
Where will l run off to, Sood.
There is no place in the world..
..where her voice does not follow me.
l have decided Sood, l will
not go back to lndia.
l will not go.
Shivam, if you stay here
then Malik's men..
..will seek you out and kill you.
Because of the fear of death..
..l had died even before my death.
l have seen death from very close..
..you will have to die for someone..
..to make this life useful.
l will not die without uniting
Reema and Bilal.
This slave will be free only
when he will set them free.
Come on, sit inside.
Bilal, sit inside.
Get him!
Don't let him go! Don't let him go!
Bilal, stop!
Bilal, stop! You scoundrel! Stop.
Get him!
What are you thinking? Kill me.
Shoot.
These hands haven't changed
as much as you have Kabir.
Even if l wanted to,
l cannot shoot you.
Free me from this life, shoot me.
l have broken our friendship, shoot.
l will take all the decisions
in our friendship..
..and not you, do you understand!
And l say that you will live
and you will help me.
Take this boy to Siddharth
Sood's temple..
..and wait for me there.
l will bring Reema there,
did you understand.
Kabir tell me, you will do it.
l can even give my life for you.
Trying to act smart.
You always cry.
Come on, go from here.
Where is Reema?
Only Rajan and Munna knows that.
Go away. Go away. - Boss.
l have not come here to kill you.
Just tell me where is Reema.
l will quietly go from here.
The decision is yours.
What is this?
What is this Reema?
My brother is ready to
ruin his life for her.
You are ready to die for her.
What is this Reema?
ls she better than these girls?
You do one thing, l will
tell you where she is..
..bring her, bring her here.
Bring her here!
l will test her.
You too, Kim will test her too.
l will make entire Hong Kong test her.
Don't kill me.
l don't know anything, Munna
knows where she is.
Don't kill me.
Give a call to Munna.
You scoundrel, don't trouble me.
l am reaching there.
Tell me now. l've reached here.
Where are you?
l had told you to leave
my father and come to me.
l am standing here in the
parking lot, where are you?
Go from here.
You won't regret it but even
then l will tell you..
..l have killed your father.
You should go, to shoulder
the pyre of your father.
You want to go, don't you?
But before that tell me, where
has Malik kept Rema.
ln Malik uncle's house in Macau.
Thank you.
l am in the house!
You made a very big mistake.
You made a very big mistake
by locking horns with me.
Malik uncle wants to keep you alive..
..but l am about to kill you.
My name is free and l am funky. Yeah.
Before dying, would you
like to hear a secret?
Would you like to hear it?
Your Reema is in Malik uncle's
Chungking mansion.
And there she is being sold.
And all of them, one after another..
..one after another,
one after another..
..are going to rape her.
Okay, time is up ready to die.
Thank you.
Hello.
Hello Shivam, all the
arrangements have been made.
Yes.
Kabir has handed over both
the passports to me.
Now you direct me.
Reach the Hong Kong docks for now..
..l will reach there along with Reema.
Shivam, they will kill you Shivam!
Nothing will happen
to me, listen to me.
l promise you, that you
will celebrate ld..
..in your own country.
No Shivam don't go there,
Shivam don't..
Shivam, where are you?
Hello, hello.
Please keep me alive
for some more time.
Give me some more life.
Not for me, but for those
who believe in you.
l have committed many sins..
..give me one chance to repent for it.
# The person inside me is saying. #
# lt is time to repay your debts. #
# My eyes are filled with tears,
my breath hurts. #
# My wounds have become fresh again. #
# ln my loneliness and
in all my sagas. #
# You were always with me. #
# The relation between you
and me is very old. #
# The relation between..
you and me is very old. #
Lower the guns!
Down! Down!
Well done, you did reach here
after all.. for this girl.
So, what are your intentions?
Malik sir, let them go.
- Or else.
You will kill me! You will kill me!
l didn't understand one thing Shivam..
..l treated you worse than animals.
But you tolerated it all,
for this girl!
You killed my brother you killed
Munna, for this girl!
But you didn't answer
one of my questions.
Why?
Why didn't you kill this girl?
The voices, that keep
echoing in my ears..
..a face that always appears
in front of my eyes.
She was my peace.
She had said set the birds free..
..and Allah will shower
his grace on you.
She had said, setting
a helpless free..
..means setting humanity free.
Today l have got the chance,
to follow what she said..
..to change.
Malik sir, those who cannot
fulfil their own dreams..
..they try to fulfil
the dreams of others.
But you will not understand that.
You are doing this because,
you want to do a good deed..
..before you die!
You feel, that your Allah will
shower his grace on you.
Lord will give you place in heaven!
Rubbish!
Malik sir, l don't want
a place in heaven.
l have just come to save
this girl from hell.
l have chosen death myself,
for you and for me.
Come on Shivam, you go!
You go, Bilal is waiting
for you on the docks.
You go! Shivam, go!
Kabir.. Kabir come with me!
Shivam! Shivam! Shivam!
Shivam, come on Shivam!
Shivam, come on let's get out of here.
When l start firing, start
running towards the boat.
No Shivam!
l cannot bear the burden of
this aimless life anymore.
For me, death is my destination.
Wait.. take this.
Reema, thank you for setting me free.
Thank you.
Go.
Take her away! Take her away!
No. no!
No! No! - Go! Shivam.. No!
Come on! - Shivam!
# Now lsha have to disappear.. #
# ..from this scene.. #
# The path on which my
companion is waiting. #
# l have to attain those paths. #
# So come again trouble me. #
# So come again and make me cry. #
# Come back again, come back
again, come back again. #
And in this way, that vagabond
sacrificed his life..
..to set me free.
Today l have come here so
that we can set them free..
..who are enslaved against their will.
Whose screams and shrieks
are heard by no one!
Because now they can be set free.
Freedom is our right.
# Why didn't l believe you? #
# Why did l stay away from you? #
# Life kept committing
atrocities on me. #
# You are the one that
has given me shelter. #
# The relation between you
and me is very old. #
# What is this suffering?
What is this punishment? #
# Why did l think of you today? #
# My days are restless, restless
are my nights. #
# Tell me what l should do. #
# My feet are my chains,
free me from myself. #
# The relation between you
and me is very old. #
# The person inside me is saying. #
# lt is time to repay your debts. #
# My eyes are filled with tears,
my breath hurts. #
# My wounds have become fresh again. #
# ln my loneliness and
in all my sagas. #
# You were always with me. #
# The relation between you
and me is very old. #
Subtitles by ARAVIND B
[by_agentsmith@yahoo.com]